[{"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Nmfaf_3daDataManagement_Deconfigure service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To configure the MFAF to map data or analytics received by the MFAF to out-bound notification endpoints\n2) To configure the MFAF to stop mapping data or analytics received by the MFAF to out-bound notification endpoints\n3) To supply data or analytics from the MFAF to notification endpoints\n4) To fetch data or analytics from the MFAF based on fetch instructions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 0, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To configure the MFAF to stop mapping data or analytics received by the MFAF to out-bound notification endpoints", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does a supporting UE attach to the same core network operator from which it detached in a shared network? \n\nOptions:\n1) It requests the core network node to remember its previous selection.\n2) It uses information stored in the UE when it was detached.\n3) It relies on the SIM/USIM card for information.\n4) It performs a fresh attach procedure.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  It uses information stored in the UE when it was detached.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can the setting of the Privacy exception list be changed? \n\nOptions:\n1) Never\n2) Only during emergency services\n3) Anytime\n4) Only with operator permission\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 11, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Anytime", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NEF notify to the AF after determining the suitable DNAI(s)? \n\nOptions:\n1) AF Identifier\n2) EAS address information\n3) DNN\n4) DNAI(s) or the updated DNAI information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 12, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  DNAI(s) or the updated DNAI information", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn online charging, how are chargeable events transformed into charging events? \n\nOptions:\n1) By the CTF\n2) By the OCF\n3) By the CGF\n4) By the CHF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 14, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  By the OCF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the PSFCH channel in NR V2X sidelink? \n\nOptions:\n1) To transmit Uplink and Downlink V2X messages\n2) To transmit HARQ feedback for unicast and groupcast\n3) To transmit sidelink synchronization signals\n4) To transmit physical layer structure information\n5) To transmit resource allocation configurations\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 19, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To transmit HARQ feedback for unicast and groupcast", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich feature proposes to integrate selected WLAN direct discovery technologies as an alternative technology for ProSe Direct Discovery? \n\nOptions:\n1) Unlicensed Spectrum Offloading System\n2) Enhancements to LTE operation in unlicensed spectrum\n3) Voice services over WLAN\n4) WLAN Offloading System\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 23, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  WLAN Offloading System", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can there be two N3 tunnel terminations at the RAN for a PDU Session? \n\nOptions:\n1) When there are multiple PDU Session Ids for the PDU Session\n2) When the QoS Flows of the PDU Session are split across the two RATs\n3) When the PDU Session belongs to a specific Network Slice\n4) When the Master RAN node is congested\n5) When the Secondary RAN node is congested\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 29, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  When the QoS Flows of the PDU Session are split across the two RATs", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich NGAP procedure is used for inter-system load balancing? \n\nOptions:\n1) eNB Configuration Transfer\n2) Downlink RAN Configuration Transfer\n3) Uplink RAN Configuration Transfer\n4) MME Configuration Transfer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 37, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Uplink RAN Configuration Transfer", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Validity Period for predictions? \n\nOptions:\n1) To indicate the area of interest\n2) To provide the Target of Analytics Reporting\n3) To determine the Reporting Threshold\n4) To define the time window\n5) To specify the maximum number of objects\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 41, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To define the time window", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the MCImp-MC_ARCH work item? \n\nOptions:\n1) To specify a common functional architecture for MCVideo\n2) To specify a common functional architecture for MCData\n3) To specify a common functional architecture for all mission critical services\n4) To specify a common functional architecture for MCPTT only\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 42, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To specify a common functional architecture for all mission critical services", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat should the UE consider if it cannot detect any cell meeting the S criterion on a frequency for sidelink operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Out-of-coverage for sidelink operation on that frequency\n2) Out-of-coverage for V2X sidelink communication on that frequency\n3) Out-of-coverage for NR sidelink communication on that frequency\n4) In-coverage for NR sidelink communication on that frequency\n5) In-coverage for sidelink operation on that frequency\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 45, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Out-of-coverage for sidelink operation on that frequency", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Member UE selection assistance functionality hosted by NEF? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide filtering criteria for AF's inputs\n2) To collect corresponding data from relevant 5GC NFs\n3) To select member UEs for AF's application operations\n4) To provide QoS for the updated list of UEs\n5) To assist the AI/ML application server in scheduling UEs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 46, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To select member UEs for AF's application operations", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the AMF enable or disable the 5G access stratum time distribution for a UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) When UE is in CM-REJECTED state\n2) When UE is in CM-IDLE state\n3) When UE is in CM-REGISTERED state\n4) When UE is in CM-DISCONNECTED state\n5) When UE is in CM-CONNECTED state\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 49, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  When UE is in CM-CONNECTED state", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can target UEs be positioned for lawful interception services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only if the target UE user authorizes it\n2) Only if the privacy attribute value allows positioning\n3) Under all circumstances required by local regulatory requirements\n4) Never\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 53, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Under all circumstances required by local regulatory requirements", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are DCI formats with CRC scrambled by MCCH-RNTI or G-RNTI referred to as? \n\nOptions:\n1) Multicast DCI formats\n2) Broadcast DCI formats\n3) Unicast DCI formats\n4) PUCCH DCI formats\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 60, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Broadcast DCI formats", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat kind of access can enterprise UEs have to non-public networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) Access to the non-public network of the enterprise only\n2) Access to both a non-public network and a PLMN\n3) Access to a PLMN only\n4) Access to a PLMN and a non-public network via a different network\n5) Access to a PLMN and a non-public network via multiple subscriptions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 70, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Access to both a non-public network and a PLMN", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the TRP Measurement Grid? \n\nOptions:\n1) To calculate the CDF of the EIRP/EIS distribution in 3D\n2) To determine the total power radiated by the DUT in the TX beam peak direction\n3) To determine the TX and RX beam peak direction\n4) To perform TRP measurements taken on the sampling grid\n5) To perform 3D Throughput/RSRP/EIS scans for RX beam peak direction\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 73, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To perform TRP measurements taken on the sampling grid", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat action is necessary to get access to services in Idle mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) Camping on a cell\n2) Performing location registration\n3) Performing CN type selection\n4) Performing RNA update\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 74, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Camping on a cell", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does EC-GSM-IoT improve coverage performance for Cellular IoT devices? \n\nOptions:\n1) By increasing the transmit power\n2) By reducing the MS complexity\n3) By using modified channel coding schemes\n4) By adding more timeslot resources\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 76, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By using modified channel coding schemes", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat triggers the NF/NF Service Context Transfer Push procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) The Target NF/NF Service receiving a notification about the decommissioning\n2) The Source NF informing the NRF about the decommissioning\n3) The Source NF sending a request to the Target NF/NF Service\n4) The Target NF/NF Service receiving a request from the Source NF/NF Service\n5) The Target NF/NF Service setting up necessary information about the new context location\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 80, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The Source NF sending a request to the Target NF/NF Service", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich 5G vertical domain is the maritime domain a part of? \n\nOptions:\n1) Public safety domain\n2) Automotive domain\n3) Factory automation domain\n4) Satellite industrial domain\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 87, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  None of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the User Configuration mechanism in the IMS Multimedia Telephony service? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support synchronization of communication logs between multiple devices\n2) To indicate which identities are active or inactive on a specific UE\n3) To provide user preferences for media handling capabilities\n4) To modify the Caller Identity Analytics function\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 96, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To indicate which identities are active or inactive on a specific UE", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of packet buffering in Edge Relocation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To prevent packet loss during EAS migration\n2) To optimize user plane latency\n3) To enable simultaneous connectivity over source and target PSA\n4) To eliminate the need for EAS IP replacement\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 100, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To prevent packet loss during EAS migration", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Multi-Identity (MiD) service enable? \n\nOptions:\n1) A user to use different UEs registered under different public user identities\n2) A user to use different identities on a single UE\n3) Call distribution to different members of a group or firm\n4) A user to share identities with another user\n5) A user to use different UEs that are registered under the same public user identity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 101, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  A user to use different identities on a single UE", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum number of PDU Sessions? \n\nOptions:\n1) 128\n2) 32\n3) 8\n4) 256\n5) 64\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 108, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  256", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identity is used for indication of pre-emption in the downlink? \n\nOptions:\n1) C-RNTI\n2) CI-RNTI\n3) CS-RNTI\n4) INT-RNTI\n5) P-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 111, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  INT-RNTI", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the group identifier called 'External Group ID'? \n\nOptions:\n1) To identify individual UEs within a group\n2) To resolve the group ID to individual UE ID\n3) To reduce signalling for sending event reports of group members\n4) To indicate the time for which monitoring event reporting can be aggregated\n5) To handle group-based enhancements in the network capability exposure function\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 121, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To resolve the group ID to individual UE ID", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can the V-SMF delete the DNS context from the selected V-EASDF? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the request for HR-SBO is not authorized\n2) When the V-SMF selects a new V-EASDF\n3) When the UE initiates a Mobility Registration Update procedure\n4) When the AF triggers EAS rediscovery\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 123, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  When the request for HR-SBO is not authorized", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a UE determine when selecting a power for an S-SS/PSBCH block transmission occasion? \n\nOptions:\n1) Value of dl-P0-PSBCH-r16\n2) Value of dl-Alpha-PSBCH\n3) Number of resource blocks for a S-SS/PSBCH block transmission\n4) Value of dl-P0-PSBCH-r17\n5) Value of dl-P0-PSBCH-r16 if provided, else dl-Alpha-PSBCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 135, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Value of dl-P0-PSBCH-r16 if provided, else dl-Alpha-PSBCH", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is supported in enhanced TTI bundling compared to Rel-13 CE mode A in eMTC? \n\nOptions:\n1) UL asynchronous HARQ transmission\n2) Different repetition levels of scheduled PUSCH\n3) Bundle frequency hopping\n4) Multi-subframe channel estimation\n5) HARQ process ID\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 140, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Different repetition levels of scheduled PUSCH", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the MasterInformationBlockSidelink message? \n\nOptions:\n1) To request UE sidelink capabilities\n2) To indicate the failure of a PC5 RRC AS reconfiguration\n3) To transfer UE radio access capabilities\n4) To include sidelink DRX assistance information used to determine the sidelink DRX configuration\n5) To include the system information transmitted by a UE via SL-BCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 141, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To include the system information transmitted by a UE via SL-BCH", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the indication used to invoke the terminal application in the peer end of a multimedia call? \n\nOptions:\n1) H.243 information\n2) H.223 and H.245 information\n3) Call Control Capabilities information\n4) H.324 information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 143, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  H.324 information", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of the bearer control function? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide interfaces for supplementary services\n2) To define the characteristics of bearers\n3) To assign and release bearers for a call\n4) To enable subscribers to control services\n5) To adapt bearers for fixed network use\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 146, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To assign and release bearers for a call", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of interworking between a 5G core network and an EPC? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support home network provided data connectivity\n2) To preserve IP address for PS service\n3) To provide support for services in the home network\n4) To support mobility procedures with minimum impact to the user experience\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 149, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To support mobility procedures with minimum impact to the user experience", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Relaxed monitoring for cell reselection feature in NB-IoT allow the UE to do? \n\nOptions:\n1) Avoid monitoring neighbouring cells for 24 hours in stationary or non-changing network topology\n2) Request NPUSCH resources for BSR transmission\n3) Reduce system acquisition time for the UE\n4) Support small cell deployments with lower maximum transmit power\n5) Improve the accuracy of narrowband measurement\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 152, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Avoid monitoring neighbouring cells for 24 hours in stationary or non-changing network topology", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens during session termination in online charging? \n\nOptions:\n1) The resource usage is debited from the subscriber account immediately\n2) The network element sends an interim charging event\n3) A certain amount of units is blocked on the subscriber's account\n4) The CDF produces a matching CDR\n5) The value of unused quota is returned to the subscriber's account\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 159, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The value of unused quota is returned to the subscriber's account", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nCan any party in a multiparty call undergo voice call continuity? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes, any party in a multiparty call can undergo voice call continuity\n2) No, only the calling party can undergo voice call continuity\n3) No, only the called party can undergo voice call continuity\n4) No, voice call continuity is not supported for multiparty calls\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 173, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Yes, any party in a multiparty call can undergo voice call continuity", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is covered by enhanced application layer support for V2X services? \n\nOptions:\n1) PC5 radio resource control\n2) Advanced V2X services\n3) SDAP layer enhancements\n4) V2X communication over NR PC5 reference point\n5) Tele-Operated Driving\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 179, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Advanced V2X services", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the UE Capability Management Function (UCMF)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To store UE radio capability IDs\n2) To assign UE radio capability IDs\n3) To provision UE radio capability IDs\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 184, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does a non-supporting UE select a core network operator to serve it in a shared network? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE selects an operator from the available CN operators.\n2) The shared network selects an operator for the UE.\n3) The RAN routes the UE to an available CN node.\n4) The BSC/RNC/eNodeB relays the chosen operator to the core network node.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 185, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The shared network selects an operator for the UE.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nFor PSFCH transmission with HARQ-ACK information, how are the PRBs allocated? \n\nOptions:\n1) In an ascending order of the PRB index only\n2) In an ascending order of the cyclic shift pair index only\n3) In an ascending order of both the PRB index and the cyclic shift pair index\n4) In a random order\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 187, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  In an ascending order of both the PRB index and the cyclic shift pair index", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the energy detection threshold in channel access procedures? \n\nOptions:\n1) The maximum eNB/gNB output power in dBm for the channel\n2) The single channel bandwidth in MHz\n3) The absence of any other technology sharing the channel\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 188, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Load-Balancing steering mode do? \n\nOptions:\n1) Splits the traffic of a data flow across 3GPP and non-3GPP accesses\n2) Balances the load on the core network nodes\n3) Restricts the UE to a single access type\n4) Improves network performance measurements\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 191, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Splits the traffic of a data flow across 3GPP and non-3GPP accesses", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the home environment need to provide to the visited network when allowing a subscriber to roam to different domains? \n\nOptions:\n1) Service data\n2) Authentication data\n3) Subscription data\n4) Capabilities data\n5) Roaming agreement data\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 194, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Subscription data", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does VarConnEstFailReportList include? \n\nOptions:\n1) Information about connection resume successes\n2) Information about connection establishment successes\n3) Information about connection resume failures\n4) Information about connection establishment failures\n5) Information about successful handovers\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 195, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Information about connection establishment failures", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used to transfer short messages between the SGSN and SMS-GMSC/SMS-IWMSC? \n\nOptions:\n1) Gn/Gp-interface\n2) Gr-interface\n3) Gs-interface\n4) Gb-interface\n5) Gd-interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 198, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Gd-interface", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the RRC protocol offer to upper layers? \n\nOptions:\n1) Broadcast of common control information\n2) Notification of UEs in RRC_IDLE\n3) Transfer of dedicated signalling\n4) Broadcast of positioning assistance data\n5) Transfer of application layer measurement configuration and reporting\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 203, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Broadcast of common control information", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is SIPTO at the Local Network? \n\nOptions:\n1) A collocated L-GW in the eNB\n2) A standalone GW\n3) A collocated S-GW and L-GW in the eNB\n4) A collocated MME and S-GW\n5) A collocated MME and L-GW\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 206, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  A collocated L-GW in the eNB", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn the indirect communication model without delegated discovery, what is the role of the SCP? \n\nOptions:\n1) It authorizes the NF service consumer's request\n2) It selects the NF service producer instance for the NF service consumer\n3) It stores and marks the NF service consumer as available\n4) It routes the request from the NF service consumer to the selected NF service producer instance\n5) It notifies the NF service consumer of newly registered/updated/deregistered NF instances\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 216, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  It routes the request from the NF service consumer to the selected NF service producer instance", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is Paging with Wake Up Signal (WUS) used? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the UE is in RRC_INACTIVE state\n2) When the UE is in RRC_IDLE state\n3) When the UE detects a PTW\n4) When the UE supports DRX\n5) When the UE supports GWUS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 225, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  When the UE is in RRC_IDLE state", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn unpaired spectrum operation, when are a DL BWP and an UL BWP linked together? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the DL BWP index and the UL BWP index are the same\n2) When the center frequency for both BWP is the same\n3) When they have the same SCS configuration\n4) When they have the same number of RB sets\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 233, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  When the DL BWP index and the UL BWP index are the same", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is Extended Access Barring supported in shared networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) The BSC/RNC/eNodeB configures the UE for access barring.\n2) The shared network applies access barring uniformly for all UEs.\n3) The UE requests access barring for specific operators.\n4) The BSC/RNC/eNodeB provides independent support for each sharing operator.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 244, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The BSC/RNC/eNodeB provides independent support for each sharing operator.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the peak packet data rates supported by the Evolved Packet System on the radio access bearer? \n\nOptions:\n1) 100 Mbps downlink and 50 Mbps uplink\n2) 50 Mbps downlink and 100 Mbps uplink\n3) 100 Mbps both downlink and uplink\n4) 50 Mbps both downlink and uplink\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 249, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  100 Mbps downlink and 50 Mbps uplink", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a Personal IoT Network (PIN)? \n\nOptions:\n1) A network located within a residence, office or shop that provides connectivity to the 5G network.\n2) A network owned, installed, and configured by a public network operator.\n3) A network that consists of PIN Elements and communicates using PIN Direct Connection.\n4) A network that supports mechanisms for identifying a PIN, PIN Element, eRG, and PRAS.\n5) A network that supports regulatory requirements for emergency calls, PWS, and eCall for UEs connected via 3GPP access.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 257, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  A network that consists of PIN Elements and communicates using PIN Direct Connection.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat criteria are considered for network broadcast geographic area coverage management? \n\nOptions:\n1) OTT provider request and available network capacity\n2) OTT provider request and number of users under broadcast network coverage\n3) Location information of UE and number of users under broadcast network coverage\n4) OTT provider request and location information of UE\n5) Number of users under broadcast network coverage and available network capacity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 268, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  OTT provider request and number of users under broadcast network coverage", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the 5G system need to provide for mobile base station relays using 5G connectivity provided by a different MNO? \n\nOptions:\n1) Separate network infrastructure for MNO-B to communicate with MNO-A through the relay\n2) Specific QoS handling for traffic relayed through the MNO-B's network\n3) Ability for MNO-A and MNO-B to share relay resources for UEs connected to the 5G network\n4) Authorization from MNO-A for MNO-B to provide 5G connectivity through the relay\n5) Ownership and control of the relay by MNO-A despite using connectivity from MNO-B\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 279, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Ability for MNO-A and MNO-B to share relay resources for UEs connected to the 5G network", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can a UE apply Type 1 channel access procedures for a UL transmission(s)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Before receiving the corresponding capability\n2) After performing Type 2 channel access procedures\n3) After receiving the corresponding capability\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 281, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  After receiving the corresponding capability", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich power saving scheme achieves power consumption reduction by potentially skipping PDCCH monitoring at subsequent slots of PDSCH/PUSCH transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) Cross-slot scheduling\n2) Same slot scheduling\n3) Multi-slot scheduling\n4) Dynamic DRX configuration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 282, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Multi-slot scheduling", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of authentication and authorization is required for accessing a 5G VN group? \n\nOptions:\n1) No authentication/authorization is required\n2) Primary 5G VN group authentication/authorization\n3) Individual UE authentication/authorization\n4) Common DN authentication/authorization\n5) Secondary authentication/authorization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 289, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Secondary authentication/authorization", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the timing advance command for a TAG indicate? \n\nOptions:\n1) Change of synchronization signal transmission timing\n2) Change of downlink timing relative to the current downlink timing\n3) Change of uplink timing relative to the current uplink timing\n4) Change of broadcast channel transmission timing\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 290, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Change of uplink timing relative to the current uplink timing", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can be configured separately for each SPS configuration in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) The time reference\n2) The PDCP duplication settings\n3) The cyclic shift for the UL Demodulation Reference Signal (DMRS)\n4) The allocated RBs (Resource Blocks)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 296, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The cyclic shift for the UL Demodulation Reference Signal (DMRS)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the supported scenarios for MPS for MMTEL voice? \n\nOptions:\n1) MPS for MMTEL voice and voice conference calls for an authorized Service User using a UE with an MPS subscription\n2) MPS for MMTEL voice and voice conference calls for an authorized Service User using a UE that does not have an MPS subscription\n3) MPS for all participants of an authorized MMTEL voice conference call\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 303, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the high quality criterion for reporting a PLMN to the NAS in the E-UTRA and NB-IoT case? \n\nOptions:\n1) Measured RSRP value greater than or equal to -110 dBm\n2) Measured RSRP value less than -110 dBm\n3) Measured RSRP value greater than or equal to -100 dBm\n4) Measured RSRP value less than -100 dBm\n5) Measured RSRP value greater than or equal to -120 dBm\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 313, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Measured RSRP value greater than or equal to -110 dBm", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat power saving gain range is observed for the power saving scheme with UE adaptation to the number of antenna/MIMO layer? \n\nOptions:\n1) 3% - 20%\n2) 6% - 30%\n3) 15% - 45%\n4) 30% - 280%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 316, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  6% - 30%", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the SIP Reason header extension work item do? \n\nOptions:\n1) Specifies procedures for interworking of eCall over IMS to CS domain\n2) Introduces password protection for activation of supplementary services in IMS\n3) Ensures consistency of all the possible extensions of the SIP Reason header field\n4) Provides media handling extensions for IMS-based telepresence\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 318, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Ensures consistency of all the possible extensions of the SIP Reason header field", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main objective of intent driven management for service or network management? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support monitoring of the progress of file download in a downloading job\n2) To provide detailed knowledge of the underlying network resources\n3) To optimize the provisioning of management services for UEs in a specified area\n4) To reduce the complexity of management for network resources\n5) To enhance the support for the NSA in the service-based management architecture\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 319, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To reduce the complexity of management for network resources", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the RRC buffer size for a UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) 45 MB\n2) 45 KB\n3) 45 GB\n4) 45 TB\n5) 4500 KB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 325, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  45 KB", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the ECS provide to the EEC? \n\nOptions:\n1) Edge configuration information\n2) EAS configuration information\n3) Network capability information\n4) Application Data Traffic\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 338, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Edge configuration information", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nAre the MuD and MiD services mutually exclusive? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes, a user can only use either MuD or MiD service at a time\n2) No, they can both be used at the same time\n3) No, a user can switch between MuD and MiD services\n4) Yes, a user can only use MuD service on one type of UE and MiD service on another\n5) No, a user can only use either MuD or MiD service based on their subscription\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 360, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  No, they can both be used at the same time", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the feature 'Accessing a list of deferred data communications' enable for the MCData service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Sharing the current MCData system defined status\n2) Real-time updates of changes to group dynamic data\n3) Sending an application level message to MCData clients\n4) Temporary storage of data communications\n5) Extending the MCData application identifier\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 366, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Temporary storage of data communications", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the enhancements specified for the 3GPP Northbound APIs in Release 16? \n\nOptions:\n1) Optimization of APIs\n2) Handling communication failure cases\n3) HTTP-based protocol or OpenAPI file improvements\n4) Additional deployment models\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 368, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere is the UE Radio Capability ID signaled by the UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Over Uu interface between the UE and the CN\n2) Within the RAN in handover procedures\n3) Within the CN\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 383, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is one of the requirements for interworking between fixed access and Evolved Packet Core? \n\nOptions:\n1) Efficient usage of system resources\n2) Policy management and authentication for WLAN terminals\n3) Routing different PDN connections through different accesses\n4) Support for simultaneous access to PLMN services\n5) Support for offline charging for traffic routed via the Evolved Packet Core\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 384, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Routing different PDN connections through different accesses", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the modulation order (Qm) and target code rate (R) determined for PSSCH transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) Based on the DM-RS configuration\n2) Based on the MCS table\n3) Based on the number of REs in the slot\n4) Based on the redundancy version\n5) Based on the number of DMRS port\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 388, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Based on the MCS table", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat inputs are required for the Nmfaf_3daDataManagement_Configure service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Data Consumer or Analytics Consumer Information\n2) Formatting Instructions, Processing Instructions, MFAF Notification Information, Transaction Reference Id, ADRF ID\n3) Notification Correlation Information\n4) Set of Fetch Correlation ID(s)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 398, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Data Consumer or Analytics Consumer Information", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the enhanced RRM requirements in DRX in connected mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reduced cell identification delay and measurement period.\n2) Reduced cell detection delay, measurement period, and evaluation time.\n3) Reduced cell identification delay, measurement period, and evaluation time.\n4) Reduced cell detection delay and measurement period.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 405, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Reduced cell identification delay and measurement period.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich TS specification defines the Proximity-based Services (ProSe) architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.401\n2) TS 23.228\n3) TS 23.303\n4) TS 23.468\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 408, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS 23.303", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich parameter in SL-TxProfileList-r17 indicates compatibility with DRX? \n\nOptions:\n1) spare1\n2) spare2\n3) drx-Compatible\n4) drx-Incompatible\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 414, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  drx-Compatible", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn the context of pathloss models, what is O2I? \n\nOptions:\n1) Over-to-Inaction\n2) Out-of-Office\n3) On-to-Infinity\n4) Outdoor to Indoor\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 417, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Outdoor to Indoor", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is true about services not mentioned within the interaction clause? \n\nOptions:\n1) They have no impact on other supplementary services\n2) They are mandatory for IMS Multimedia Telephony service\n3) They are optional for IMS Multimedia Telephony service\n4) They are applicable to UE accessing IMS via 3GPP accesses\n5) They are applicable to CEPT members\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 419, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  They have no impact on other supplementary services", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the 5G system need to support for a UE accessing multiple network slices? \n\nOptions:\n1) Access to the most suitable network slice in minimum time\n2) Minimization of power consumption\n3) Minimization of service interruption time\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 437, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat QoS characteristics does the MPS system support? \n\nOptions:\n1) Specific QoS characteristics for MPS Voice, Video, and Data\n2) Equal QoS characteristics for all MPS sessions\n3) No QoS characteristics for MPS sessions\n4) Priority QoS characteristics for MPS sessions\n5) Higher QoS characteristics for MPS Voice than Video or Data\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 441, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Specific QoS characteristics for MPS Voice, Video, and Data", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the key functionalities supported by the common services core in MC services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Group management\n2) User authentication\n3) Service configurations\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 449, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the 5G system prevent in terms of privacy for UEs using 5G LAN-type service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Sharing of UE's identifying information\n2) Sharing of UE's IP address\n3) Sharing of UE's location information\n4) Sharing of UE's communication history\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 454, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Sharing of UE's identifying information", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich 3GPP specification specifies the architecture for enabling Edge Applications in 5GS? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.501\n2) TS 23.502\n3) TS 23.558\n4) TS 23.548\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 456, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS 23.558", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is associated with a time and/or date setting in the IMS Multimedia Telephony service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Media capabilities\n2) Caller identity verification results\n3) Activation, deactivation, and invocation of services\n4) Allow/block lists for service activation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 463, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Activation, deactivation, and invocation of services", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the EAS discovery in the application layer architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide mechanisms for an EEC to discover available EASs\n2) To provide relevant configuration information of the EASs to the EEC\n3) To support exposure of 3GPP network's capabilities to the EASs\n4) To support exposure of EES's capabilities to the EASs\n5) To support exposure of EAS's capabilities to the other EASs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 468, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide mechanisms for an EEC to discover available EASs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich entities can consume Management Data Analytics Service (MDAS)? \n\nOptions:\n1) MnFs, NFs, SON functions, SLS assurance functions, human operators, and AFs\n2) MnS producers, NWDAF, network and service optimization tools/functions, and AFs\n3) Producers and consumers of network and service management\n4) MnFs, NFs, SON functions, and AFs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 470, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  MnFs, NFs, SON functions, SLS assurance functions, human operators, and AFs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich solutions in LTE support configurable reliability and latency combinations? \n\nOptions:\n1) Semi-static CFI configuration and PDSCH repetition\n2) UL SPS repetition and PDCP packet duplication\n3) Granular time reference provision and PDCP packet duplication\n4) PDSCH repetition and Granular time reference provision\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 475, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Semi-static CFI configuration and PDSCH repetition", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of frames does the Ethernet transport service need to support? \n\nOptions:\n1) IP frames\n2) TCP frames\n3) Ethernet frames\n4) UDP frames\n5) DNS frames\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 478, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Ethernet frames", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the typical connection density in factory automation applications? \n\nOptions:\n1) 10 connections per 10 m2\n2) 1 connection per 100 m3\n3) 10 connections per km2\n4) 100 connections per factory hall\n5) 1,000 connections per 1,000 m2\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 483, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  10 connections per km2", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Common API Framework (CAPIF) for 3GPP Northbound APIs? \n\nOptions:\n1) To define a standard API framework for 3rd party Application Servers\n2) To handle communication failure cases\n3) To optimize the 3GPP Northbound APIs\n4) To specify the xMB API for MBMS\n5) To support the implementation of SEAL services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 499, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To define a standard API framework for 3rd party Application Servers", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are capability parameters signalled in the corresponding FSs for intra-band contiguous CA? \n\nOptions:\n1) Per band\n2) Per carrier\n3) Per feature set\n4) Per block of contiguous serving cells\n5) Per duplex mode\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 506, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Per block of contiguous serving cells", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Enhanced TNL Address Discovery with the X2 GW? \n\nOptions:\n1) To route X2AP messages between (H)eNBs\n2) To detect (H)eNB unavailability\n3) To register (H)eNBs with the X2 GW\n4) To enhance the TNL address discovery procedure\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 530, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To enhance the TNL address discovery procedure", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of providing secure means for communication scheduling information to an NPN in a 5G network? \n\nOptions:\n1) To perform network energy saving and network resource optimization\n2) To assign a UE to a network slice used for the third-party\n3) To expose broadcasting capabilities to trusted third-party broadcasters' management systems\n4) To allow a third-party to manage this trusted third-party owned application(s) in the operator's Service Hosting Environment\n5) To monitor the resource utilization of the network service that are associated with the third-party\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 539, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To perform network energy saving and network resource optimization", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the ThreshServingOffloadWLAN parameters used for? \n\nOptions:\n1) To specify the WLAN channel utilization threshold.\n2) To define the RSRP threshold for traffic steering from WLAN to E-UTRAN.\n3) To specify the WLAN RSSI threshold in dB.\n4) To determine the timer value for traffic steering between E-UTRAN and WLAN.\n5) To define the RSRP threshold for traffic steering from E-UTRAN to WLAN.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 540, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To define the RSRP threshold for traffic steering from E-UTRAN to WLAN.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nFor FR2-2 measurement system, what is the minimum channel bandwidth required for modelling multi-path fading in single carrier scenarios? \n\nOptions:\n1) 400 MHz\n2) 200 MHz\n3) 600 MHz\n4) 100 MHz\n5) 300 MHz\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 548, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  400 MHz", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does 5GS act as when integrated with IEEE TSN network? \n\nOptions:\n1) Layer 2 Ethernet Bridge\n2) TSN AF\n3) DetNet Router\n4) Transport Network Controller\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 552, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Layer 2 Ethernet Bridge", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the scrambling sequence generator initialized with for a PDCCH with the CRC scrambled by G-RNTI in a common search space? \n\nOptions:\n1) dataScramblingIdentityPDSCH\n2) dataScramblingIdentityPDSCH2\n3) C-RNTI\n4) MCS-C-RNTI\n5) CS-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 558, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  dataScramblingIdentityPDSCH", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich RRC state is the UE in when no RRC connection is established? \n\nOptions:\n1) RRC_UNAVAILABLE\n2) RRC_INACTIVE\n3) RRC_CONNECTED\n4) RRC_DISCONNECTED\n5) RRC_IDLE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 563, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  RRC_IDLE", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the management aspects addressed by the OAM_LTE_WLAN work item? \n\nOptions:\n1) Energy efficiency\n2) Network and service management\n3) LTE and WLAN integration\n4) Methodology for 5G management\n5) Closed loop SLS assurance\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 564, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  LTE and WLAN integration", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are the antenna elements placed on each antenna panel? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only in the vertical direction\n2) Only in the horizontal direction\n3) In both the vertical and horizontal directions\n4) In a random arrangement\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 566, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  In both the vertical and horizontal directions", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the map-based hybrid channel model? \n\nOptions:\n1) To calibrate the channel model for different companies\n2) To evaluate system performance using a digital map\n3) To generate large-scale parameters for random clusters\n4) To calculate angular spreads for each cluster\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 577, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To evaluate system performance using a digital map", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat types of services can be included in a subscription? \n\nOptions:\n1) Basic Services, PS services, and IM-Services\n2) Teleservices, Bearer services, and Value added services\n3) PS CN service profile and QoS parameter ranges\n4) Network operator services and value added services\n5) Access services and radio access systems\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 589, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Basic Services, PS services, and IM-Services", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of the serving network in fraud control? \n\nOptions:\n1) To process charging information in real time\n2) To collect charging information from network elements\n3) To handle cost control mechanisms\n4) To meter charge flows independently\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 596, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To collect charging information from network elements", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information may be provided to an emergency services LCS Client without any request? \n\nOptions:\n1) Geographic location\n2) Dispatchable Location\n3) Both 1 and 2\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 604, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both 1 and 2", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the term for the interference between UL transmission in one cell and DL reception in another cell? \n\nOptions:\n1) Remote interference\n2) Backhaul-based interference\n3) CLI interference\n4) RIM interference\n5) Semi-static interference\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 609, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  CLI interference", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich keys are derived from KAMF for the protection of NAS signaling? \n\nOptions:\n1) KNASint and KNASenc\n2) KUPint and KUPenc\n3) KRRCint and KRRCenc\n4) KgNB and NH\n5) NH and KAMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 619, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  KNASint and KNASenc", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can be part of the 3GPP PS Data Off Exempt Services? \n\nOptions:\n1) VoLTE calls\n2) SMS over IMS\n3) USSD over IMS\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 621, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the components of the Charging Trigger Function (CTF)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Accounting Metrics Collection and Accounting Data Forwarding\n2) Account Balance Management Function and Charging Gateway Function\n3) Charging Data Function and Rating Function\n4) Online Charging Function and Event Based Charging Function\n5) Charging Data Function and Charging Gateway Function\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 628, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Accounting Metrics Collection and Accounting Data Forwarding", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are some examples of UICC applications? \n\nOptions:\n1) USIM and ISIM\n2) Identity management and banking applications\n3) Electronic commerce applications\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 631, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does V2X stand for in the context of the document? \n\nOptions:\n1) Vehicle-to-Infrastructure\n2) Vehicle-to-Vehicle\n3) Vehicle-to-Internet\n4) Vehicle-to-Pedestrian\n5) Vehicle-to-Everything\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 634, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Vehicle-to-Everything", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the NWDAF collect information from the UPF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Via NEF(PFDF)\n2) Via NRF\n3) Via SMF\n4) Directly from UPF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 636, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Via SMF", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does a Multi-USIM UE indicate the supported Multi-USIM features to the AMF during the Registration procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) When it has more than one USIM active\n2) When it has only one USIM active\n3) When it requests connection release\n4) When it requests paging restriction\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 638, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  When it has more than one USIM active", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can the network request the mobile station to change the UMTS codec during a speech call? \n\nOptions:\n1) By sending a MODIFY message to the mobile station\n2) By sending a SETUP message to the mobile station\n3) By sending a NOTIFY message to the mobile station\n4) By sending the new selected codec type in the NAS Synchronisation Indicator IE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 643, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  By sending the new selected codec type in the NAS Synchronisation Indicator IE", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of inter-network settlement mechanisms? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allow real-time processing of charging data\n2) To enable fraud control between home environments and serving networks\n3) To handle cost control mechanisms\n4) To determine payments between parties on a periodic basis\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 644, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To determine payments between parties on a periodic basis", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat enhancements were introduced in Release-14 for LTE-WLAN Aggregation (LWA)? \n\nOptions:\n1) UL aggregation on LTE and WLAN\n2) Support for 60GHz 802.11 band\n3) Neighbour eNB reporting for ANR and WLAN suspend/resume\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 646, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of cross-network slice coordination? \n\nOptions:\n1) To coordinate network slices in multiple 5G networks\n2) To prevent unauthorized access to network slices\n3) To optimize resource utilization in a network\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 647, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To coordinate network slices in multiple 5G networks", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Rel. 16 feature of Subscription information allow? \n\nOptions:\n1) Indication of existing identifiers relating to a 3GPP subscription or UE\n2) Selection of an AMF that supports the required Network Slices\n3) Authentication and authorization of User Identity for a network slice\n4) Indication of which S-NSSAIs are subject to Network Slice-Specific Authentication and Authorization\n5) Creation and management of User Identities\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 648, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Indication of which S-NSSAIs are subject to Network Slice-Specific Authentication and Authorization", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of control plane load control, congestion and overload control in the 5G System? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide connectivity and necessary services to the UE\n2) To ensure that the UE is always connected to the 5G-AN\n3) To balance the load between AMFs in the same AMF set\n4) To prioritize emergency services over regular services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 649, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide connectivity and necessary services to the UE", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is the authorization for connectivity and services evaluated? \n\nOptions:\n1) During network selection\n2) During identification and authentication\n3) During access control and barring\n4) During UE Registration\n5) During lawful interception\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 652, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  During UE Registration", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the LMF connected to the NG-RAN node in the positioning architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through the PCF\n2) Through the 5GC\n3) Directly\n4) Through the SMF\n5) Through the AMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 654, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Through the AMF", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the SCEF+NEF node in the non-roaming architecture for Service Exposure? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide southbound interfaces between SCEF and EPC nodes\n2) To associate the UE with an SCEF+NEF node for Service Capability Exposure\n3) To support monitoring APIs between SCEF and NEF\n4) To discover the north-bound APIs supported by EPC or 5GC network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 658, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To associate the UE with an SCEF+NEF node for Service Capability Exposure", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a RedCap UE expect if it monitors PDCCH according to Type1-PDCCH CSS set and does not monitor PDCCH according to Type2-PDCCH CSS set? \n\nOptions:\n1) The initial DL BWP to include SS/PBCH blocks and the CORESET with index 0\n2) The initial DL BWP to exclude SS/PBCH blocks and the CORESET with index 0\n3) The active DL BWP to include SS/PBCH blocks and the CORESET with index 0\n4) The active DL BWP to exclude SS/PBCH blocks and the CORESET with index 0\n5) No expectation regarding the inclusion or exclusion of SS/PBCH blocks and the CORESET with index 0\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 669, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The initial DL BWP to exclude SS/PBCH blocks and the CORESET with index 0", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat key information is used by the Terminating Access Domain Selection (T-ADS) mechanism? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE's current access network\n2) UE's IMS registration status\n3) UE's WLAN AP association status\n4) UE's time stamps of most recent IMS registration or re-registration and radio contact with the access network\n5) UE's WLAN encryption keys\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 671, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  UE's time stamps of most recent IMS registration or re-registration and radio contact with the access network", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich channels are used for the performance requirements in Narrowband IoT? \n\nOptions:\n1) NPUSCH format1\n2) NPUSCH format2\n3) NPRACH\n4) PUCCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 674, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  NPRACH", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which operation does the UDM update session management subscriber data stored in the SMF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Nudm_SDM_Notification service operation\n2) Nudr_DM_Unsubscribe for the data\n3) Nudm_UECM_Deregistration request (SUPI, NF ID, Access Type) operation\n4) Nudr_DM_Update (SUPI, Subscription Data)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 681, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Nudm_SDM_Notification service operation", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does QCI-1 represent in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Best effort\n2) Real-time interactive\n3) Streaming\n4) Background\n5) Signaling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 688, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Real-time interactive", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich physical channel informs the UE and the RN about the number of OFDM symbols used for the PDCCHs? \n\nOptions:\n1) PBCH\n2) PCFICH\n3) PDSCH\n4) PHICH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 702, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  PCFICH", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specification specifies the Support of NR MBS in non-split gNB case? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.501\n2) TS 36.300\n3) TS 38.300\n4) TS 38.305\n5) TS 38.400\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 710, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS 38.300", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of reports are used to support QoS-aware packet scheduling in the uplink? \n\nOptions:\n1) Delay reports\n2) Power headroom reports\n3) Transmission reports\n4) Uplink buffer status reports\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 715, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Uplink buffer status reports", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the ePWS feature? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enhance the Public Warning System by improving the comprehension of Warning Notifications for users with disabilities and non-fluent users\n2) To define behaviours for UEs with no user interface\n3) To specify additional requirements for PWS-UEs\n4) To enable language-independent content in Warning Notifications\n5) To specify how graphical symbols or images can be used in Warning Notifications\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 716, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enhance the Public Warning System by improving the comprehension of Warning Notifications for users with disabilities and non-fluent users", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when the Control Plane data back-off timer is running? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE cannot initiate any data transfer via Control Plane CIoT 5GS Optimization\n2) The AMF stops processing any further requests (except for exception reporting and paging response) for data transport via Control Plane Service Request from that UE\n3) The UE is allowed to initiate Service Request procedures for activating User Plane connection\n4) The UE is allowed to initiate Session Management procedures for emergency services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 717, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The UE cannot initiate any data transfer via Control Plane CIoT 5GS Optimization", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main role of the DeNB in the mobility of a UE to or from an RN? \n\nOptions:\n1) To trigger the S1 or X2 handover procedure for the UE\n2) To provide GUMMEI information to the RN\n3) To update the cell information of the RN\n4) To transfer neighbouring information to the RN\n5) To initiate the RRC connection establishment for the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 721, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To trigger the S1 or X2 handover procedure for the UE", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich reference point is between SMF and the CHF in the same PLMN? \n\nOptions:\n1) N28\n2) N40\n3) N41\n4) N42\n5) N44\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 731, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  N40", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Nnef_MSISDN-less_MO_SMS service? \n\nOptions:\n1) To send the MSISDN-less MO SMS to the AF.\n2) To request the network to send an Application trigger to the UE.\n3) To resolve the GPSI to SUPI when the AF is authorized to trigger the UE.\n4) To retrieve the UE SMSF identities.\n5) To create, update, or delete the group-level N4 session for a 5G VN group.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 754, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To send the MSISDN-less MO SMS to the AF.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn a split gNB architecture, how is RACH configuration conflict resolved? \n\nOptions:\n1) The gNB-CU reassigns a new PCI for NR cells suffering PCI conflict.\n2) The gNB-DU reports RACH configuration conflict to the gNB-CU.\n3) The gNB-DU signals the PRACH configuration per-cell to the gNB-CU.\n4) The gNB-CU merges the outgoing RIM information received from its gNB-DUs.\n5) The gNB-CU forwards neighbor cell's PRACH configurations to the gNB-DU.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 761, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The gNB-CU forwards neighbor cell's PRACH configurations to the gNB-DU.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich positioning techniques are supported in the NR positioning work item? \n\nOptions:\n1) DL TDOA, DL AoD, MLAT, NR E-CID\n2) UL TDOA, UL AoA (Azimuth and Zenith), OTDOA, GNSS SSR\n3) DL TDOA, DL AoD, UL TDOA, UL AoA (Azimuth and Zenith), Multi-RTT, NR E-CID\n4) UL TDOA, UL AoA (Azimuth and Zenith), GNSS SSR, PPP-RTK\n5) DL TDOA, DL AoD, Multi-RTT, NR E-CID, GNSS SSR\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 763, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  DL TDOA, DL AoD, UL TDOA, UL AoA (Azimuth and Zenith), Multi-RTT, NR E-CID", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the observed range of BS energy savings when the traffic is reduced for BWP adaptation within a carrier? \n\nOptions:\n1) 17.4%~52.2%\n2) 28.4%~14.47%\n3) 6.44%~39.4%\n4) negative %\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 767, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  17.4%~52.2%", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat should the UE do when checking access Class or ACDC category related cell access restrictions during RRC connection establishment for E-UTRA connected to EPC? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ignore the access restrictions\n2) Reject the cell for camping on\n3) Trigger cell reselection\n4) Check the access restrictions and proceed accordingly\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 773, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Check the access restrictions and proceed accordingly", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does MINT stand for? \n\nOptions:\n1) Maximum Internet Network Transmission\n2) Minimization of Interruption Network Technology\n3) Maximization of Internet Network Traffic\n4) Minimization of Service Interruption\n5) Maximum Internet Network Technology\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 797, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Minimization of Service Interruption", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the two main types of multimedia services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Interactive and distribution services\n2) Conversational and messaging services\n3) Retrieval and distribution services\n4) Broadcast and retrieval services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 799, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Interactive and distribution services", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many demodulation branches are the radiated performance requirements limited to for SAN type 1-O? \n\nOptions:\n1) Up to 2 demodulation branches\n2) Up to 4 demodulation branches\n3) Up to 1 demodulation branch\n4) Up to 3 demodulation branches\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 812, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Up to 2 demodulation branches", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is DCP configured on the PCell? \n\nOptions:\n1) When DRX is not configured\n2) When BA is not configured\n3) When CA is not configured\n4) When BA and CA are not configured\n5) When CA is configured\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 813, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  When CA is configured", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a requirement for clock synchronisation of the 5G system? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Support for IEEE 1588v2\n2) Support for 3rd-party applications\n3) Synchronize UEs with a working clock\n4) Support for multiple sync domains\n5) Interface for IEEE 802.1AS sync domains\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 815, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Interface for IEEE 802.1AS sync domains", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identity is used for identification of the Random Access Response in the downlink? \n\nOptions:\n1) CI-RNTI\n2) RA-RNTI\n3) Temporary C-RNTI\n4) Random value for contention resolution\n5) I-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 818, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  RA-RNTI", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Service Enabler Architecture Layer (SEAL) for Verticals? \n\nOptions:\n1) To specify application layer support for V2X\n2) To define common capabilities for mission critical services\n3) To provide a common API framework for 3GPP Northbound APIs\n4) To enhance the topology of SMF and UPF in 5G networks\n5) To support MBMS APIs for Mission Critical Services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 823, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To define common capabilities for mission critical services", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which mode does an MS store the forbidden tracking area identity (TAI) in a list for regional provision of service? \n\nOptions:\n1) A/Gb mode\n2) Iu mode\n3) S1-mode\n4) N1-mode\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 824, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  S1-mode", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the requirements for relay UE selection for Evolved ProSe Remote UE access? \n\nOptions:\n1) Selection based on the subscription owner of the Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay\n2) Selection based on the QoS achievable by the Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay\n3) Selection based on the power consumption required by the Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay and Evolved ProSe Remote UE\n4) Selection based on the access technology used by the Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 832, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the term used to describe an end user device replacing the UE that does not support 5G capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) Wireless and Wireline Convergence Enhancement\n2) Trusted Non-3GPP Access Network\n3) Wireline Access Gateway Function (W-AGF)\n4) Fixed Wireless Access (FWA)\n5) FN-RG\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 835, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  FN-RG", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which specification are the training guidelines for MDA ML entities given? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 28.105\n2) TS 28.511\n3) TS 28.531\n4) TS 28.552\n5) TS 32.422\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 836, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  TS 28.105", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum frequency considered for the SNR calculation in band n263? \n\nOptions:\n1) 43.5 GHz\n2) 48.2 GHz\n3) 71 GHz\n4) 90 GHz\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 849, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  71 GHz", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum value of E-UTRA carrier frequency? \n\nOptions:\n1) 262143\n2) 3279165\n3) 8\n4) 1280\n5) 512\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 855, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  262143", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the numerology based on for PSS, SSS, and PBCH? \n\nOptions:\n1) Bandwidth-dependent sub-carrier spacing\n2) Fixed sub-carrier spacing\n3) Exponentially scalable sub-carrier spacing\n4) Carrier-dependent sub-carrier spacing\n5) Symbol duration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 856, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Exponentially scalable sub-carrier spacing", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of model can the consumer request for QoS Sustainability analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) Subscribe-Notify model\n2) Request-Response model\n3) Both Subscribe-Notify and Request-Response models\n4) Neither Subscribe-Notify nor Request-Response models\n5) It is not specified in the document\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 863, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both Subscribe-Notify and Request-Response models", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when a mobile station (MS) attempts to camp on a cell for which it does not have service entitlement? \n\nOptions:\n1) The MS is granted access to the cell without any restrictions.\n2) The MS is denied access to the cell and enters a limited service state.\n3) The MS is allowed access to the cell but with reduced functionality.\n4) The MS is automatically redirected to a different cell with service entitlement.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 875, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The MS is denied access to the cell and enters a limited service state.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can the MTLF determine ML Model degradation? \n\nOptions:\n1) By comparing predictions with ground truth data\n2) By collecting feedback information from AnLF\n3) Both option 1 and option 2\n4) By reselecting a new ML model\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 886, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both option 1 and option 2", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Robust Call Setup for VoLTE subscriber in LTE Work Item aim to address? \n\nOptions:\n1) Improvement of LTE RSRP for VoLTE\n2) Enhancement of voice and video for LTE\n3) Provision of emergency call information\n4) Reduction of roaming charges for VoLTE\n5) Optimization of LTE data sessions for VoLTE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 888, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Improvement of LTE RSRP for VoLTE", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the User Service Identity Module (USIM)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To host multiple applications\n2) To provide security features\n3) To access the IMS services\n4) To store provisioning parameters\n5) To provide a unique identity for a user\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 890, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To provide security features", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Immediate Divert in IP-PBX? \n\nOptions:\n1) To divert a call to a messaging system\n2) To explicitly transfer an in-progress call to another device\n3) To allow a call to be resumed from a different device\n4) To provide Connected Name and Number Display\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 892, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To divert a call to a messaging system", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich logical channel can be mapped to UL-SCH in the uplink? \n\nOptions:\n1) CCCH\n2) DCCH\n3) DTCH\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 900, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Dual Connectivity in the RAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) To increase the capacity of the core network nodes\n2) To provide redundancy for the control plane path\n3) To increase the capacity of the radio network nodes\n4) To provide redundancy for the user plane path\n5) To improve the signal quality of the radio network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 913, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To provide redundancy for the user plane path", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the group identifier 'External Group ID' used by the SCS/AS and SCEF represent? \n\nOptions:\n1) A unique identifier assigned to each individual UE\n2) A group identifier used to identify the group of UEs\n3) A parameter used for monitoring event configuration/reporting\n4) A mechanism for operator control of UE configuration parameters\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 917, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  A group identifier used to identify the group of UEs", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the scrambling sequence generator initialized with for a UE-specific search space? \n\nOptions:\n1) C-RNTI\n2) SSB\n3) PBCH\n4) pdcch-DMRS-ScramblingID\n5) MCS-C-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 921, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  pdcch-DMRS-ScramblingID", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the spacing between carriers for category M1? \n\nOptions:\n1) 200 kHz\n2) 100 kHz\n3) 300 kHz\n4) Depends on the deployment scenario\n5) The same as the channel bandwidth\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 923, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Depends on the deployment scenario", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich architecture supports offline and online charging for Non-seamless WLAN offloaded traffic from a 3GPP UE and for fixed devices? \n\nOptions:\n1) 5G data connectivity converged charging architecture\n2) Converged charging architecture with CTF, CHF (ABMF / RF)\n3) Centralized CHF deployment\n4) Local/Edge CHF deployment\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 929, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Converged charging architecture with CTF, CHF (ABMF / RF)", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Make-Before-Break solution? \n\nOptions:\n1) To minimize the mobility interruption including handover and SeNB change\n2) To reduce the grant request delay in the UL\n3) To improve the DL beamforming performance\n4) To increase the latency reduction gains\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 934, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To minimize the mobility interruption including handover and SeNB change", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat kind of coordination communication is used in the RIM frameworks? \n\nOptions:\n1) Wireless communication\n2) Backhaul communication\n3) Core network communication\n4) Satellite communication\n5) Fiber optic communication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 941, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Backhaul communication", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of CS multimedia calls? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support multimedia services with IP telephony\n2) To support multimedia services with circuit-switched technology\n3) To provide streaming services using packet-switched technology\n4) To enable real-time text conversation in 3GPP networks\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 943, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To support multimedia services with circuit-switched technology", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich stage introduced eCall for EPS over E-UTRAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) Stage 1\n2) Stage 2\n3) Stage 3\n4) Stage 4\n5) Stage 5\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 946, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Stage 2", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of the home environment in the delegation of charging authority? \n\nOptions:\n1) To handle cost control mechanisms\n2) To process charging data in real time\n3) To control fraud in the network\n4) To authenticate users before they incur any charges\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 955, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To authenticate users before they incur any charges", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the potential impact of ARP errors on NR carrier phase positioning accuracy? \n\nOptions:\n1) ARP errors have negligible impact on positioning accuracy\n2) ARP errors may have a significant impact on positioning accuracy\n3) ARP errors have a larger impact on multi-frequency positioning compared to single-frequency positioning\n4) ARP errors have a larger impact on single-frequency positioning compared to multi-frequency positioning\n5) ARP errors only impact initial phase error but not positioning accuracy\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 962, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  ARP errors may have a significant impact on positioning accuracy", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is an acceptable cell? \n\nOptions:\n1) A cell that provides limited service for emergency calls and notifications\n2) A cell that provides normal service for public use\n3) A cell that is not barred and fulfills cell selection criteria\n4) A cell that is reserved for operator use\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 976, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  A cell that provides limited service for emergency calls and notifications", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can be achieved with semi-static TRP reduction in multi-TRP operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) BS energy saving of 36.9%~41.6%\n2) BS energy saving of 19.7%~28.7%\n3) BS energy saving of 7.27%~22%\n4) UE power savings of about 12%\n5) UPT loss of 0.02%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 979, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  BS energy saving of 36.9%~41.6%", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich clause provides the MU assessment for 52.6GHz? \n\nOptions:\n1) Static propagation conditions\n2) Multi-path fading propagation conditions\n3) DUT antenna location estimation\n4) Probe antenna pattern\n5) Measurement uncertainty budget for FR2-2 test methods\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 986, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Measurement uncertainty budget for FR2-2 test methods", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the gNB-DU respond with to the gNB-CU after receiving the UE CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST message? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION REQUEST\n2) UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE\n3) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND\n4) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMPLETE\n5) UE CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 990, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  UE CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the QoS profile in NG-RAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) To establish PDU sessions\n2) To determine radio interface treatment\n3) To identify QoS flows\n4) To map packets to DRBs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1005, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To determine radio interface treatment", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of 5G LAN-type service in indirect communication mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support authorized UEs using indirect network connection\n2) To provide required QoS for Ethernet packets transferred between remote UE and relay UE\n3) To ensure service continuity for private communication between remote UE and other member UEs\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1014, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are Mobile Terminated Voice calls delivered for MEs capable of offering voice service on CS and IMS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Based on the network conditions\n2) Based on the user's preferences\n3) Based on the IMS registration status\n4) Based on the CS attachment status\n5) Based on the domain specified by the Home operator policy\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1016, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Based on the domain specified by the Home operator policy", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of service management requirements? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable the user to establish and maintain several connections simultaneously\n2) To support the development of multimedia services\n3) To enable control, creation, and subscription of service capabilities and services\n4) To allow the home environment to be notified when a user has changed ME\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1019, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To enable control, creation, and subscription of service capabilities and services", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the procedure called by which a UE acquires time and frequency synchronization with a cell and detects the Cell ID of that cell? \n\nOptions:\n1) Power control\n2) Cell search\n3) Link adaptation\n4) Coordinated Multi-Point transmission\n5) Wake-up signal\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1025, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Cell search", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat should URSP rules based on AF guidance not be set as? \n\nOptions:\n1) Match all traffic descriptor\n2) URSP rules with low priority\n3) URSP rules without traffic descriptor\n4) URSP rules for specific locations\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1029, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Match all traffic descriptor", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich type of reporting is supported for CLI measurements? \n\nOptions:\n1) Event triggered only\n2) Periodic only\n3) Both event triggered and periodic\n4) Continuous\n5) Manual\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1030, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both event triggered and periodic", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Media Streaming AF Event Exposure work item? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support data collection and event exposure by an AF to event consumers\n2) To extend the 5G Media Streaming functionality for UE data collection\n3) To define generic UE data collection and reporting procedures\n4) To provide interoperability for 5G Media Streaming services\n5) To specify the architecture for generic UE data collection and reporting\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1032, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To support data collection and event exposure by an AF to event consumers", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the LCS Server enable in terms of services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Location-based services determined by users and service providers\n2) Privacy control for location requests\n3) Positioning for target UEs\n4) Support for telecommunication services\n5) Exchange of information through LCS messages\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1036, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Location-based services determined by users and service providers", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn the context of LTE, what is the purpose of the Downlink Multiuser Superposition Transmission (MUST) feature? \n\nOptions:\n1) To assist UE in cancelling inter-cell interference\n2) To achieve interference cancellation within one cell\n3) To enable switching between transmit diversity schemes\n4) To support SRS switching on PUSCH-less TDD CCs\n5) To define power control parameters for SRS transmission\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1037, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To achieve interference cancellation within one cell", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich physical channel carries the DL-SCH and PCH? \n\nOptions:\n1) PDSCH\n2) PMCH\n3) PUCCH\n4) PBCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1043, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  PDSCH", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the default value for the sl-MaxCID-r16 parameter in SidelinkPreconfigNR-r16? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1\n2) 15\n3) 1000\n4) 16383\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1044, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  15", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the allowed network exposure information for the UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) The AF's request to the NEF\n2) The SMF's subscription record stored in the UDM\n3) The UE's PDU Session ID\n4) The AIML operation type\n5) The UE's subscription record stored in the UDM\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1054, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The UE's subscription record stored in the UDM", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn SNPN access operation mode over 3GPP access, what lists does the MS maintain for regional provision of service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Lists of forbidden access points\n2) Lists of forbidden tracking areas\n3) Lists of selected SNPNs\n4) Lists of PLMN subscriptions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1065, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Lists of forbidden tracking areas", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can power saving be enabled during active-time? \n\nOptions:\n1) By enabling PDCCH monitoring\n2) By eDRX configuration\n3) By adapting the minimum scheduling offsets\n4) By cross-slot scheduling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1066, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  By cross-slot scheduling", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the granularity of the dl-PRS-ResourceBandwidth parameter? \n\nOptions:\n1) 4 PRBs\n2) 1 PRB\n3) 24 PRBs\n4) 272 PRBs\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1067, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  4 PRBs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat functionalities does the RRC sublayer provide for sidelink communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) Configuration of sidelink resource allocation\n2) Reporting of UE sidelink information\n3) Measurement configuration and reporting related to sidelink\n4) Reporting of UE assistance information for SL traffic pattern(s)\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1078, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the categories of users that the ePWS feature aims to better disseminate Warning Notifications to? \n\nOptions:\n1) Users with disabilities who use text assistive technologies\n2) Users with disabilities who use assistive technologies beyond text assistive technologies\n3) Users who are fluent in the language of the Warning Notifications\n4) Users with no user interface on their UEs\n5) Users who have UEs with user interfaces incapable of displaying text-based Warning Notifications\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1083, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Users with disabilities who use assistive technologies beyond text assistive technologies", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow do victim gNBs determine if the atmospheric ducting phenomenon has ceased in the wireless framework? \n\nOptions:\n1) By establishing backhaul coordination\n2) By receiving a specific signal from the core network\n3) By analyzing the TDD DL-UL patterns\n4) By measuring the total received power\n5) By not receiving any reference signal sent from aggressors\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1095, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  By not receiving any reference signal sent from aggressors", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which scenarios does the consumer NF determine new QoS parameters? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the Target of Analytics Reporting is 'any UE'\n2) When multiple Network Slice instances are deployed\n3) When the application SLA is not satisfied\n4) When NWDAF provides Service Experience statistics\n5) When AF provides Service Experience Information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1096, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  When the application SLA is not satisfied", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the 5G VN group configuration information delivered to the UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Via the NEF using the Nudm_SDM_Get service operation\n2) Via the UDM using the SM subscription data\n3) Via the PCF using the URSP in the UE Configuration Update procedure\n4) Via the SMF using the AF request and the PCF policies\n5) Via the AMF using the SM subscription data and the Internal Group ID(s)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1099, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Via the PCF using the URSP in the UE Configuration Update procedure", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information does the consumer of NF load analytics need to indicate in the request? \n\nOptions:\n1) SUPI and S-NSSAI\n2) NF Instance IDs and NF Set IDs\n3) Analytics ID and Target of Analytics Reporting\n4) Area of interest and list of analytics subsets\n5) Preferred order of results and Reporting Threshold\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1101, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Analytics ID and Target of Analytics Reporting", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the scrambling sequence initialized with at the start of each SS/PBCH block? \n\nOptions:\n1) SSB\n2) PBCH\n3) Candidate SS/PBCH block index\n4) C-RNTI\n5) MCS-C-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1104, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Candidate SS/PBCH block index", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the requirement for network traffic patterns in service capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) To consider the overheads and signalling surge caused by frequent transmissions of large amounts of data\n2) To consider the discontinuous and symmetric nature of most teleservices and user applications\n3) To consider the discontinuous and asymmetric nature of most teleservices, multimedia services, and user applications\n4) To consider the continuous and symmetric nature of most teleservices and user applications\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1110, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To consider the discontinuous and asymmetric nature of most teleservices, multimedia services, and user applications", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich conditions must be satisfied for traffic steering from E-UTRAN to WLAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) RSRPmeas < ThreshServingOffloadWLAN, LowP and ChannelUtilizationWLAN < ThreshChUtilWLAN, Low\n2) RSRQmeas < ThreshServingOffloadWLAN, LowQ and BackhaulRateDlWLAN > ThreshBackhRateDLWLAN, High\n3) RSRPmeas > ThreshServingOffloadWLAN, HighP and BackhaulRateUlWLAN > ThreshBackhRateULWLAN, High\n4) ChannelUtilizationWLAN > ThreshChUtilWLAN, High and WLANRSSI < ThreshWLANRSSI, Low\n5) RSRPmeas < ThreshServingOffloadWLAN, LowP and WLANRSSI > ThreshWLANRSSI, High\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1112, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  RSRPmeas < ThreshServingOffloadWLAN, LowP and ChannelUtilizationWLAN < ThreshChUtilWLAN, Low", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the characteristics of the interfering signals for E-UTRA SAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) A PDSCH containing data and reference symbols\n2) A PUSCH containing data and reference symbols\n3) A NPUSCH containing data and reference symbols\n4) A PRACH containing data and reference symbols\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1119, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  A PUSCH containing data and reference symbols", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of integrity protection in NR connected to 5GC security? \n\nOptions:\n1) Provides user data confidentiality\n2) Provides user data integrity protection\n3) Provides signaling data confidentiality\n4) Provides signaling data integrity protection\n5) Ensures physical protection of data handling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1123, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Provides signaling data integrity protection", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the NG-RAN perform NG-RAN paging before reporting the UE's location? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the UE is in RRC_CONNECTED state\n2) When the UE is in RRC_INACTIVE state\n3) When the NG-RAN receives Location Reporting Control message indicating single stand-alone report\n4) When the NG-RAN receives Location Reporting Control message indicating continuous reporting\n5) When PSCell reporting is requested and the PSCell ID is known\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1134, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  When the NG-RAN receives Location Reporting Control message indicating single stand-alone report", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the key characteristic of a roaming broker enabled Home Environment? \n\nOptions:\n1) It has a direct commercial agreement with different serving networks.\n2) It interworks with one or more serving network operators.\n3) It uses fraud and cost control mechanisms to ensure charges do not exceed credit limits.\n4) It routes registration requests to its serving networks.\n5) It is capable of operating as a roaming broker.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1143, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  It is capable of operating as a roaming broker.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specifications define the Network Resource Model (NRM) information service and solution set for 5G networks and network slicing? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 28.541, TS 28.623, TS 28.622\n2) TS 28.554, TS 28.550, TS 28.552\n3) TS 28.540, TS 28.658, TS 28.626\n4) TS 28.531, TS 28.532, TS 28.533\n5) TS 28.541, TS 28.540, TS 28.658\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1144, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  TS 28.541, TS 28.623, TS 28.622", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Timing Delta MAC CE indicate to an IAB-node? \n\nOptions:\n1) Time difference between DU transmission and IAB-MT reception\n2) Time difference between IAB-MT reception and transmission\n3) Timing advance offset value for a serving cell\n4) Timing Case Indication for a serving cell\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1148, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Time difference between DU transmission and IAB-MT reception", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIs supporting periodic location reporting a requirement for Emergency Services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes, it is a requirement\n2) No, it is not a requirement\n3) It depends on asset management services\n4) It depends on the PLMN operator\n5) It depends on the Privacy Exception List\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1160, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  No, it is not a requirement", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of fraud control in the home environment? \n\nOptions:\n1) To collect charging information from serving networks\n2) To notify the customer care centre about charge thresholds\n3) To process charging information in real time\n4) To set limits for accumulated charges\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1161, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To notify the customer care centre about charge thresholds", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich feature in Rel-16 allows transmission of uplink data payload without performing random access procedures? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE-group wake-up signals (GWUS)\n2) Mobile-terminated early data transmission (MT-EDT)\n3) Support for Preconfigured uplink resources (PUR) in idle mode\n4) Scheduling of multiple DL/UL transport blocks with single DCI\n5) Presence of NRS on a non-anchor carrier for paging\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1166, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Support for Preconfigured uplink resources (PUR) in idle mode", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main goal of enabling 5G LAN-type services and virtual networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide long distance access and mobility\n2) To offer private communication using IP and/or non-IP type communications\n3) To support 5G LAN-virtual networks\n4) To enhance the security and privacy of LAN services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1170, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To offer private communication using IP and/or non-IP type communications", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the key functionality introduced for prioritization between overlapping uplink resources of one UE in the 5G Core network? \n\nOptions:\n1) Support for up to eight simultaneously active semi-persistent scheduling (SPS) configurations\n2) Support for accurate reference timing delivery\n3) Support for prioritization between overlapping uplink resources of one UE\n4) Support for multiple active configured grant configurations for a BWP\n5) Support for PDCP packet duplication enhancements\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1173, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Support for prioritization between overlapping uplink resources of one UE", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat action does the network take if a QCI-1 bearer setup request for VoLTE is rejected during a terminating session? \n\nOptions:\n1) The call will be dropped\n2) The network will retry the call setup over CS domain\n3) The call will fallback to 2/3G in weak coverage areas\n4) The network will initiate a handover to a stronger LTE signal\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1174, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The network will retry the call setup over CS domain", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does network diagnostics aim to achieve? \n\nOptions:\n1) Early detection of faults\n2) Evaluation of impact on the service/network\n3) Clear explanations of failures\n4) Suggestion of corrective actions\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1176, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of load-balancing steering mode enhancements? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide better network performance measurements\n2) To prioritize non-3GPP access over 3GPP access in load balancing\n3) To enable the UE and UPF to freely select split percentages for each access type\n4) To enhance the functionality of the AMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1184, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To enable the UE and UPF to freely select split percentages for each access type", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum number of CBR range configurations for sidelink communication congestion control? \n\nOptions:\n1) 8\n2) 7\n3) 16\n4) 15\n5) 12\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1185, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  8", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information is included in the Location Report message when the NG-RAN detects that the UE has moved out of or into multiple areas of interest? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE Location\n2) UE Presence in Area Of Interest\n3) Request Reference ID\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1189, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich satellite access network type has the lowest end-to-end latency requirement in a 5G system? \n\nOptions:\n1) GEO based satellite access\n2) MEO based satellite access\n3) LEO based satellite access\n4) All have the same end-to-end latency requirement\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1191, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  LEO based satellite access", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich standard defines the integration of the 5G System into a TSN data network (DN)? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS\u00a023.040\n2) TS\u00a023.273\n3) TS\u00a023.502\n4) TS\u00a023.540\n5) IEEE Std 802.1Q\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1196, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  IEEE Std 802.1Q", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the on-duration of DRX? \n\nOptions:\n1) The duration that the UE monitors PDCCH\n2) The duration until a retransmission can be expected\n3) The duration that the UE waits for, after waking up, to receive PDCCHs\n4) The total duration that the UE monitors PDCCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1207, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The duration that the UE waits for, after waking up, to receive PDCCHs", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat inputs are required for the Nmfaf_3caDataManagement_Notify service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Data Consumer or Analytics Consumer Information, Transaction Reference Id\n2) Notification Correlation Information\n3) Requested Data with timestamp or Analytics with timestamp, Fetch Instructions\n4) Set of Fetch Correlation ID(s)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1210, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Notification Correlation Information", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich 3GPP working group is responsible for defining the security aspects of LTE based V2X communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) SA WG1\n2) SA WG2\n3) SA WG3\n4) CT WG1\n5) CT WG3\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1211, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  SA WG3", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the data services included in MCData in Release 14? \n\nOptions:\n1) Short message service only\n2) File transfer service only\n3) Both short message service and file transfer service\n4) Email service\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1215, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both short message service and file transfer service", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of service continuity in the Evolved Packet System? \n\nOptions:\n1) To optimize routing for user plane traffic\n2) To support mobility within and across access systems\n3) To minimize packet loss during inter- and/or intra-access technology changes\n4) To provide continuous service during and following changes of access systems\n5) To support simultaneous usage of multiple accesses\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1217, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To provide continuous service during and following changes of access systems", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the SMF do when it receives the enabling request for analytics information exposure from a UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Subscribes to the Analytics ID for the UE\n2) Checks if it has already subscribed to the Analytics ID for other UEs\n3) Unsubscribes from the Analytics ID for the UE\n4) Requests analytics information from the NWDAF\n5) Includes an Accept or Reject to the enabling request\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1226, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Checks if it has already subscribed to the Analytics ID for other UEs", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can the user change in the privacy exception list? \n\nOptions:\n1) The LCS Client and/or group of LCS Clients list\n2) The codeword\n3) The requestor\n4) The service types\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1228, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a '1' value for a bit in the TRS availability indication field indicate? \n\nOptions:\n1) Change to a current assumption for the availability of TRS resource sets\n2) No change to the availability of TRS resource sets\n3) Unavailability of associated TRS resource sets\n4) Validity of TRS resource sets\n5) Presence of associated TRS resource sets\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1241, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Presence of associated TRS resource sets", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of transferring CDRs via Bx? \n\nOptions:\n1) To transfer CDRs from CDF to CGF for processing.\n2) To transfer CDRs from CGF to BD for persistent storage.\n3) To transfer CDRs from CDF to CTF for charging data transfer.\n4) To transfer CDRs from OCF to OCS for online charging.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1246, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To transfer CDRs from CGF to BD for persistent storage.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of spreading in PUCCH formats 3 and 4? \n\nOptions:\n1) To increase the bandwidth of the PUCCH transmission.\n2) To enhance the orthogonality of the transmitted symbols.\n3) To improve the immunity of the transmitted signal to multipath fading.\n4) To reduce the inter-UE interference in the PUCCH transmission.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1248, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To enhance the orthogonality of the transmitted symbols.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the NWDAF collect input data for PDU Session traffic analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) Directly from the UPF using the 'UserDataUsageMeasures' event exposure event.\n2) Indirectly via the SMF.\n3) Both options 1 and 2.\n4) None of the above.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1253, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both options 1 and 2.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following options does NWDAF collect input data from? \n\nOptions:\n1) OAM\n2) NRF\n3) AMF\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1254, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the xMB API? \n\nOptions:\n1) To define the reference point specification for MBMS\n2) To handle packet losses in MBMS\n3) To manage content providers in MBMS\n4) To control MBMS delivery procedures\n5) To provide extended control features for MC Services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1258, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To control MBMS delivery procedures", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Indirect 3GPP Communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) To connect an Evolved ProSe Remote UE to the 3GPP network via an Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay\n2) To enable GSM and UMTS communication\n3) To support small data services for an Evolved ProSe Remote UE\n4) To provide resource efficient management of shared radio spectrum\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1264, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To connect an Evolved ProSe Remote UE to the 3GPP network via an Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the SNR target for higher CBWs assuming 16 and 20 dB? \n\nOptions:\n1) 14.4 dB\n2) 18.6 dB\n3) 16 dB\n4) 20 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1274, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  16 dB", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is a 5G VN group identified? \n\nOptions:\n1) By the UE's GPSI\n2) By the AF using the External Group ID\n3) By the NEF using the Internal Group ID\n4) By the UDM using the Internal Group ID\n5) By the PCF using the External Group ID\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1283, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  By the AF using the External Group ID", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich message contains the low layer configuration for the UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) INITIAL UE MESSAGE\n2) DL RRC MESSAGE TRANSFER\n3) RRC CONNECTION SETUP COMPLETE\n4) UL RRC MESSAGE TRANSFER\n5) INITIAL UL RRC MESSAGE TRANSFER\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1287, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  INITIAL UL RRC MESSAGE TRANSFER", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the two main groups of logical channels in the MAC sublayer? \n\nOptions:\n1) Broadcast channels and Dedicated channels\n2) Control channels and Traffic channels\n3) Physical channels and Transport channels\n4) Scheduling channels and Error correction channels\n5) Primary channels and Secondary channels\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1288, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Control channels and Traffic channels", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the feature 'Multi-server bearer coordination' for MBMS usage in MC services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Allowing a single MC service server to manage all MBMS media transmission\n2) Activating an MBMS bearer and notifying relevant events\n3) Application layer FEC to recover packet losses\n4) Applying header compression over MBMS transmissions\n5) Supporting multiple security domains\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1299, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Allowing a single MC service server to manage all MBMS media transmission", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is VarMeasIdleConfig used for? \n\nOptions:\n1) To configure the measurements to be performed by the UE while in RRC_IDLE or RRC_INACTIVE\n2) To configure the reporting of measurements performed by the UE while in RRC_IDLE or RRC_INACTIVE\n3) To configure the logging of measurements performed by the UE while in RRC_IDLE or RRC_INACTIVE\n4) To configure the mobility behavior of the UE while in RRC_IDLE or RRC_INACTIVE\n5) To configure the random-access procedure of the UE while in RRC_IDLE or RRC_INACTIVE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1310, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To configure the measurements to be performed by the UE while in RRC_IDLE or RRC_INACTIVE", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of a Relay Node (RN) in E-UTRAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) To terminate the radio protocols of the E-UTRA radio interface\n2) To manage the EPS bearers and session for the RN\n3) To handle the S1 and X2 interfaces between the DeNB and the MME\n4) To support PWS towards UEs\n5) To perform the RRC connection establishment for the RN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1311, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To terminate the radio protocols of the E-UTRA radio interface", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of S-NSSAI based congestion control? \n\nOptions:\n1) To restrict data transfer via Control Plane CIoT 5GS Optimization\n2) To avoid and handle NAS signalling congestion for UEs with a back-off timer associated with or without an S-NSSAI\n3) To handle overload situations in the SMF\n4) To apply congestion control to a specific group of UEs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1312, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To avoid and handle NAS signalling congestion for UEs with a back-off timer associated with or without an S-NSSAI", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich access control mechanisms are supported by NG-RAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) RACH back off\n2) RRC Connection Reject\n3) RRC Connection Release\n4) UE based access barring mechanisms\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1318, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the N26 interface in the non-roaming architecture for interworking between 5GS and EPC? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable interworking between EPC and the NG core\n2) To support subset of the functionalities that are supported over S10\n3) To provide inter-CN interface between the MME and 5GS AMF\n4) To support interworking between EPC and NG-RAN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1321, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable interworking between EPC and the NG core", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used between the BSC and BTS to support the services offered to the GSM users and subscribers? \n\nOptions:\n1) S1-MME-interface\n2) S1-U-interface\n3) Abis-interface\n4) Iub-interface\n5) Iur-interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1331, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Abis-interface", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the 'Connect-streaming' communication paradigm in management service interactions? \n\nOptions:\n1) To authenticate the management service consumer\n2) To establish a connection for management data streaming\n3) To enable the management service producer to invoke operations\n4) To request a subscription to notifications and receive network events\n5) To provide response based on a request from the management service consumer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1343, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To establish a connection for management data streaming", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used to transfer OAM traffic between the RN and the OAM system? \n\nOptions:\n1) S1 interface\n2) X2 interface\n3) Un interface\n4) MME interface\n5) OAM interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1345, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Un interface", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich state is the UE expected to receive the DL PRS for RTT-based propagation delay compensation in? \n\nOptions:\n1) RRC_IDLE state\n2) RRC_CONNECTED state\n3) RRC_INACTIVE state\n4) RRC_RELEASED state\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1348, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  RRC_CONNECTED state", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat aspect does the CT Work Item \"V8-CT\" focus on? \n\nOptions:\n1) Emergency call in Local breakout roaming architecture\n2) Location determination at IMS entities in the HPLMN\n3) Local number translation in VPLMN for legacy CS and Local Breakout\n4) Fetching and providing necessary information for emergency call\n5) Charging principles for S8HR roaming architecture\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1355, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Fetching and providing necessary information for emergency call", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere can the UE receive PLMN identity and CN type information in a given cell? \n\nOptions:\n1) Data channel\n2) Access channel\n3) Control channel\n4) Broadcast channel\n5) Paging channel\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1358, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Broadcast channel", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the cyclic-prefix length for normal cyclic prefix in SC-FDMA? \n\nOptions:\n1) 160Ts\n2) 144Ts\n3) 512Ts\n4) 256Ts\n5) 768Ts\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1361, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  144Ts", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat physical channel is used for sidelink transmitted data itself? \n\nOptions:\n1) PSCCH\n2) PSBCH\n3) PSFCH\n4) PSSCH\n5) Synchronization signal\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1370, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  PSSCH", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the reference point between the GGSN and a packet data network? \n\nOptions:\n1) Mm Reference Point\n2) GMLC - external LCS Client\n3) Le reference point\n4) Gi reference point\n5) Wi reference point\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1375, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Gi reference point", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can a consumer of user data congestion analytics request? \n\nOptions:\n1) Identifiers of the applications that contribute the most to the traffic\n2) Preferred level of accuracy of the analytics\n3) Temporal granularity size\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1379, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat actions are taken when an AMF fails and is detected by the 5G-AN? \n\nOptions:\n1) AMF is deregistered from NRF\n2) AMF is marked as failed in the 5G-AN\n3) NGAP UE-TNLA-binding is released for CM-CONNECTED UE(s)\n4) Backup AMF is selected if available\n5) Notification is sent to peer CP NFs about the AMF failure\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1380, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  AMF is marked as failed in the 5G-AN", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are the metrics related to the provided thresholds evaluated for WLAN BSS? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE evaluates all metrics related to the provided thresholds.\n2) The UE excludes the WLAN BSS if not all metrics related to the provided thresholds can be acquired.\n3) The WLAN BSS is excluded if the UE cannot evaluate the provided thresholds.\n4) The UE considers the metrics with unprovided thresholds as zero.\n5) The UE considers the metrics with unprovided thresholds as infinite.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1383, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The UE excludes the WLAN BSS if not all metrics related to the provided thresholds can be acquired.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the NG-RAN initiate the Connection Inactive procedure with CN based MT communication handling? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the UE is in CM-CONNECTED with RRC_CONNECTED state and has received the \"RRC Inactive Assistance Information\" from the AMF\n2) When CN based mobile terminating (MT) communication handling is requested for a UE with eDRX cycle value longer than 10.24 seconds for RRC_INACTIVE state\n3) When the UE is registered in the network with negotiated eDRX parameters for CM-IDLE state and is in CM-CONNECTED with RRC_CONNECTED state\n4) When the AMF provides the eDRX cycle value for CM-IDLE state to NG-RAN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1387, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  When CN based mobile terminating (MT) communication handling is requested for a UE with eDRX cycle value longer than 10.24 seconds for RRC_INACTIVE state", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the power headroom reports (PHR)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide support for power-aware packet scheduling\n2) To allocate resources for the initial HARQ transmissions to UEs\n3) To enable coordination of TDM and FDM cell resources between MAC in the gNB and the corresponding entity in the ng-eNB\n4) To enable fast SCell activation when CA is configured\n5) To provide support for QoS-aware packet scheduling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1389, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide support for power-aware packet scheduling", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the high-level features specified for 5G Location Services? \n\nOptions:\n1) LCS Quality of services\n2) LMF selection, UE LCS privacy handling\n3) LCS Quality of services, LMF selection\n4) UE LCS privacy handling, LMF selection\n5) UE LCS privacy handling, LCS Quality of services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1391, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  LMF selection, UE LCS privacy handling", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich network function is responsible for network exposure? \n\nOptions:\n1) AMF\n2) SMF\n3) NRF\n4) NEF\n5) UDM\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1395, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  NEF", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Formatting Instructions? \n\nOptions:\n1) To buffer and send several notifications in one message\n2) To specify the time window for sending notifications\n3) To summarize notifications and reduce the volume of data reported to the Data Consumer\n4) To determine the exact time for sending notifications\n5) To specify the parameter names and values to be reported to the Consumer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1397, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To summarize notifications and reduce the volume of data reported to the Data Consumer", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a capability added in the V2X Application Enabler (VAE) layer? \n\nOptions:\n1) V2X UE group management\n2) V2X service discovery\n3) Session-oriented services\n4) Network monitoring by the V2X UE\n5) Support for PC5 provisioning\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1399, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  V2X service discovery", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat defines the comb size of a DL PRS resource? \n\nOptions:\n1) dl-PRS-ResourceSymbolOffset\n2) dl-PRS-StartPRB\n3) numSymbols\n4) dl-PRS-ResourceSlotOffset\n5) nr-DL-PRS-CombSizeN-AndReOffset\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1400, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  nr-DL-PRS-CombSizeN-AndReOffset", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NWDAF containing MTLF consider when using untrusted AF(s) as data sources? \n\nOptions:\n1) The rating of untrusted AF(s)\n2) The accuracy of ML models\n3) Both option 1 and option 2\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1411, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The rating of untrusted AF(s)", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a '0' value for a bit of the bitmap, provided by dormancyGroupOutsideActiveTime, indicate? \n\nOptions:\n1) A firstOutsideActiveTimeBWP-Id for the UE.\n2) A dormant DL BWP for the UE.\n3) A current active DL BWP for the UE.\n4) An active DL BWP for the UE.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1425, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  An active DL BWP for the UE.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the 5G system need to support for the tactile and multi-modal communication service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ability to provide customized QoS handling for each communication mode\n2) Support for synchronization between different media components\n3) Ability to handle haptic data for touch-based communication\n4) Provision of real-time sensor data for environment awareness\n5) Capability to handle immersive VR applications with low latency\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1426, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Support for synchronization between different media components", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when a registration attempt is rejected with a cause of 'permanent' PLMN restriction? \n\nOptions:\n1) The PLMN is added to the forbidden PLMNs list\n2) The UE enters the limited service state\n3) The UE stores the location area or tracking area in a forbidden list\n4) The UE searches for a suitable cell in the same PLMN\n5) The UE performs an investigation scan for a higher priority PLMN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1433, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The PLMN is added to the forbidden PLMNs list", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the interaction between the 5GC NF(s) and the EASDF? \n\nOptions:\n1) They do not interact within a PLMN\n2) They interact using DNS messages\n3) They interact to exchange DNS message handling rules\n4) They interact for EASDF discovery and selection\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1445, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  They interact for EASDF discovery and selection", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the relative increase in cable loss per meter from 43.5 GHz to 71 GHz? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.33 dB\n2) 0.9 dB\n3) 3.5 dB\n4) 7.7 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1449, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  0.33 dB", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the polarization slant angle for a purely vertically polarized antenna element? \n\nOptions:\n1) 90 degrees\n2) 180 degrees\n3) 45 degrees\n4) 0 degrees\n5) 60 degrees\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1458, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  90 degrees", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the mapping between service data of different domains? \n\nOptions:\n1) The visited network\n2) The home environment\n3) The roaming agreement\n4) The capabilities of the visited network\n5) The roaming subscriber\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1459, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The home environment", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat aspect of the URSP rule does the Application Traffic Descriptor from the AF guidance affect? \n\nOptions:\n1) Route Selection Descriptor Precedence\n2) URSP Traffic Descriptor\n3) DNN selection component\n4) Location Criteria\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1461, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  URSP Traffic Descriptor", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specification defines the Nchf_SpendingLimitControl service? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.203\n2) TS 32.27x\n3) TS 23.502\n4) TS 23.272\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1463, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS 23.502", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is Network Slice-Specific Authentication and Authorization (NSSAA)? \n\nOptions:\n1) The authentication and authorization process for the SUPI in the 5G system\n2) The authentication and authorization process for the network slice in the 5G system\n3) The authentication and authorization process for the AMF in the 5G system\n4) The authentication and authorization process for the V-SMF in the 5G system\n5) The authentication and authorization process for the AAA-S in the 5G system\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1473, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The authentication and authorization process for the network slice in the 5G system", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the motion-to-photon latency range required to support VR environments with low motion-to-photon capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1 ms to 5 ms\n2) 5 ms to 10 ms\n3) 7 ms to 15 ms\n4) 15 ms to 20 ms\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1476, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  7 ms to 15 ms", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich event notification is used to monitor the movement of candidate UEs in/out of the monitoring area? \n\nOptions:\n1) Namf_EventExposure_Subscribe service\n2) Npcf_PolicyAuthorization_Create request\n3) Nnef_AFsessionWithQoS_Revoke\n4) Namf_EventExposure_Notify service\n5) PDU session modification\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1479, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Namf_EventExposure_Notify service", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the HR-SBO PDU Session in roaming? \n\nOptions:\n1) To establish a secure connection between the UE and the V-SMF\n2) To enable local traffic routing in the visited PLMN\n3) To provide access to the data network in the home PLMN\n4) To support session breakout in V-PLMN based on the subscription\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1480, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To enable local traffic routing in the visited PLMN", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the UE Capability Retrieval framework? \n\nOptions:\n1) To report the UE's radio access capabilities to the network\n2) To request specific capabilities from the network\n3) To optimize the UE's power consumption\n4) To enable sidelink communication\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1495, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To report the UE's radio access capabilities to the network", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat functionality does LLDP provide in the TSN Transport Network? \n\nOptions:\n1) Dynamic address assignment\n2) Stream management\n3) Topology information exchange\n4) Priority queueing\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1497, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Topology information exchange", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the function of the Radio Bearer Service? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide transport between RAN and CN\n2) To handle the radio interface transport\n3) To provide QoS in the backbone network\n4) To connect the UMTS CN Edge Node with the external network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1503, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To handle the radio interface transport", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UE ignore regarding cell access restrictions for cell reselection when camping on E-UTRA connected to 5GC? \n\nOptions:\n1) Access Class or ACDC category restrictions\n2) Access Category and Identity restrictions\n3) Emergency call restrictions\n4) Cell status restrictions\n5) Access restrictions for NAS initiated access attempts\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1508, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Access Category and Identity restrictions", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the MDA capability for paging optimization analysis used for? \n\nOptions:\n1) Optimizing network resource usage\n2) Predicting potential network failures\n3) Analyzing service experience of end users\n4) Analyzing handover performance\n5) Avoiding wastage of network resources\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1512, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Avoiding wastage of network resources", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich two new QoS Class Identifiers (QCIs) are added in 5G for Ultra Low Latency GBR services? \n\nOptions:\n1) QCI 80 and QCI 81\n2) QCI 84 and QCI 85\n3) QCI 82 and QCI 83\n4) QCI 86 and QCI 87\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1524, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  QCI 84 and QCI 85", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat reference point enables interactions between the EES and the EEC? \n\nOptions:\n1) EDGE-1\n2) EDGE-2\n3) EDGE-3\n4) EDGE-4\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1532, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  EDGE-1", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the definition of OTA sensitivity? \n\nOptions:\n1) The receiver's ability to receive an unwanted signal in the presence of a wanted signal.\n2) The minimum mean power received at the RIB for a specified reference measurement channel.\n3) The receiver's ability to receive an OTA wanted signal at its assigned channel frequency.\n4) The measure of the capability of the receiver unit to receive a wanted signal in the presence of an interfering signal.\n5) The ability of the receiver to receive a wanted signal in the presence of an interfering signal.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1538, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The ability of the receiver to receive a wanted signal in the presence of an interfering signal.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the UE apply the MCCH information acquisition procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) Upon receiving SIB20 of an SCell\n2) Upon receiving a change notification about MCCH information\n3) Upon entering the cell providing SIB1\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1542, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich 3GPP release introduced NR-V2X with a focus on V2X (Vehicle-to-Everything) communication?\n\nOptions:\n1) Rel-8\n2) Rel-12\n3) Rel-14\n4) Rel-16\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1543, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Rel-16", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a multi-modal communication service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Service that supports communication between different MNOs\n2) Service that enables communication between different devices and networks\n3) Service that allows input and output from multiple sources and destinations\n4) Service that provides communication through multiple communication modes\n5) Service that supports communication with multiple users simultaneously\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1545, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Service that allows input and output from multiple sources and destinations", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is one of the challenges of energy saving schemes in the radio access network (RAN)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Inaccurate cell load prediction\n2) Lack of energy-saving related parameters\n3) Difficulty in identifying energy-saving actions\n4) Lack of feedback on energy efficiency\n5) Conflicting targets between system performance and energy efficiency\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1550, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Inaccurate cell load prediction", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the range of frequencies for which the O2I car penetration loss models are applicable? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.1-10 GHz\n2) 0.6-60 GHz\n3) 100-1000 GHz\n4) 10-100 GHz\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1562, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  0.6-60 GHz", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which bearer option is the S1-U connection terminated in the MeNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) Split bearer\n2) SCG bearer\n3) MCG bearer\n4) Primary bearer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1566, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  MCG bearer", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the UE monitor DCP on the active BWP? \n\nOptions:\n1) During active-time and BWP switching\n2) During measurement gaps and CFRA preamble transmission\n3) During PUSCH transmission and MIMO layers\n4) At a configured offset before the on-duration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1573, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  At a configured offset before the on-duration", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of introducing shorter scheduling periods in downlink and sidelink for V2X messages? \n\nOptions:\n1) To reduce latency for V2X services\n2) To increase power saving in pedestrian UEs\n3) To reduce resource collision probability\n4) To adjust transmission parameters based on congestion control\n5) To enable synchronization outside eNB coverage\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1574, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To reduce latency for V2X services", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich USIM registration triggers the allocation of a new 5G-GUTI for the Paging Timing Collision Control feature? \n\nOptions:\n1) Emergency registration\n2) Normal registration\n3) Connection release\n4) Paging restriction\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1580, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Normal registration", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the MnS discovery service? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable MnS instances to be discovered by MnS consumers\n2) To provide access control capabilities in a multiple tenant environment\n3) To authenticate and authorize MnS consumers and producers\n4) To provision management capabilities for MnS consumers\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1581, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable MnS instances to be discovered by MnS consumers", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the WI 'OAM14-FILMEAS'? \n\nOptions:\n1) Management of measurements for cross-operator accounting\n2) Management concepts, architecture, and requirements\n3) Enabling the operator to provide maximum time between SIP request and response\n4) Functions and solutions related to Lifecycle Management\n5) Use cases and requirements for management of fault and performance measurements\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1583, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Management of measurements for cross-operator accounting", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of dynamic resource schedulers in MAC in gNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allocate physical layer resources for downlink and uplink\n2) To configure the parameters of gNB and UE\n3) To measure radio conditions at the gNB\n4) To provide support for QoS-aware packet scheduling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1595, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To allocate physical layer resources for downlink and uplink", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the UE determine the PDU Session Pair ID and/or RSN for redundant PDU Sessions in URLLC? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE determines them based on URSP rules and matched traffic descriptors.\n2) The UE receives them from the SMF during PDU Session establishment.\n3) The UE generates them independently based on its implementation.\n4) The UE obtains them from the PCF via local configuration.\n5) The UE uses the implementation of FRER in its operating system.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1599, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The UE determines them based on URSP rules and matched traffic descriptors.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of 3GPP PS Data Off feature? \n\nOptions:\n1) To prevent transport via PDN connections of all data packets\n2) To configure operator services\n3) To provide consistent charging between HPLMN and VPLMN\n4) To support falling back to operate over the CS domain\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1609, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To prevent transport via PDN connections of all data packets", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does VarMeasReportList include? \n\nOptions:\n1) Information about the measurements that have been completed by the UE\n2) Information about the measurements that are currently being performed by the UE\n3) Information about the measurements that are scheduled to be performed by the UE\n4) Information about the measurements for which the triggering conditions have been met\n5) Information about the measurements that have been requested by the network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1614, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Information about the measurements for which the triggering conditions have been met", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat additional information is included in the initial SIP request for tracking IMS NEs generating charging information? \n\nOptions:\n1) P-GW address and EPC Charging ID\n2) MSC address and Call Reference Number\n3) Address or specific NE identifier of each IMS NE\n4) Address or identifier of the hosting AS\n5) Application identifier of the hosting AS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1622, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Address or specific NE identifier of each IMS NE", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens if the SDT procedure is unsuccessful? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE transitions to RRC_INACTIVE state.\n2) The UE transitions to RRC_CONNECTED state.\n3) The UE transitions to RRC_RELEASE state.\n4) The UE transitions to RRC_SUSPEND state.\n5) The UE transitions to RRC_IDLE state.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1640, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The UE transitions to RRC_IDLE state.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the main services and functions of the PDCP sublayer? \n\nOptions:\n1) Header compression and decompression, ciphering and deciphering, and timer-based SDU discard\n2) Transfer of upper layer PDUs, error correction through ARQ, and reassembly of SDUs\n3) Mapping between logical channels and transport channels, error correction through HARQ, and priority handling\n4) Marking QoS flow ID in packets, mapping between QoS flows and data radio bearers, and transfer of data\n5) Multiplexing/demultiplexing of MAC SDUs, scheduling information reporting, and priority handling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1641, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Header compression and decompression, ciphering and deciphering, and timer-based SDU discard", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does PDSCH repetition improve in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Uplink data channel reliability\n2) Downlink data channel reliability\n3) Uplink latency\n4) Downlink latency\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1644, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Downlink data channel reliability", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Edge Data Network (EDN) in enabling edge applications? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable discovery of Edge Application Servers\n2) To provide configurations to the Edge Enabler Client (EEC)\n3) To support service provisioning for UE\n4) To host the Edge Application Server(s) and Edge Enabler Server (EES)\n5) To expose EES capability as APIs to EAS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1647, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To host the Edge Application Server(s) and Edge Enabler Server (EES)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the serving core network operator for a non-supporting UE in a network broadcasting a multiple PLMN-id list? \n\nOptions:\n1) The serving core network operator located nearest to the UE\n2) The operator configuration\n3) The type of radio access technology used by the UE\n4) The number of PLMN-id lists broadcasted by the network\n5) The core network operator selected by a supporting UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1651, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The operator configuration", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat events should the Hosting E-UTRAN/NG-RAN Operator collect for accounting purposes? \n\nOptions:\n1) Start of service for a UE\n2) End of service for a UE\n3) Both start and end of service for a UE\n4) Signalling events for a UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1673, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both start and end of service for a UE", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the relation between the antenna element pattern in the GCS and the LCS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Antenna element pattern in the GCS is equal to the antenna element pattern in the LCS\n2) Antenna element pattern in the GCS is derived from the antenna element pattern in the LCS\n3) Antenna element pattern in the GCS is orthogonal to the antenna element pattern in the LCS\n4) Antenna element pattern in the GCS depends on the zenith and azimuth angles of the GCS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1682, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Antenna element pattern in the GCS is derived from the antenna element pattern in the LCS", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the three features specified in TS 23.304 for 5G ProSe Direct Communication over NR based PC5 reference point? \n\nOptions:\n1) Broadcast mode, Multicast mode, Unicast mode\n2) Broadcast mode, Groupcast mode, Unicast mode\n3) Broadcast mode, Groupcast mode, Multicast mode\n4) Unicast mode, Groupcast mode, Multicast mode\n5) Unicast mode, Multicast mode, Broadcast mode\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1687, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Broadcast mode, Groupcast mode, Unicast mode", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat parameter from the AF guidance is used to set the Route Selection Descriptor in the URSP rule? \n\nOptions:\n1) DNN and S-NSSAI\n2) Route Selection Precedence\n3) Validation Criteria\n4) Spatial Validity Condition\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1690, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  DNN and S-NSSAI", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the capacity of eNB-ID in a Macro eNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1.04 million\n2) 2.04 million\n3) 1024\n4) 256\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1703, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  1.04 million", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the scheduler assign resources between UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Based on the QoS requirements of each UE and associated radio bearers\n2) Based on the radio conditions at the UE identified through measurements made at the gNB\n3) Based on the UE buffer status\n4) Based on the power headroom reports\n5) Based on the measurements of a UEs radio environment\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1707, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Based on the QoS requirements of each UE and associated radio bearers", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Caller Identity Verification Results Delivery to the User? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide information to the end user about potential risks associated with the caller identity\n2) To modify the caller identity information based on the originating network's policy\n3) To deliver the full or partial name string to the UE\n4) To support synchronization of communication logs between multiple devices\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1708, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide information to the end user about potential risks associated with the caller identity", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the architecture component introduced to support wireline access network? \n\nOptions:\n1) Trusted Non-3GPP Gateway Function (TNGF)\n2) Trusted WLAN Interworking Function (TWIF)\n3) Wireline Access Gateway Function (W-AGF)\n4) Global Cable Identifier (GCI)\n5) Global Line Identifier (GLI)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1711, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Wireline Access Gateway Function (W-AGF)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIs the number of lists of forbidden tracking areas supported by an MS fixed or implementation-specific? \n\nOptions:\n1) Fixed\n2) Implementation-specific\n3) Depends on the network operator\n4) Varies depending on the MS model\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1715, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Implementation-specific", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the function of a Base Transceiver Station (BTS)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Control of one or more BTS\n2) Communicating with Mobile Stations in a certain area\n3) Serve one cell\n4) Serve one or more UTRAN cells\n5) Provide the E-UTRA user plane and control plane protocol terminations towards the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1721, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Serve one cell", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is service continuity supported for specific slice(s)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through Multi-Carrier Resource Sharing or Resource Repartitioning\n2) By monitoring and controlling the number of registered UEs per network slice\n3) By enforcing the Slice MBR and the usage of Target NSSAI\n4) By providing Target NSSAI and RFSP to RAN to steer the UE to another cell\n5) By supporting slice specific RACH configuration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1724, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Through Multi-Carrier Resource Sharing or Resource Repartitioning", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Location Service Request report provide? \n\nOptions:\n1) The result of an immediate Location Service Request\n2) The result of a deferred Location Service Request\n3) The result of a location request from the LCS Server\n4) The location information for target UEs\n5) The services provided by the LCS Server\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1728, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The result of a deferred Location Service Request", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following options is used by NWDAF to collect input data on the number of UEs registered in a S-NSSAI or S-NSSAI and NSI ID combination? \n\nOptions:\n1) Namf_EventExposure_Subscribe\n2) Nnsacf_SliceEventExposure_Subscribe\n3) Nsmf_EventExposure_Subscribe\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1734, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat frequency bands are defined for NR SL (Sidelink) in 3GPP Rel-16?\n\nOptions:\n1) 2.5 GHz and 5.9 GHz\n2) 2.5 GHz and 30 GHz\n3) 5.9 GHz and 30 GHz\n4) 30 GHz and 60 GHz\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1746, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  2.5 GHz and 5.9 GHz", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the MSC/SGSN inform gsmSCF about? \n\nOptions:\n1) The type of radio access technology used by the UE\n2) The location of the serving core network operator\n3) Whether the UE selected or the network allocated the serving operator\n4) The number of PLMN-id lists broadcasted by the network\n5) The identity of the Serving GW\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1747, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Whether the UE selected or the network allocated the serving operator", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich reference point is used to force traffic between a WLAN UE and PDG to go through the WAG? \n\nOptions:\n1) Gi reference point\n2) Le reference point\n3) Mm Reference Point\n4) Wi reference point\n5) Wn reference point\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1750, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Wn reference point", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of CDR generation in offline charging? \n\nOptions:\n1) To reserve credit from the subscriber account\n2) To furnish charging information to the OCS/CCS for Credit-Control\n3) To determine the amount of resources a user will consume\n4) To supervise the actual network resource consumption\n5) To transform charging information into CDRs for generating bills\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1751, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To transform charging information into CDRs for generating bills", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat triggers the UE mobility and AF relocation? \n\nOptions:\n1) AF session revocation\n2) EAS relocation\n3) PSA relocation\n4) NEF discovery\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1758, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  PSA relocation", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the NG-RAN node initiate Unified Access Control? \n\nOptions:\n1) When AMFs request load restriction\n2) When OAM requests access control\n3) When NG-RAN receives overload start messages\n4) When UE indicates extended access barring\n5) When NG-RAN is under lawful interception\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1770, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  When NG-RAN receives overload start messages", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the Work Item addressing handling of data services within the Mission Critical framework? \n\nOptions:\n1) MCImp-MC_VIDEO\n2) MCImp-MCData\n3) MCImp-MC_ARCH\n4) MCPTT\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1780, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  MCImp-MCData", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of management data analytics capability? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide authentication and authorization services\n2) To discover management capabilities of MnS producers\n3) To support access control in a multiple tenant environment\n4) To improve network performance and efficiency through data analysis\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1785, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To improve network performance and efficiency through data analysis", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich message is generated by the gNB-CU to transition the UE from RRC connected to RRC inactive? \n\nOptions:\n1) PAGING message\n2) RRCResumeRequest message\n3) RRCRelease message\n4) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND message\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1787, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  RRCRelease message", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat measures does the AMF contain for handling overload situations? \n\nOptions:\n1) N2 overload control and NAS congestion control\n2) Load balancing and re-balancing of TNL associations\n3) Control plane data specific NAS level congestion control\n4) Group specific NAS level congestion control\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1791, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  N2 overload control and NAS congestion control", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat specific identifiers are used for charging data correlation in the packet-switched domain? \n\nOptions:\n1) MSC address and Call Reference Number\n2) P-GW address and EPC Charging ID\n3) 5GC Charging ID\n4) Multimedia Charging ID\n5) IMS Charging Identifier\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1805, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  P-GW address and EPC Charging ID", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the minimum number of unique grid points based on the simulation results for the non-uniform measurement grids? \n\nOptions:\n1) 200\n2) 275\n3) 300\n4) 320\n5) 366\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1810, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  300", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does PDSCH repetition improve? \n\nOptions:\n1) UL data channel reliability\n2) DL control channel reliability\n3) UL control channel reliability\n4) DL data channel reliability\n5) DL and UL data channel reliability\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1812, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  DL data channel reliability", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich TS document includes the catalog of general security assurance requirements? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.682\n2) TS 32.277\n3) TS 33.117\n4) TS 33.116\n5) TS 33.250\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1814, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS 33.117", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich feature in Rel-16 enables reduced UE power consumption in idle mode by transmitting a wakeup signal to a group of UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Scheduling of multiple DL/UL transport blocks with single DCI\n2) Mobile-terminated early data transmission (MT-EDT)\n3) Support for Preconfigured uplink resources (PUR) in idle mode\n4) UE-group wake-up signals (GWUS)\n5) Presence of NRS on a non-anchor carrier for paging\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1820, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  UE-group wake-up signals (GWUS)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum value for the DTX to ACK probability for PUCCH transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1%\n2) 5%\n3) 10%\n4) 15%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1821, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  1%", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information does the H-SMF provide in the Nsmf_PDUSession_Create Response? \n\nOptions:\n1) V-EASDF IP address\n2) DNS server address provided by HPLMN\n3) VPLMN Specific Offloading Information\n4) HR-SBO authorization result\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1822, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  VPLMN Specific Offloading Information", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the major service requirements for typical V2X application? \n\nOptions:\n1) Message transfer latency no longer than 100 ms\n2) Transfer of message size up to 1200 bytes\n3) Support of up to 10 message transfer per second\n4) Communication range sufficient to give driver enough response time\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1828, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the eMBMS enhancements for LTE work item specify? \n\nOptions:\n1) Procedures for interworking of eCall over IMS to CS domain\n2) Core and UE performance requirements for eMBMS enhancements for LTE\n3) Authentication and security measures for IMS Multimedia Telephony service\n4) Media handling extensions for IMS-based Telepresence\n5) Password-based service activation for IMS Multimedia Telephony service\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1841, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Core and UE performance requirements for eMBMS enhancements for LTE", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat additional functions does the eNB support in case of SIPTO@LN with collocated L-GW? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transfer of the collocated S-GW IP address to the EPC\n2) First packet sending and subsequent packet buffering\n3) Support of MME-triggered S-GW relocation\n4) Notification of uplink TEID(s) or GRE key(s) for SIPTO@LN bearer(s)\n5) Activation of SIPTO@LN PDN for requested APN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1855, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  First packet sending and subsequent packet buffering", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Last Active USIM? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide security features\n2) To store provisioning parameters\n3) To automatically select the active USIM on switch on\n4) To access the IMS services\n5) To update USIM-specific information via the radio interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1873, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To automatically select the active USIM on switch on", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the responsibility of the network in the call control protocol? \n\nOptions:\n1) Establishing a MM connection\n2) Activating integrity protection\n3) Exchanging messages across the radio interface\n4) Communicating internally with other protocol (sub)layers\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1875, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Activating integrity protection", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the SNR difference corresponding to a \u2206thermal value of 6 dB? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.33 dB\n2) 0.9 dB\n3) 3.5 dB\n4) 1 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1877, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  1 dB", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Binding Indication in the NF service discovery procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) To authorize the request from the NF service consumer\n2) To select the NF service producer instance for the NF service consumer\n3) To store and mark the NF service consumer as available\n4) To indicate the target for subsequent requests from the NF service consumer concerning the data context\n5) To notify the NF service consumer of newly registered/updated/deregistered NF instances\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1881, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To indicate the target for subsequent requests from the NF service consumer concerning the data context", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere does the USIM reside? \n\nOptions:\n1) On a server\n2) On a terminal\n3) On a USIM card\n4) On a SIM card\n5) On a UICC\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1884, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  On a UICC", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat must a multi-mode terminal do when it enters 3GPP mode of operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Act as a 3GPP only UE which had just been switched-on\n2) Prioritize network selection based on system capabilities\n3) Perform regular investigation scans for higher priority PLMNs\n4) Avoid ping-pong between systems by using a hysteresis function\n5) Store the forbidden PLMNs list in the SIM/USIM\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1891, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Act as a 3GPP only UE which had just been switched-on", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the ZSM framework reference architecture enable? \n\nOptions:\n1) Construction of more complex management services and functions\n2) Streaming management data over an established connection\n3) Requesting a subscription to receive network events\n4) Authenticating the management service consumer\n5) Establishing a connection for management data streaming\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1894, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Construction of more complex management services and functions", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the principle for the long term evolution of the IM CN subsystem? \n\nOptions:\n1) It is restricted by the short/mid-term inter-domain roaming requirements.\n2) It is not restricted by the short/mid-term inter-domain roaming requirements.\n3) It is dependent on the subscription options in the visited network.\n4) It is dependent on the subscription options in the home environment.\n5) It is restricted by the capabilities of the visited network.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1898, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  It is not restricted by the short/mid-term inter-domain roaming requirements.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following analytics subsets is applicable to any consumer? \n\nOptions:\n1) List of top applications in UL\n2) List of top applications in DL\n3) Both list of top applications in UL and DL\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1902, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both list of top applications in UL and DL", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which 3GPP releases are high accuracy and positioning integrity enhancements being addressed?\n\nOptions:\n1) Rel-15 and Rel-16\n2) Rel-17 and Rel-18\n3) Rel-19 and Rel-20\n4) Rel-21 and Rel-22\n5) Rel-23 and Rel-24\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1903, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Rel-17 and Rel-18", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is the minimum applicable scheduling offset restriction applied? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the UE is scheduled with DCI format 0_1 or 1_1\n2) When the DCI in slot n indicates an active DL (UL) BWP change\n3) When there is an active DL BWP change in the scheduling cell\n4) When the PDCCH reception includes two PDCCH candidates from two respective search space sets\n5) When the 'Minimum applicable scheduling offset indicator' field is received outside the first three symbols of the slot\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1918, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  When the UE is scheduled with DCI format 0_1 or 1_1", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can UE power consumption due to false paging alarms be reduced? \n\nOptions:\n1) By switching to a target SSSG\n2) By reducing PDCCH monitoring\n3) By relaxing UE measurements for RLM and/or BFD\n4) By providing TRS/CSI-RS occasions to idle/inactive-mode UEs\n5) By dividing UEs into multiple subgroups\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1922, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  By dividing UEs into multiple subgroups", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many subframes are there in half-frame 0? \n\nOptions:\n1) 4\n2) 5\n3) 6\n4) 7\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1956, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  4", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Generic Bootstrapping Architecture (GBA) in 5GC? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable application functions to establish shared cryptographic material\n2) To authenticate and authorize user equipment\n3) To provide secure communication between UE and the network\n4) To protect very low throughput MTC devices\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1959, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable application functions to establish shared cryptographic material", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the sensing with semi-persistent transmission based mechanism in distributed scheduling (Mode 4)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enhance resource separation between transmitters\n2) To estimate future congestion on a resource\n3) To optimize the use of the channel\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1961, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NWDAF collect from the UPF or the AF related to user data congestion analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) Measurement information for the UE location\n2) Input data for the applications being served by AF(s)\n3) Both measurement information for the UE location and input data for the applications being served by AF(s)\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1963, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both measurement information for the UE location and input data for the applications being served by AF(s)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interfaces connect the eNodeBs to the EPC? \n\nOptions:\n1) S1-MME and S1-U\n2) Iu-CS and Iu-PS\n3) A and Gb\n4) S1 interface\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1975, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  S1-MME and S1-U", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when the Target NF/NF Service triggers the NF/NF Service Context Transfer Pull procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) The Target NF/NF Service sends the Context to the Source NF\n2) The Source NF requests the Context from the Target NF/NF Service\n3) The Target NF/NF Service sends a notification to the Old NF about the decommissioning\n4) The Target NF/NF Service receives a response indicating the result of the operation\n5) The Target NF/NF Service sets up the necessary information about the new context location\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1981, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The Target NF/NF Service receives a response indicating the result of the operation", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Spherical Coverage Grid? \n\nOptions:\n1) To calculate the CDF of the EIRP/EIS distribution in 3D\n2) To determine the total power radiated by the DUT in the TX beam peak direction\n3) To determine the TX and RX beam peak direction\n4) To perform 3D EIRP scans for TX beam peak direction\n5) To perform 3D Throughput/RSRP/EIS scans for RX beam peak direction\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1985, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To calculate the CDF of the EIRP/EIS distribution in 3D", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich supplementary service is unaffected by the user's ability to undergo voice call continuity? \n\nOptions:\n1) Call Forwarding\n2) Call Hold\n3) Call Waiting\n4) Multiparty\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1988, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Call Waiting", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is ProSe Communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) The process of determining proximity between ProSe-enabled UEs.\n2) The process of establishing new communication paths between ProSe-enabled UEs.\n3) The process of relaying data for multiple ProSe-enabled UEs.\n4) The process of enabling communication between Public Safety ProSe-enabled UEs.\n5) The process of enabling ProSe-assisted WLAN direct communication.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 1996, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The process of establishing new communication paths between ProSe-enabled UEs.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Small Data Transmission (SDT) feature in NR? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable data transmission in the INACTIVE state for UEs with periodic data packets\n2) To enable data transmission in the RRC_CONNECTED state for UEs with small data packets\n3) To enable data transmission in the RRC_INACTIVE state for UEs with frequent data traffic\n4) To enable data transmission in the RRC_INACTIVE state for UEs with infrequent data traffic\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2003, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To enable data transmission in the RRC_INACTIVE state for UEs with infrequent data traffic", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nThe Ga reference point allows the sending of __________ from the CDF to the CGF. \n\nOptions:\n1) Acknowledgements\n2) CDRs\n3) Charging events\n4) Changeover mechanisms\n5) Reliability mechanisms\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2007, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  CDRs", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the assumption about the scheduling or configuration of the UE for reception of other downlink signals in the DL PRS resource for RTT-based propagation delay compensation? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE expects to be scheduled or configured for reception of other downlink channel signals\n2) The UE does not expect to be scheduled or configured for reception of any downlink channel or any other downlink signals\n3) The UE expects to be scheduled or configured for reception of specific downlink signals\n4) The UE expects to be scheduled or configured for reception of downlink signals outside the DL active bandwidth part\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2009, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The UE does not expect to be scheduled or configured for reception of any downlink channel or any other downlink signals", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich type of precoding is supported for PSSCH transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transform precoding\n2) Wideband precoding\n3) Beamforming precoding\n4) Codebook-based precoding\n5) Spatial multiplexing precoding\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2015, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Wideband precoding", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are QoS flows mapped to DRBs in the uplink? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reflective mapping\n2) Explicit configuration\n3) Both reflective mapping and explicit configuration\n4) Random mapping\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2017, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both reflective mapping and explicit configuration", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does NSA stand for in the context of 5G architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) New Stand Alone\n2) Non-Standard Architecture\n3) Non-Stand Alone\n4) Next Generation System Architecture\n5) Network Slicing Architecture\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2023, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Non-Stand Alone", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identity is used for UE identification temporarily used for scheduling during the random access procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) CI-RNTI\n2) RA-RNTI\n3) Temporary C-RNTI\n4) Random value for contention resolution\n5) I-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2025, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Temporary C-RNTI", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of modulation is used for PDCCH? \n\nOptions:\n1) QPSK\n2) 16QAM\n3) 64QAM\n4) 256QAM\n5) 1024QAM\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2043, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  QPSK", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the ISIM-specific information? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide security features\n2) To access the IMS services\n3) To store provisioning parameters\n4) To update ISIM-specific information via the radio interface\n5) To protect against unauthorized access or alteration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2048, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To protect against unauthorized access or alteration", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat functionality does Signalling Based Activation provide? \n\nOptions:\n1) Activation of management services for UEs in a specified area\n2) Deactivation of management services for UEs in a specified area\n3) Temporary stop and restart of management services during RAN overload\n4) Request for end user service performance information for one specific UE\n5) Handling management services during handover\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2057, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Request for end user service performance information for one specific UE", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does authentication (charging/billing network) occur in order to get access to services? \n\nOptions:\n1) For all types of calls\n2) For emergency calls\n3) For CS calls\n4) For PS calls\n5) For both CS and PS calls\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2060, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  For all types of calls", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a Paging Occasion (PO)? \n\nOptions:\n1) A subframe where RRC_IDLE state is entered\n2) A subframe where the paging message is transmitted\n3) A subframe where DRX is used\n4) A subframe where RRC_INACTIVE state is entered\n5) A subframe where P-RNTI is transmitted\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2061, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  A subframe where P-RNTI is transmitted", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich new services drive the need for very low latency and high service availability in 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) Enhanced Mobile Broadband (eMBB)\n2) Massive Internet of Things (mIoT)\n3) Critical Communications (CC)\n4) Flexible network operations\n5) Efficient content delivery\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2067, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Critical Communications (CC)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich connectivity model requires URSP rules for steering the mapping between UE applications and PDU Sessions? \n\nOptions:\n1) Distributed Anchor Point\n2) Session Breakout\n3) Multiple PDU Sessions\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2079, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Multiple PDU Sessions", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is one of the functionalities introduced by the Media Handling Extensions for 5G Conversational Services work item? \n\nOptions:\n1) To introduce support for delay tolerant content delivery and video transmission optimization\n2) To enhance the LTE system for efficient delivery of streaming services\n3) To enhance the framework for live uplink streaming\n4) To specify the media streaming architecture for 5G\n5) To specify the enhancements to enable conformance testing for non bit-exact floating-point implementations of the EVS codec\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2080, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To introduce support for delay tolerant content delivery and video transmission optimization", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the enhancements for idle/inactive-mode UE power saving in NR? \n\nOptions:\n1) Enhanced search space set group (SSSG) switching\n2) Provision of potential TRS/CSI-RS occasion(s) to idle/inactive-mode UEs\n3) Relaxation of UE measurements for RLM and/or BFD\n4) Paging enhancements to reduce UE reception power consumption\n5) PDCCH skipping mechanism\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2081, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Paging enhancements to reduce UE reception power consumption", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat triggers the UE to send the RRCResumeRequest message? \n\nOptions:\n1) RNA update\n2) DL data arrival\n3) UL data arrival\n4) RAN-based paging\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2082, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  RAN-based paging", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the channel spacing for UE category NB1 and NB2 in stand-alone mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) 200 kHz\n2) 100 kHz\n3) 300 kHz\n4) Depends on the deployment scenario\n5) The same as the channel bandwidth\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2086, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  200 kHz", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich uncertainty contribution originates from estimating the phase centre of the active antenna array? \n\nOptions:\n1) DUT antenna location estimation\n2) Probe antenna pattern\n3) EIRP measurement error in NF\n4) TRP measurement error in NF\n5) Near-field interaction between probe antenna and DUT antenna\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2097, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  DUT antenna location estimation", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich document describes the transport channel and control channel data processing? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 36.211: Physical channels and modulation\n2) TS 36.212: Multiplexing and channel coding\n3) TS 36.213: Physical layer procedures\n4) TS 36.214: Physical layer \u2013 Measurements\n5) TS 36.216: Physical layer for relaying operation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2101, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  TS 36.212 Multiplexing and channel coding", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the formula to determine the Paging Frame (PF)? \n\nOptions:\n1) SFN mod T= (T div N)*(UE_ID mod W)\n2) SFN mod T= (T div N)*(UE_ID_H mod N)\n3) SFN mod T= (T div N)*(UE_ID_H mod TeDRX,H)\n4) SFN mod T= (T div N)*(UE_ID mod TeDRX,H)\n5) SFN mod T= (T div N)*(UE_ID mod N)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2105, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  SFN mod T= (T div N)*(UE_ID mod N)", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich entity may redirect the AF to a local NEF? \n\nOptions:\n1) PCF\n2) UPF\n3) SMF\n4) NEF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2106, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  NEF", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the new uplink coverage class CC5 in EC-GSM-IoT? \n\nOptions:\n1) To improve downlink MCL performance\n2) To reduce power consumption\n3) To enable extended coverage operation\n4) To improve uplink MCL performance\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2108, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To improve uplink MCL performance", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of network optimization is supported based on context information in the 3GPP system? \n\nOptions:\n1) Optimized service provisioning procedures\n2) Support for efficient transmission of small data\n3) Support for network resource utilization\n4) Support for quality of service equal to or better than GSM and UMTS\n5) Support for multiple parallel QoS levels\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2116, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Support for network resource utilization", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does a Multi-USIM UE indicate to the network that it does not accept the paging and requests to return to CM-IDLE state? \n\nOptions:\n1) By sending a specific AT command.\n2) By sending a Paging Restriction request to the network.\n3) By sending a UEAssistanceInformation message.\n4) By sending a Reject Paging response to the network.\n5) By sending a Service Request message.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2120, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  By sending a Reject Paging response to the network.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich basic requirements shall be supported for CS multimedia calls? \n\nOptions:\n1) Store-and-forward multimedia messaging service\n2) Real-time character by character text conversation\n3) Synchronous Transparent Data service\n4) Fallback to speech from 3.1kHz Ext. PLMN multimedia bearer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2126, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Fallback to speech from 3.1kHz Ext. PLMN multimedia bearer", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum achievable SNR for the demodulation test setup in band n262? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.33 dB\n2) 0.9 dB\n3) 3.5 dB\n4) 7.7 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2136, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  3.5 dB", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the provision of services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Providing IP connectivity through the PS CN domain\n2) Making a service available to an individual subscriber after arrangements have been made\n3) Removing an available service from all subscribers\n4) Removing an available service from individual subscribers\n5) Making a service available to all subscribers without prior arrangements\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2145, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Making a service available to all subscribers without prior arrangements", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of UE radio capability signalling optimization? \n\nOptions:\n1) To increase the size of UE radio capabilities\n2) To efficiently signal UE radio capability information\n3) To reduce the number of supported bands\n4) To implement new RAN interfaces\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2146, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To efficiently signal UE radio capability information", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat two functionalities were introduced in the enhancement of the Dedicated Core Networks selection mechanism? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reliance on UE-assisted DCN selection and load balancing between MMEs\n2) Reliance on UE-assisted DCN selection and support for NIDD data delivery\n3) Load balancing between MMEs and support for NIDD data delivery\n4) Support for CN overload control and load balancing between MMEs\n5) Support for CN overload control and reliance on UE-assisted DCN selection\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2152, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Reliance on UE-assisted DCN selection and load balancing between MMEs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Slice-Maximum Bit Rate (S-MBR)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To limit the aggregate data rate per UE across all QoS Flows for all PDU sessions associated with a slice\n2) To allocate resources to a slice in case of slice resources shortage\n3) To monitor the data rate per Network Slice\n4) To provide Target NSSAI and RFSP to RAN to steer the UE to another cell\n5) To control the number of registered UEs per network slice\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2160, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To limit the aggregate data rate per UE across all QoS Flows for all PDU sessions associated with a slice", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich uncertainty contribution is related to the coupling between the UE antenna and the measurement antenna in the near field? \n\nOptions:\n1) DUT antenna location estimation\n2) Probe antenna pattern\n3) EIRP measurement error in NF\n4) TRP measurement error in NF\n5) Near-field interaction between probe antenna and DUT antenna\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2163, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Near-field interaction between probe antenna and DUT antenna", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the pre-conditions for estimating the energy consumption of VNF/VNFCs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Presence of embedded sensors in NFVI nodes\n2) Presence of external sensors in NFVI nodes\n3) Knowledge of which NFVI nodes the VNF/VNFC instances run on\n4) Low energy consumption of VNF/VNFC instances\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2166, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Knowledge of which NFVI nodes the VNF/VNFC instances run on", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat aspects of the Disaster Roaming service are specified in TS 22.011 and TS 22.261? \n\nOptions:\n1) Disaster Condition configuration procedures.\n2) Disaster Roaming service registration procedures.\n3) System information extensions for MINT.\n4) Network selection procedures.\n5) Service requirements for the 5G system.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2174, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Service requirements for the 5G system.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the control plane protocol for the N4 interface between the SMF and UPF? \n\nOptions:\n1) To manage NAS transport procedures\n2) To manage user plane PDU Session establishment\n3) To manage Registration Management and Connection Management state machines\n4) To manage session management between the UE and the SMF\n5) To manage the connection between the SMF and the UPF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2176, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To manage the connection between the SMF and the UPF", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich frequency range should the channel model support? \n\nOptions:\n1) Up to 2 GHz\n2) Up to 6 GHz\n3) Up to 10 GHz\n4) Up to 50 GHz\n5) Up to 100 GHz\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2185, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Up to 100 GHz", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of recoverySearchSpaceId? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide a configuration for PRACH transmission.\n2) To monitor PDCCH for detection of a DCI format.\n3) To indicate the presence of SSB-MTCAdditionalPCI.\n4) To link a search space set for monitoring PDCCH in a CORESET.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2186, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To link a search space set for monitoring PDCCH in a CORESET.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich reference point supports interaction between a CTF and a CDF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Bx\n2) Gz\n3) Ga\n4) Rf\n5) Gzn\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2188, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Rf", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the primary purpose of MPS for MMTEL voice? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide priority access to enterprise networks in periods of severe network congestion\n2) To provide priority video communication sessions in periods of severe network congestion\n3) To provide priority data transport service in periods of severe network congestion\n4) To provide priority voice communication sessions in periods of severe network congestion\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2190, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To provide priority voice communication sessions in periods of severe network congestion", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the UE report its 3GPP PS Data Off status? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through the PDU Session Establishment procedure.\n2) Through the inter-RAT mobility to NG-RAN.\n3) Through the inter-LADN mobility.\n4) Through the ATSSS feature.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2193, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Through the PDU Session Establishment procedure.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich penetration loss model is applicable to UMa and UMi-Street Canyon scenarios? \n\nOptions:\n1) Low-loss model\n2) High-loss model\n3) Both low-loss and high-loss models\n4) No penetration loss model\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2196, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both low-loss and high-loss models", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the RB set for the PUSCH transmission determined when using RB set allocation? \n\nOptions:\n1) By the number of RBs in the initial UL BWP\n2) By the frequency hopping flag\n3) By the RB set of the PRACH transmission\n4) By the number of repetitions for the PUSCH transmission\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2197, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By the RB set of the PRACH transmission", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a '0' value for the Wake-up indication bit, when reported to higher layers, indicate? \n\nOptions:\n1) To start the drx-onDurationTimer for the next long DRX cycle.\n2) To not start the drx-onDurationTimer for the next long DRX cycle.\n3) To activate the dormantBWP-Id for the UE.\n4) To activate the firstOutsideActiveTimeBWP-Id for the UE.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2205, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To not start the drx-onDurationTimer for the next long DRX cycle.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NWDAF derive when the Analytics target period is in the future? \n\nOptions:\n1) QoS change statistics\n2) QoS requirements\n3) Predictions for potential QoS changes\n4) Location information\n5) UE device and context information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2208, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Predictions for potential QoS changes", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Provision of potential TRS/CSI-RS occasion(s) to idle/inactive-mode UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) To reduce UE power consumption during data scheduling\n2) To reduce UE power consumption for PDCCH monitoring\n3) To reduce UE power consumption for RLM and/or BFD measurements\n4) To reduce UE power consumption for synchronization\n5) To reduce UE power consumption during subframe transmission\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2210, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To reduce UE power consumption for synchronization", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can a Target UE subscription profile specify? \n\nOptions:\n1) Location Quality of Service (QoS) requirements\n2) Location information in a standard format\n3) Location service components and bearers\n4) External user entities connected to the LCS Client\n5) Positioning parameters for the Positioning function\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2214, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Location Quality of Service (QoS) requirements", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a Premises Radio Access Station (PRAS)? \n\nOptions:\n1) A network located within a residence, office or shop that provides connectivity to the 5G network.\n2) A network owned, installed, and configured by a public network operator.\n3) A network that consists of PIN Elements and communicates using PIN Direct Connection.\n4) A base station installed in a CPN for UEs to access the CPN and/or 5G network services.\n5) A PIN Element that provides a means for an authorized administrator to configure and manage a PIN.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2216, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  A base station installed in a CPN for UEs to access the CPN and/or 5G network services.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the SCP (Service Communication Proxy) in the Service-Based Architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable indirect communication between NF and NF Services\n2) To facilitate communication between the HSS and the UDR\n3) To provide service-based interfaces for interactions between 5GC and IMS\n4) To enable 5G migration towards the UDM/UDR architecture\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2217, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable indirect communication between NF and NF Services", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the time reference provided to users broadcasted in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Via a dedicated RRC signalling\n2) Using the GPS/UTC time format\n3) Via SIB16\n4) Through a synchronization channel\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2228, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Via SIB16", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main characteristic of the 5GC architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Deeper use of Network Slicing\n2) Mobile Edge Computing\n3) Network Capability Exposure\n4) Service-Based Architecture\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2245, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Service-Based Architecture", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the PDCCH-based power saving signal/channel for wake-up purpose? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide assistance information to the network\n2) To skip the PDCCH during the next occurrence of the drx-onDurationTimer\n3) To indicate UE preference of transitioning out of RRC_CONNECTED state\n4) To reduce PDCCH monitoring on activated SCells\n5) To monitor the PDCCH during the next occurrence of the drx-onDurationTimer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2254, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To monitor the PDCCH during the next occurrence of the drx-onDurationTimer", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following functions are included in the mobility functions of the RRC sublayer? \n\nOptions:\n1) Handover and context transfer\n2) UE cell selection and reselection\n3) Control of cell selection and reselection\n4) Inter-RAT mobility\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2256, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich keys are derived from KgNB for the protection of UP traffic between ME and gNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) KNASint and KNASenc\n2) KUPint and KUPenc\n3) KRRCint and KRRCenc\n4) KgNB and NH\n5) NH and KAMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2259, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  KUPint and KUPenc", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of MDT data collection? \n\nOptions:\n1) To optimize resource usage in the RAN\n2) To capture user consent related to privacy\n3) To provide performance measurements on the Shared E-UTRAN/NG-RAN\n4) To improve signal strength for UEs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2264, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To provide performance measurements on the Shared E-UTRAN/NG-RAN", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat physical layer measurement quantity can be used for sidelink? \n\nOptions:\n1) RSRP\n2) RSRQ\n3) RSSI\n4) CQI\n5) UL SINR\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2268, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  RSSI", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identity is used for Semi-Persistent Scheduling in the downlink or configured grant in the uplink? \n\nOptions:\n1) C-RNTI\n2) CI-RNTI\n3) CS-RNTI\n4) INT-RNTI\n5) P-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2276, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  CS-RNTI", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of bearer is used for IMS Signalling and IMS voice in the NSA architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Master Cell Group bearer\n2) Secondary Cell Group bearer\n3) Split bearer\n4) Primary Cell Group bearer\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2278, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Secondary Cell Group bearer", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum value for the false alarm probability for PRACH detection? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.1%\n2) 1%\n3) 5%\n4) 10%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2279, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  0.1%", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the MuD and MiD services used for? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allow another user to use one or more of its identities\n2) To support the increasing number of smart devices with call capabilities\n3) To distribute calls to any member of a group or firm\n4) To provide a consistent user experience for multi-device and multi-identity use cases\n5) To realize IMS enhancement for Multi-device and multi-identity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2293, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To provide a consistent user experience for multi-device and multi-identity use cases", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich performance criterion is used to minimize cell congestion in the Evolved Packet System? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reduced network complexity\n2) Steering of roaming methods\n3) Mixed traffic support\n4) Enhanced load balancing\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2296, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Enhanced load balancing", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UE do when 3GPP PS Data Off is activated? \n\nOptions:\n1) Informs the network that 3GPP PS Data Off is activated\n2) Ceases the sending of uplink IP Packets of all services\n3) Ceases the sending of uplink traffic over non-IP PDN types\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2310, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does SL DRX stand for in the context of NR Sidelink? \n\nOptions:\n1) Sidelink Directional Resource Control\n2) Sidelink Data Retransmission and Retransmission Timer\n3) Sidelink Dynamic Radio Connection\n4) Sidelink Discontinuous Reception\n5) Sidelink Distributed Resource Allocation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2320, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Sidelink Discontinuous Reception", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can RF (radio frequency) interference between aerial and ground users be minimized in the 3GPP network?\n\nOptions:\n1) Using multiple antennas and beamforming\n2) Using open loop and closed loop power control\n3) Using new scheduling, admission, and congestion control mechanisms\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2321, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of information is transferred in the TL-Container? \n\nOptions:\n1) InterfaceConfiguration\n2) EndStationInterfaces\n3) Buffer capability\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2326, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the work item related to group based enhancements in the network capability exposure functions? \n\nOptions:\n1) To reduce the signaling burden in handling a high number of UEs\n2) To improve operator control using new UE configuration parameters\n3) To specify the management concepts, architecture, requirements and procedures for CM, FM, PM, LCM\n4) To enable cross-operator accounting based on consumed data volume\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2337, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To reduce the signaling burden in handling a high number of UEs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich error sources are studied for timing-based positioning methods? \n\nOptions:\n1) TRP/UE measurements errors.\n2) Error in assistance data.\n3) TRP/UE Timing error.\n4) All of the above.\n5) None of the above.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2347, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the responsibility of the NG-RAN regarding the maximum UP integrity protection data rate? \n\nOptions:\n1) To negotiate the maximum data rate with the UE\n2) To inform the SMF if the maximum data rate is exceeded\n3) To strictly enforce the maximum data rate\n4) To reject the establishment of UP resources if it cannot support the maximum data rate\n5) To adjust the maximum data rate based on network congestion\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2352, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To strictly enforce the maximum data rate", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the SCG of the UE suspended in RRC_INACTIVE state? \n\nOptions:\n1) The CU of SN sends the UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND\n2) The CU of SN sends the UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE\n3) The DU of SN sends the UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE\n4) The CU of SN sends the UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION REQUEST\n5) The DU of SN sends the UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION REQUEST\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2355, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The DU of SN sends the UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION REQUEST", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is Non-Seamless WLAN offload (NSWO) in the context of 5GS? \n\nOptions:\n1) A network function that supports authentication for NSWO\n2) A capability of a UE to route specific IP flows via WLAN access\n3) A service-based interface for NSWO authentication\n4) A configuration for NSWO roaming\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2357, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  A capability of a UE to route specific IP flows via WLAN access", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of measurements does the Performance Measurement Function (PMF) support for ATSSS-LL functionality? \n\nOptions:\n1) Latency measurements\n2) Quality of Service (QoS) measurements\n3) Throughput measurements\n4) Availability measurements\n5) Round Trip Time (RTT) measurements\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2358, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Round Trip Time (RTT) measurements", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich IE includes the sidelink pre-configured parameters used for NR sidelink communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) SL-PreconfigurationNR\n2) SL-TxProfile-r17\n3) SL-AccessInfo-L2U2N-r17\n4) SL-RoHC-Profiles-r16\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2365, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  SL-PreconfigurationNR", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat authentication method does the 5G system support for legacy non-3GPP devices accessing a 5G LAN-VN? \n\nOptions:\n1) Biometrics\n2) Alternative authentication methods\n3) 3GPP credentials\n4) Non-3GPP identities and credentials\n5) EAP framework\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2367, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  3GPP credentials", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Work Item for eMBMS enhancements address? \n\nOptions:\n1) Mobile network interface for MBMS delivery\n2) System architecture enhancements for TV service\n3) Improved streaming QoE reporting\n4) Media handling aspects of multi-stream multiparty conferencing\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2370, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  System architecture enhancements for TV service", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of N4 session management procedures? \n\nOptions:\n1) To control the functionality of the SMF\n2) To control the functionality of the UPF\n3) To establish N4 sessions between the SMF and UPF\n4) To report events from the UPF to the SMF\n5) To release N4 session contexts in the UPF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2380, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To control the functionality of the UPF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the power components recommended to be considered for RRM measurement power saving evaluation in the CONNECTED state? \n\nOptions:\n1) Sleep\n2) PDCCH-only monitoring during active time\n3) SSB measurement\n4) Neighboring cell search\n5) Loop convergence (AGC, TTL & FTL) / time-frequency tracking\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2382, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Loop convergence (AGC, TTL & FTL) / time-frequency tracking", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen are the 3GPP Data Off Exempt Services enforced in the IMS domain? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the non-Allowed Area reporting procedure is initiated.\n2) During inter-LADN mobility procedures.\n3) During the ATSSS Control procedure.\n4) When the 3GPP Data Off status of the UE is set to 'activated'.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2386, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  When the 3GPP Data Off status of the UE is set to 'activated'.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich entities are dedicated for interworking between 5GS and EPC? \n\nOptions:\n1) PGW and SMF/UPF\n2) UPF and PGW-U\n3) PGW-C and SMF\n4) SMF and UPF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2396, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  UPF and PGW-U", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the feature 'Enhancements to LTE operation in unlicensed spectrum' enable? \n\nOptions:\n1) QoS differentiation for better user experience\n2) Extended reach of the ProSe framework\n3) Integration of selected WLAN direct discovery technologies\n4) Efficient use of UL resources on unlicensed spectrum\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2397, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Efficient use of UL resources on unlicensed spectrum", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum tolerable packet loss rate for reliability of V2X application messages? \n\nOptions:\n1) 10%\n2) 5%\n3) 3%\n4) 1%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2404, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  1%", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the function of the Home Subscriber Server (HSS)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide support to the call control servers.\n2) To hold user identification and numbering information.\n3) To generate user security information.\n4) To support the authentication procedures.\n5) To provide access to service profile data.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2408, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide support to the call control servers.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat should a 5G Visited Mobile Network have in order to allow a UE with a 5G subscription to roam into it? \n\nOptions:\n1) A roaming agreement with the UE's 5G Home Mobile Network\n2) Support for establishing home network\n3) Support for services provided in the home network\n4) Access to a partnership network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2414, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  A roaming agreement with the UE's 5G Home Mobile Network", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the definition of in-channel selectivity (ICS)? \n\nOptions:\n1) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive a wanted signal in the presence of an interfering signal in the received SAN channel bandwidth.\n2) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive the wanted signal at its assigned channel frequency in the presence of an adjacent channel signal.\n3) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive the wanted signal at its assigned resource block locations in the presence of an interfering signal at a larger power spectral density.\n4) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive a wanted signal in the presence of a spurious emission.\n5) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive a wanted signal in the presence of an unwanted interferer out of the operating band.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2430, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The measure of the receiver's ability to receive the wanted signal at its assigned resource block locations in the presence of an interfering signal at a larger power spectral density.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the relative increase in free space path loss from 43.5 GHz to 48.2 GHz? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.33 dB\n2) 0.9 dB\n3) 3.5 dB\n4) 7.7 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2432, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  0.9 dB", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat location information can be provided in the request for QoS Sustainability analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) Area Of Interest in coarse granularity\n2) Area Of Interest in fine granularity\n3) Path of Interest in coarse granularity\n4) Path of Interest in fine granularity\n5) Both Area Of Interest in coarse granularity and Path of Interest in fine granularity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2443, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Both Area Of Interest in coarse granularity and Path of Interest in fine granularity", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the supported functionality of the RN? \n\nOptions:\n1) RRC, NAS, and physical layer functionality\n2) S1 and X2 protocol termination\n3) Serving UEs and NNSF support\n4) Configuration and reconfiguration of RN subframe\n5) Inter-cell handover\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2455, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  RRC, NAS, and physical layer functionality", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the definition of OTA occupied bandwidth? \n\nOptions:\n1) The measure of the difference between the actual SAN transmit frequency and the assigned frequency.\n2) The difference between the power of an RE and the average RE power for a SAN at maximum output power.\n3) The difference between the maximum and the minimum transmit power of an OFDM symbol for a specified reference condition.\n4) The width of a frequency band such that, below the lower and above the upper frequency limits, the mean powers emitted are each equal to a specified percentage of the total mean transmitted power.\n5) The ratio of the filtered mean power centered on the assigned channel frequency to the filtered mean power centered on an adjacent channel frequency.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2456, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The width of a frequency band such that, below the lower and above the upper frequency limits, the mean powers emitted are each equal to a specified percentage of the total mean transmitted power.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is considered for evaluation purpose in the energy consumption modeling for a BS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Multiple power state(s)\n2) Reference configuration\n3) Scaling method\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2461, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Signalling gateway function? \n\nOptions:\n1) To interconnect different signalling networks\n2) To provide voice and other CS-domain services\n3) To support charging and billing mechanisms\n4) To facilitate communications with packet data networks and applications\n5) To enable Proximity-based Services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2467, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To interconnect different signalling networks", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the extended work item on 8K Television over 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) To define HEVC-based 8K TV operation point and media decoding capabilities\n2) To improve the distribution of 8K TV content with 5G\n3) To support higher decoding capabilities in TV and mobile device\n4) To specify ISO BMFF encapsulation and DASH signalling for 8K TV\n5) To conduct trials and produce content in 8K\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2471, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To define HEVC-based 8K TV operation point and media decoding capabilities", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn supporting an MA PDU Session, what does Rel-17 enable in terms of 3GPP access over EPC? \n\nOptions:\n1) Direct connection of 3GPP access to 5GC\n2) Establishment of user-plane resources over EPC\n3) Use of NG-RAN access for all user-plane traffic\n4) Exclusive use of a non-3GPP access for user-plane traffic\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2474, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Establishment of user-plane resources over EPC", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the NG-C interface in the NG-RAN architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transport of user plane data towards the UPF\n2) Transport of control plane information towards the AMF\n3) Transport of NAS messages\n4) Configuration transfer\n5) UE mobility management\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2477, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Transport of control plane information towards the AMF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the system properties required for 5G systems to be suitable for automation in vertical domains? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Reliability, availability, and maintainability\n2) Flexibility, safety, and integrity\n3) Dependability, reliability, and maintainability\n4) Availability, safety, and integrity\n5) Reliability, availability, maintainability, safety, and integrity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2480, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Reliability, availability, maintainability, safety, and integrity", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the format of the UE Radio Capability ID? \n\nOptions:\n1) It includes a Vendor ID\n2) It includes a Version ID\n3) It includes both Vendor ID and Version ID\n4) It does not include any IDs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2483, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  It includes both Vendor ID and Version ID", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich feature in Rel-16 allows transmission of uplink data payload using preconfigured uplink resources? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE-group wake-up signals (GWUS)\n2) Mobile-terminated early data transmission (MT-EDT)\n3) Support for Preconfigured uplink resources (PUR) in idle mode\n4) Scheduling of multiple DL/UL transport blocks with single DCI\n5) Presence of NRS on a non-anchor carrier for paging\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2487, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Support for Preconfigured uplink resources (PUR) in idle mode", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of contention window adjustment procedures for UL transmissions? \n\nOptions:\n1) To increase the contention window size for a specific priority class\n2) To increase the contention window size for all priority classes\n3) To decrease the contention window size for all priority classes\n4) To adjust the contention window size for a specific priority class\n5) To adjust the contention window size for all priority classes\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2488, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To adjust the contention window size for all priority classes", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the release condition for SIPTO@LN PDN connection after handover with a stand-alone gateway? \n\nOptions:\n1) The eNB triggers the release over the S5 interface\n2) The MME sends a release command to the eNB\n3) The collocated S-GW releases the connection\n4) The UE initiates the release procedure\n5) The SIPTO@LN PDN connection is not released after handover\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2491, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The SIPTO@LN PDN connection is not released after handover", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is EC-GSM-IoT? \n\nOptions:\n1) An extended version of EGPRS\n2) A new radio interface for Cellular IoT\n3) A low-power version of GPRS/EGPRS\n4) An enhanced version of GPRS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2493, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  An extended version of EGPRS", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the term 'user perception' refer to in the context of downlink parallel transfer of the same content via broadcast/multicast and/or unicast? \n\nOptions:\n1) User satisfaction with the delivered content.\n2) The difference in delay of typically less than 20 ms between receivers in a given area.\n3) The quality level (i.e. video resolution) of broadcast/multicast content.\n4) The capability of the UE to receive content via a broadcast/multicast radio carrier.\n5) The availability of the broadcast/multicast service.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2494, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The difference in delay of typically less than 20 ms between receivers in a given area.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UE do if it receives an RRC message on DCCH or CCCH that does not include a mandatory field? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ignore the message\n2) Treat the list as if the entry including the missing or not comprehended field was absent\n3) Consider the 'parent' field to be set to a not comprehended value\n4) Apply the generic error handling to the subsequent 'parent' field(s)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2507, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Ignore the message", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does a UE determine the number of PSFCH resources available for multiplexing control information? \n\nOptions:\n1) Based on sl-PSFCH-Occasion\n2) Based on sl-PSFCH-Period\n3) Based on sl-PSFCH-CandidateResourceType\n4) Based on sl-NumMuxCS-Pair\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2508, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Based on sl-NumMuxCS-Pair", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the MARCOM feature? \n\nOptions:\n1) To correct inconsistencies and clarify ambiguities\n2) To enhance the performance of LTE in high-speed scenarios\n3) To specify UE RRM requirements and demodulation requirements for high-speed train scenarios\n4) To enable maritime communication services to be supported over 3GPP systems\n5) To support the specific communication needs of railways\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2509, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To enable maritime communication services to be supported over 3GPP systems", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the average cable loss per meter at 48.2 GHz? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.33 dB\n2) 0.725 m\n3) 6 dB\n4) 43.5 GHz\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2510, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  0.33 dB", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is required for SRS bandwidth aggregation from RRM perspective? \n\nOptions:\n1) Different numerology for different carriers to be aggregated.\n2) Same slot and symbol for SRS resources from different carriers to be aggregated.\n3) Different TRP for SRS resources from different carriers to be aggregated.\n4) Different Antenna Reference Point (ARP) for SRS resources from different carriers to be aggregated.\n5) Different bandwidths for SRS resources from different carriers to be aggregated.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2518, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Same slot and symbol for SRS resources from different carriers to be aggregated.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of N19-based traffic forwarding? \n\nOptions:\n1) To forward UL/DL traffic for 5G VN communication\n2) To handle unicast, broadcast, and multicast communication\n3) To serve as a common PSA UPF for different PDU Sessions\n4) To realize traffic routing for multiple SMF Sets\n5) To establish user plane tunnels between different SMFs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2523, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To forward UL/DL traffic for 5G VN communication", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can the NW configure for NES-capable UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Priority of other UEs\n2) Down-prioritization of other UEs\n3) Specific NES cell(s) prioritization/down-prioritization on a specific frequency\n4) Both option 1 and option 2\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2533, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Specific NES cell(s) prioritization/down-prioritization on a specific frequency", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the polarization of a single polarized antenna? \n\nOptions:\n1) Horizontal polarization\n2) Vertical polarization\n3) Circular polarization\n4) Dual polarization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2537, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Vertical polarization", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn Rel-17, enhancements are made to several SEAL services. Which of the following is NOT an enhancement to SEAL services in Rel-17? \n\nOptions:\n1) Support for external group Id and group fetch procedure\n2) Support for management of 5G VN groups\n3) Support for temporary groups in a VAL system\n4) Support for enhanced Service Enabler Architecture Layer (SEAL)\n5) Support for location criteria in group creation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2561, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Support for enhanced Service Enabler Architecture Layer (SEAL)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface provides non-guaranteed delivery of user plane PDUs between the NG-RAN node and the UPF? \n\nOptions:\n1) NG-C interface\n2) Xn-C interface\n3) NG-U interface\n4) Xn-U interface\n5) NGAP interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2562, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  NG-U interface", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich protocol sublayer is responsible for maintaining the PDCP sequence numbers? \n\nOptions:\n1) MAC sublayer\n2) RLC sublayer\n3) PDCP sublayer\n4) SDAP sublayer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2581, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  PDCP sublayer", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat problem can occur with the current paging procedures in 5G networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) Handover failures\n2) Coverage holes\n3) Low UE throughput\n4) Repeated paging attempts\n5) Insufficient transmission power\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2582, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Repeated paging attempts", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Flow Based Charging (FBC) in 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable roaming Qos Flow Based Charging\n2) To enable flow-based QoS\n3) To enable charging for network slicing\n4) To enable charging for PDU session connectivity\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2590, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To enable charging for PDU session connectivity", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is TRS used for in TRS occasions? \n\nOptions:\n1) To configure DRX parameters\n2) To trigger PDCCH monitoring\n3) To enable cross-slot scheduling\n4) To track UE paging occasions\n5) To indicate L1 availability\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2596, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To track UE paging occasions", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn the NWDAF providing PDU Session traffic analytics, who requests or subscribes to the NWDAF? \n\nOptions:\n1) ULF\n2) SMF\n3) PCF\n4) UPF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2608, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  PCF", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of UICC applications? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide security features\n2) To host multiple applications\n3) To access the IMS services\n4) To store provisioning parameters\n5) To address applications via the radio interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2612, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To host multiple applications", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat message does the gNB-CU send to establish the UE context in the gNB-DU? \n\nOptions:\n1) RRCReconfiguration\n2) INITIAL CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST\n3) UE CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST\n4) UL RRC MESSAGE TRANSFER\n5) INITIAL UE MESSAGE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2614, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  UE CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Beam Peak Search Grid? \n\nOptions:\n1) To calculate the CDF of the EIRP/EIS distribution in 3D\n2) To determine the total power radiated by the DUT in the TX beam peak direction\n3) To determine the TX and RX beam peak direction\n4) To perform 3D EIRP scans for TX beam peak direction\n5) To perform 3D Throughput/RSRP/EIS scans for RX beam peak direction\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2633, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To determine the TX and RX beam peak direction", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the feature Scheduling of multiple DL/UL transport blocks with single DCI allow? \n\nOptions:\n1) Scheduling of multiple transport blocks in uplink\n2) Scheduling of multiple transport blocks in downlink\n3) HARQ bundling for uplink transmission\n4) Reduced DCI overhead for contiguous UL/DL transmissions\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2638, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the gNB request the UE UTRA-FDD capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) During NAS signalling\n2) Before handover to UTRAN\n3) When responding to the gNB\n4) When the capabilities are the same\n5) During NR capabilities request\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2640, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Before handover to UTRAN", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main role of the UTM (UAS Traffic Management) in the 3GPP network?\n\nOptions:\n1) To manage UAS node authentication and credential information\n2) To establish C2 communications between the UAV and the ground control station\n3) To extend the coverage and capacity of the cellular network\n4) To support local routing and proximity-based services\n5) To minimize RF interference in the network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2646, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To manage UAS node authentication and credential information", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main function of a Radio Network Controller (RNC)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Control of one or more Node B\n2) Communicating with Mobile Stations in a certain area\n3) Serve one cell\n4) Serve one or more UTRAN cells\n5) Provide the E-UTRA user plane and control plane protocol terminations towards the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2652, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Control of one or more Node B", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn online charging without reservation, what happens if the OCS rejects the resource usage request? \n\nOptions:\n1) The NE disallows the resource usage.\n2) The OCS initiates a refund for the original resource usage.\n3) The NE returns the resource usage authorisation to the network element.\n4) The network element executes the resource usage according to the user request and the OCS authorisation.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2654, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The NE disallows the resource usage.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich procedures are impacted by MUSIM according to TS 23.502 and TS 23.401? \n\nOptions:\n1) Service Request\n2) Registration / Attach / Tracking Area Update\n3) N2 Paging / S1 Paging\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2659, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat control mechanism allows/prevents UEs from accessing the network based on their capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) Access Class Barring\n2) Service Specific Access Control\n3) Control of UE Capabilities\n4) Extended Access Barring\n5) Application Specific Congestion Control for Data Communication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2666, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Control of UE Capabilities", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the work item on Enhanced LAA for LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable operation of an LAA SCell on the UL in unlicensed spectrum\n2) To support more than 1.04 million eNBs in a PLMN\n3) To define the requirements and signaling support for a new UE category with a single receiver\n4) To improve mobility and throughput performance under high speed scenarios\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2672, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable operation of an LAA SCell on the UL in unlicensed spectrum", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat actions can a UE take based on the recommended bitrate from the eNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) Perform CSFB\n2) Perform SRVCC\n3) Perform HARQ\n4) Perform MU-MIMO\n5) Initiate an end-to-end rate adaptation with the peer UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2699, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Initiate an end-to-end rate adaptation with the peer UE", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Discontinuous Reception (DRX) in idle mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) To increase power consumption\n2) To reduce power consumption\n3) To increase data transfer rate\n4) To reduce data transfer rate\n5) To improve network coverage\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2708, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To reduce power consumption", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat parameters are specified for MBS broadcast MTCH configurations? \n\nOptions:\n1) SL-PreconfigGeneral-r16\n2) SL-RoHC-Profiles-r16\n3) SL-UE-SelectedPreConfig-r16\n4) Parameters that are specified for MBS broadcast MTCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2716, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Parameters that are specified for MBS broadcast MTCH", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich technology can be used for the connection between the Evolved ProSe Remote UE and the Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay? \n\nOptions:\n1) E-UTRA only\n2) WLAN only\n3) Both E-UTRA and WLAN\n4) GSM and UMTS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2718, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both E-UTRA and WLAN", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can a UE transmit new data in LTE if there is new data arrival? \n\nOptions:\n1) Immediately in the same TTI (Transmission Time Interval)\n2) In the next first (s)TTI of the transmission window\n3) After waiting for a random time period\n4) After waiting for a predefined number of TTIs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2728, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  In the next first (s)TTI of the transmission window", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is a default DRB used? \n\nOptions:\n1) When there is congestion in the network\n2) When there is no matching mapping rule for an incoming UL packet\n3) When there is an RRC configured mapping rule\n4) When there is a reflective mapping rule\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2742, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  When there is no matching mapping rule for an incoming UL packet", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow do schedulers assign resources between UEs in MAC in gNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) Based on radio conditions reported by the UE\n2) Based on the maximum transmit power of the UE\n3) Based on the UE buffer status and QoS requirements\n4) Based on the UE's location in the network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2745, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Based on the UE buffer status and QoS requirements", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the supported sidelink resource allocation modes? \n\nOptions:\n1) Mode 1 and mode 2\n2) Mode 1 and mode 3\n3) Mode 2 and mode 4\n4) Mode 2 and mode 5\n5) Mode 3 and mode 4\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2751, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Mode 1 and mode 2", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Multimedia Priority Service Modifications? \n\nOptions:\n1) To align TS 22.153 with Stage 2 and 3 capabilities for Multimedia Priority Services\n2) To clarify and correct existing text and requirements in TS 22.153\n3) To include missing capabilities in TS 22.153\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2758, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is invocation in the context of the LCS client? \n\nOptions:\n1) An action to make the LCS feature available to a subscriber\n2) An action taken by the service provider to remove an available LCS feature from a LCS Client\u2019s subscription profile\n3) An action to invoke the LCS feature\n4) An action to bar the Location Service of a specific user\n5) An action to remove a privacy class from a target UE\u2019s PEL\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2763, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  An action to invoke the LCS feature", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the assistance information made available to the UE in UE-Assisted location services? \n\nOptions:\n1) The assistance information is encrypted and delivered through point to point signalling\n2) The assistance information is encrypted and continuously available in idle mode and during a call\n3) The assistance information is decrypted and delivered through point to point signalling\n4) The assistance information is decrypted and continuously available in idle mode and during a call\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2767, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The assistance information is encrypted and continuously available in idle mode and during a call", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat mechanisms provide priority to QoS Flows established for sessions during periods of extreme overload? \n\nOptions:\n1) (R)AN\n2) SMF\n3) AMF\n4) UPF\n5) PCF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2771, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  SMF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the SGNB ADDITION REQUEST message? \n\nOptions:\n1) To stop the data transmission for the UE\n2) To create a UE context\n3) To release the UE context\n4) To resume the SCG of the UE\n5) To setup bearer context\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2779, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To create a UE context", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does a Multi-USIM UE modify the timing of paging occasions in 5GS? \n\nOptions:\n1) By obtaining a new 5G-GUTI through a specific indication.\n2) By triggering a new 5G-GUTI reallocation without any specific indication.\n3) By requesting a 5G-GUTI reallocation from the network.\n4) By providing an IMSI offset value in the Attach Request message.\n5) By performing a MRU and obtaining a new 5G-GUTI.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2782, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  By triggering a new 5G-GUTI reallocation without any specific indication.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the periodic CSI-RS resource configuration indexes? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide radio link quality measurements on the BWP of the serving cell.\n2) To determine the set of RS indexes for monitoring PDCCH.\n3) To indicate the TCI states for PDCCH monitoring.\n4) To activate the MAC CE for failure detection.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2783, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide radio link quality measurements on the BWP of the serving cell.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the starting position of a bandwidth part defined? \n\nOptions:\n1) offsetToCarrier in the SCS-SpecificCarrier IE\n2) absoluteFrequencyPointA for all cases\n3) txDirectCurrentLocation in the UplinkTxDirectCurrentBWP IE\n4) offsetToPointA for a PCell downlink\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2788, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  offsetToPointA for a PCell downlink", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the areas covered in the eV2X work of Rel-15 to enhance 3GPP support for V2X scenarios? \n\nOptions:\n1) Vehicle platooning, advanced driving, and remote driving\n2) Basic safety services, extended sensors, and general aspects\n3) Advanced driving, remote driving, and extended sensors\n4) Vehicle platooning, advanced driving, extended sensors, and remote driving\n5) Advanced driving, extended sensors, and general aspects\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2793, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Vehicle platooning, advanced driving, extended sensors, and remote driving", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of local breakout in the Evolved Packet System? \n\nOptions:\n1) To optimize routing for user plane traffic\n2) To support mobility within and across access systems\n3) To minimize packet loss during inter- and/or intra-access technology changes\n4) To provide service continuity during changes of access systems\n5) To support simultaneous usage of multiple accesses\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2812, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To optimize routing for user plane traffic", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat architectural or protocol changes are expected to have minimum impact on the 5G system? \n\nOptions:\n1) Voice service continuity from NG-RAN to UTRAN CS\n2) Voice service continuity from NG-RAN to GERAN\n3) CS fallback from NG-RAN to UTRAN\n4) Seamless handover between NG-RAN and UTRAN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2821, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Voice service continuity from NG-RAN to UTRAN CS", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when the AF requests EAS rediscovery for impacted applications in HR-SBO context? \n\nOptions:\n1) H-SMF sends Nsmf_PDUSession_Update Request to the target V-SMF\n2) V-SMF sends Nsmf_PDUSession_Update Response to the H-SMF\n3) H-SMF sends Nsmf_PDUSession_Update Response to the AF\n4) V-SMF initiates PDU Session Modification command to the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2824, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  H-SMF sends Nsmf_PDUSession_Update Request to the target V-SMF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of timing resiliency in a 5G system? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide backup timing sources in case of GNSS signal degradation.\n2) To enhance the accuracy of primary reference Time Clocks.\n3) To monitor and report timing errors to UEs and applications.\n4) To support ranging-based services in 5G networks.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2830, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide backup timing sources in case of GNSS signal degradation.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of NWDAF in the 5G system architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) To interact with different entities for data collection\n2) To store and retrieve data from ADRF\n3) To provide analytics to consumers\n4) To exchange analytics and collect input data between PLMNs\n5) To request and subscribe to trained ML model provisioning services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2835, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To interact with different entities for data collection", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Extended Access Barring? \n\nOptions:\n1) To prevent overload of the access network and/or the core network\n2) To control access to network provided services or functions\n3) To allow/prevent new access attempts from particular applications\n4) To differentiate between CS and PS domains\n5) To specify the categories of subscribers who are barred from network access\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2841, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To prevent overload of the access network and/or the core network", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when the UE applies a zero value for a timer? \n\nOptions:\n1) The timer starts and immediately expires\n2) The timer stops and is reset\n3) The timer is paused indefinitely\n4) The timer is set to an infinite value\n5) The timer is set to a predefined default value\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2845, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The timer starts and immediately expires", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the 3GPP PS Data Off Exempt Services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Services provided by the home PLMN only.\n2) Services provided by any VPLMN.\n3) Operator services defined in specific standards.\n4) Services related to non-3GPP access.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2858, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Operator services defined in specific standards.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the N5CW device in the control plane for trusted WLAN access? \n\nOptions:\n1) To establish a secure NAS signalling connection between the UE and the WLAN access network\n2) To handle EAP-based access authentication procedure\n3) To manage session management between the UE and the TNGF\n4) To manage user plane PDU Session establishment and release\n5) To provide access control for the UE connecting to the WLAN access network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2859, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To handle EAP-based access authentication procedure", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Real-Time Text conversation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support multimedia services with IP telephony\n2) To support multimedia services with circuit-switched technology\n3) To enable real-time, character by character, text conversation\n4) To provide streaming services using packet-switched technology\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2866, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To enable real-time, character by character, text conversation", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Network Slice AS Group (NSAG)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To monitor and control the number of registered UEs per network slice\n2) To allocate resources to a slice in case of slice resources shortage\n3) To provide Target NSSAI and RFSP to RAN to steer the UE to another cell\n4) To perform slice aware cell reselection and slice specific RACH configuration\n5) To support slice specific RACH configuration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2874, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To perform slice aware cell reselection and slice specific RACH configuration", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the prohibit timer in the network? \n\nOptions:\n1) To trigger SR counters\n2) To perform rate adaptation\n3) To limit frequent query messages\n4) To enable CSFB\n5) To configure bundle frequency hopping\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2891, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To limit frequent query messages", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat factors are considered when deciding on service delivery? \n\nOptions:\n1) User preferences and network conditions\n2) User preferences and serving network capabilities\n3) User profile and network conditions\n4) User profile and serving network capabilities\n5) User preferences, user profile, and network conditions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2898, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  User profile and serving network capabilities", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the sub-frame structure in V2V communications? \n\nOptions:\n1) To handle high Doppler and improve tracking\n2) To transmit scheduling assignments\n3) To provide time synchronization\n4) To allocate data resources\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2908, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To handle high Doppler and improve tracking", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of credit pooling in charging? \n\nOptions:\n1) To reserve all the user's credit for new services\n2) To avoid credit fragmentation and unnecessary load on the server\n3) To calculate network access charges for home subscribers\n4) To determine charges for inter-operator settlement\n5) To facilitate charging for roaming architecture for Voice over IMS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2917, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To avoid credit fragmentation and unnecessary load on the server", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NEF (PFDF) send in response to the SMF after PFD retrieval? \n\nOptions:\n1) Nnef_PFDManagement_Subscribe\n2) Nudr_DM_Query\n3) Nnef_PFDManagement_Create/Update/Delete\n4) Nnef_PFDManagement_Fetch\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2924, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Nnef_PFDManagement_Fetch", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich 3GPP release introduced Device to Device (D2D) communication?\n\nOptions:\n1) Rel-8\n2) Rel-12\n3) Rel-14\n4) Rel-16\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2926, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Rel-12", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are network nodes and NG-RAN configured with Disaster Condition? \n\nOptions:\n1) Based on operator policy and the request by government agencies.\n2) Based on operator policy only.\n3) Based on the request by government agencies only.\n4) Based on international standards.\n5) Based on customer requests.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2931, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Based on operator policy and the request by government agencies.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of User Plane Security Enforcement information? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enforce maximum UP integrity protection data rate\n2) To indicate whether UP confidentiality protection is required\n3) To determine User Plane Security Policy locally\n4) To communicate the maximum supported data rate for integrity protection\n5) To provide NG-RAN with User Plane security policies\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2936, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To provide NG-RAN with User Plane security policies", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow do non-supporting UEs handle the broadcast system information in a shared network? \n\nOptions:\n1) They rely on the SIM/USIM card for information.\n2) They decode the broadcast system information to determine available operators.\n3) They request the broadcast system information from the RAN.\n4) They ignore the broadcast system information.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2947, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  They ignore the broadcast system information.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which scenario is the UL CL/BP UPF and L-PSA UPF co-located in the single V-UPF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Home-routed roaming\n2) EAS discovery with V-EASDF\n3) EAS discovery with Local DNS\n4) EAS discovery with IP replacement mechanism\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2962, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Home-routed roaming", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the UEAssistanceInformationSidelink message? \n\nOptions:\n1) To request UE sidelink capabilities\n2) To include the system information transmitted by a UE via SL-BCH\n3) To indicate the failure of a PC5 RRC AS reconfiguration\n4) To include sidelink DRX assistance information used to determine the sidelink DRX configuration\n5) To transfer UE radio access capabilities\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2964, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To include sidelink DRX assistance information used to determine the sidelink DRX configuration", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many blind physical layer transmissions are required in the new coverage class mapping for EC operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Same as existing coverage classes\n2) Twice the number compared to existing coverage classes\n3) Half the number compared to existing coverage classes\n4) One less than the number compared to existing coverage classes\n5) Three times the number compared to existing coverage classes\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2966, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Twice the number compared to existing coverage classes", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the QoE measurement configuration received from OAM or CN encapsulated in? \n\nOptions:\n1) A QoE Measurement Configuration container\n2) A Measurement Report message\n3) A Measurement Configuration container\n4) A QoE Measurement Control message\n5) A Measurement Control message\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2977, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  A Measurement Control message", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the measure of modulation quality for NB-IoT? \n\nOptions:\n1) Error Vector Magnitude (EVM) in dB\n2) Received Signal Strength Indicator (RSSI)\n3) Carrier-to-Interference plus Noise Ratio (CINR)\n4) Frequency deviation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2987, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Error Vector Magnitude (EVM) in dB", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of bundle frequency hopping in the LTE network? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enhance bundle frequency hopping\n2) To enable UL/DL bitrate recommendation\n3) To improve PUSCH enhancement mode\n4) To support multi-subframe channel estimation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2991, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To support multi-subframe channel estimation", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen the user profile is changed in the UDM/UDR and affects the user profile in the AMF, how does the UDM notify the affected AMF? \n\nOptions:\n1) By invoking Nudm_SDM_Notification service operation\n2) By invoking Nudm_SDM_Info service operation\n3) By initiating a UE Configuration Update procedure\n4) By initiating a UE Parameters Update via UDM Control Plane Procedure\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2995, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  By invoking Nudm_SDM_Notification service operation", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Access Traffic Steering, Switching and Splitting (ATSS) feature in 5G networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) To establish a Multi Access (MA) PDU Session for data communication between the UE and UPF\n2) To improve network performance measurements in Rel-16\n3) To support 3GPP access over EPC only\n4) To prioritize 3GPP access over non-3GPP access in load balancing\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 2998, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To establish a Multi Access (MA) PDU Session for data communication between the UE and UPF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are MCCH transmissions and associated radio resources indicated to the UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Via PCFICH addressed to MCCH-RNTI\n2) Via PCPICH addressed to MCCH-RNTI\n3) Via PDCCH addressed to MCCH-RNTI\n4) Via PHICH addressed to MCCH-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3004, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Via PDCCH addressed to MCCH-RNTI", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich message is used for the indication of measurement results of NR sidelink? \n\nOptions:\n1) SCCH-Message\n2) RRCReconfigurationSidelink\n3) NotificationMessageSidelink\n4) MeasurementReportSidelink\n5) UECapabilityInformationSidelink\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3012, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  MeasurementReportSidelink", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the reference condition for the SAN total power dynamic range? \n\nOptions:\n1) OFDM symbol power for a SAN when transmitting on all RBs at maximum output power\n2) Average power for single RB transmission\n3) RS power indicated on the DL-SCH\n4) Minimum deviation between the DL RS power indicated on the DL-SCH and the DL RS power of each E-UTRA carrier at the SAN antenna connector\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3015, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  OFDM symbol power for a SAN when transmitting on all RBs at maximum output power", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Network Data Analytics Function (NWDAF)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To measure PRB usage for MIMO\n2) To optimize inter-system load balancing\n3) To support network automation\n4) To calculate the energy efficiency of base stations\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3022, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To support network automation", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of data security and privacy methods does the 5G system support? \n\nOptions:\n1) Authentication and authorization methods\n2) Integrity protection and confidentiality methods\n3) Protection against tampering and spoofing\n4) End-to-end encryption\n5) Protection of user location information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3024, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Integrity protection and confidentiality methods", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the value of SCSREFSENS used in the Noc methodology? \n\nOptions:\n1) 120 kHz\n2) 100 MHz\n3) 12\n4) -1 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3030, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  120 kHz", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Evolution to and Interworking with eCall in IMS work item? \n\nOptions:\n1) To introduce password protection for activation of supplementary services in IMS\n2) To specify eMBMS enhancements for LTE\n3) To provide media handling extensions for IMS-based telepresence\n4) To introduce the support of end-to-end eCall over IMS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3034, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To introduce the support of end-to-end eCall over IMS", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the RNC indicate the UE selected core network operator to the CN for supporting UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) By sending a Target ID in the Relocation Required message\n2) By sending an RRC signalling message\n3) Implicitly from an already existing signalling connection\n4) By transmitting it in broadcast system information\n5) By using the SNA Access Information IE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3046, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Implicitly from an already existing signalling connection", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a requirement for ProSe Discovery to determine whether other ProSe-enabled UEs are of interest to a discovering ProSe-enabled UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Proximity to each other.\n2) Support from the EPC.\n3) Authorisation from the operator.\n4) PLMN registration.\n5) Use of WLAN direct discovery.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3051, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Authorisation from the operator.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does NWDAF stand for? \n\nOptions:\n1) Network Analytics Data Function\n2) Network Data Analytics Framework\n3) Network Data Analytics Function\n4) Network Data Analytics Federation\n5) Network Analytics Data Framework\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3061, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Network Data Analytics Function", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identity is used for filtering of packets at the physical layer of the receiver in NR sidelink communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) CS-RNTI\n2) TPC-SRS-RNTI\n3) Source Layer-2 ID (LSB part)\n4) CI-RNTI\n5) TPC-PUCCH-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3062, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Source Layer-2 ID (LSB part)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat do the reference architectures for supporting Edge Computing in 5GS build upon? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reference architectures for non-roaming and LBO roaming scenarios\n2) Reference architectures for non-roaming, LBO roaming, and HR-SBO roaming scenarios\n3) Reference architectures for LBO roaming and HR-SBO roaming scenarios\n4) Reference architectures specified in TS 23.501\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3066, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Reference architectures specified in TS 23.501", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the management service producer responsible for DV measurement control allow its authorized consumer to do? \n\nOptions:\n1) Request measurement data for PEE parameters\n2) Request measurement data for DV parameters\n3) Start and stop the collection of DV measurement data\n4) Fetch PEE performance data files\n5) Indicate the reporting method for PEE measurement data\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3068, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Start and stop the collection of DV measurement data", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the QFI in the downlink? \n\nOptions:\n1) To indicate QoS flow mapping in RQoS\n2) To differentiate GBR and non-GBR flows\n3) To establish PDU sessions\n4) To determine radio interface treatment\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3070, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To indicate QoS flow mapping in RQoS", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does a UE start and stop PDCCH monitoring according to search space sets with different group indexes? \n\nOptions:\n1) At the beginning of a slot after the last symbol of a PDCCH reception\n2) At the beginning of a slot after a PUCCH transmission\n3) At the beginning of a slot following timer expiration\n4) At the beginning of a slot after a PDCCH skipping duration expires\n5) At the beginning of a slot after a PDCCH reception providing the DCI format with the PDCCH monitoring adaptation field\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3072, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  At the beginning of a slot after a PDCCH reception providing the DCI format with the PDCCH monitoring adaptation field", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nUnder what conditions can the target UE be positioned? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only if allowed in the UE subscription profile\n2) Only if the target UE gives explicit authorization\n3) Only if required by local regulatory requirements\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3074, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a control-resource set consist of? \n\nOptions:\n1) Symbols\n2) Resource blocks\n3) Bits\n4) Control-channel elements\n5) Control-resource sets\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3085, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Resource blocks", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat were the RF requirements introduced in TS 36.101 for new CA scenarios? \n\nOptions:\n1) Support of Carrier Aggregation (CA) for mode-4\n2) Support for 64-QAM\n3) Reduction of the maximum time between packet arrival and resource selection\n4) Radio resource pool sharing between mode-3 and mode-4 UEs\n5) Transmit diversity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3088, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Support of Carrier Aggregation (CA) for mode-4", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich security procedure is used for RRC and UP security algorithms negotiation and RRC security activation? \n\nOptions:\n1) AMF SMC procedure\n2) NAS SMC procedure\n3) AS SMC procedure\n4) UE SMC procedure\n5) gNB SMC procedure\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3099, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  AS SMC procedure", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich power states are considered in the power consumption model for a BS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Sleep mode only\n2) Non-sleep mode only\n3) Both sleep and non-sleep modes\n4) No power states are considered\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3100, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both sleep and non-sleep modes", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information is incorporated into the CDRs produced by IMS network elements for inter operator accounting purposes? \n\nOptions:\n1) Charging events generated by CTF.\n2) IOI identities received in the session signalling.\n3) Operator identification information used for IOI.\n4) Addresses and identifiers of IMS NEs and applications.\n5) Correlation information for the same resource usage.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3103, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  IOI identities received in the session signalling.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich position accuracy can be achieved using carrier phase measurements in NR carrier phase positioning? \n\nOptions:\n1) Decameter-level accuracy\n2) Meter-level accuracy\n3) Centimeter-level accuracy\n4) Millimeter-level accuracy\n5) Kilometer-level accuracy\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3106, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Centimeter-level accuracy", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NEF (PFDF) do after determining whether to create/update/delete PFDs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Invokes Nudr_DM_Query\n2) Invokes Nnef_PFD_Management_Notify\n3) Invokes Nnef_PFDManagement_Subscribe\n4) Invokes Nnef_PFDManagement_Create/Update/Delete\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3108, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Invokes Nnef_PFD_Management_Notify", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the need for NG-RAN to continue reporting the UE's location cease? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the UE transitions to CM-IDLE state\n2) When the UE receives a cancel indication from the AMF\n3) When the NG-RAN sends a cancel indication to the AMF\n4) When the UE moves out of or into an area of interest\n5) When Dual Connectivity is activated\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3117, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  When the UE transitions to CM-IDLE state", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does BA configuration in the UE mean? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE has to monitor PDCCH on the entire DL frequency of the cell\n2) The UE does not have to monitor PDCCH on the entire DL frequency of the cell\n3) The UE has to monitor PDCCH on dedicated SSSG\n4) The UE has to monitor PDCCH continuously\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3122, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The UE does not have to monitor PDCCH on the entire DL frequency of the cell", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the ChannelAccess-CPext field indicate in Type-2 random access procedure for operation with shared spectrum channel access in FR1? \n\nOptions:\n1) Frequency band\n2) CP extension\n3) Frequency hopping flag\n4) Channel access type\n5) MCS index\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3126, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Channel access type", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the charging extensions in the feature related to WLAN access in EPC? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable QoS differentiation and better user experience\n2) To integrate WLAN direct discovery technologies\n3) To identify and charge for traffic transported over unlicensed access\n4) To enhance LTE operation in unlicensed spectrum\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3139, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To identify and charge for traffic transported over unlicensed access", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat conditions must be met for voice call continuity during emergency calls? \n\nOptions:\n1) The source network is IMS, the user is moving out of coverage, and the target network belongs to the same operator\n2) The source network is IMS, the target network supports emergency calls, and the user is moving into coverage\n3) The source network is CS, the target network supports emergency calls, and the user is moving out of coverage\n4) The source network is CS, the target network supports emergency calls, and the user is moving into coverage\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3143, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The source network is IMS, the user is moving out of coverage, and the target network belongs to the same operator", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the types of analytics that the NF can request in the Nnwdaf_AnalyticsSubscription_Subscribe Request? \n\nOptions:\n1) Statistics\n2) Predictions\n3) Both statistics and predictions\n4) The type of analytics cannot be requested in Nnwdaf_AnalyticsSubscription_Subscribe Request\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3178, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both statistics and predictions", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NG-RAN do immediately following step 1a of the Connection Inactive procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) Sends N2 MT Communication Handling request message to AMF\n2) Sends RRC message to suspend the RRC Connection towards the UE\n3) Sends Nsmf_PDUSession_UpdateSMContext Request to AMF\n4) Sends N4 Session Modification Request to UPF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3189, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Sends N2 MT Communication Handling request message to AMF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the key functionalities of MDT enhancement? \n\nOptions:\n1) To optimize inter-system load balancing\n2) To enhance energy efficiency\n3) To improve mobility optimization\n4) To enhance network data analytics services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3196, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To enhance network data analytics services", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWho decides on the service delivery in a roaming scenario? \n\nOptions:\n1) The serving network\n2) The subscriber\n3) The Home environment\n4) The network operator\n5) The user profile\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3216, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The Home environment", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat role can the 3GPP network play in the selection of an Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay? \n\nOptions:\n1) Control the selection explicitly through signaling\n2) Control the selection implicitly through provisioning of policies\n3) Pre-configure Relay UE discovery information\n4) Provision relay UE selection information in the Evolved ProSe Remote UE\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3218, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is one major limitation of Release 15 in 5GC that Release 16 Network Slicing addresses? \n\nOptions:\n1) Inadequate support for interworking between EPC and 5GC\n2) Lack of network slice based authentication and authorization\n3) Insufficient performance measurements for 5G networks\n4) Limited management capabilities for multiple tenant environments\n5) Inadequate performance assurance for 5G networks\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3222, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Inadequate support for interworking between EPC and 5GC", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens if a UE wants to access the 5GS and is configured for Extended Access Barring (EAB)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Unified Access Control checks are performed for Access Category 1\n2) Unified Access Control checks are ignored for Access Category 1\n3) Unified Access Control checks are performed for Access Category 2\n4) Unified Access Control checks are ignored for Access Category 2\n5) Unified Access Control checks are not supported by the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3234, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Unified Access Control checks are performed for Access Category 1", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Ethernet Header Compression (EHC) in the support of NR Industrial Internet of Things? \n\nOptions:\n1) To increase efficiency of Ethernet frames transmission over the NR air interface\n2) To provide redundancy over N3 tunnel between UPF and NG-RAN on a per QoS flow basis\n3) To support strict synchronization accuracy requirements of Time Sensitive Communications\n4) To maximize the reliability of transmission over the air interface\n5) To optimize handling of a mixture of URLLC and eMBB traffic\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3235, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To increase efficiency of Ethernet frames transmission over the NR air interface", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat controls the additional behavior of the SMF for 3GPP PS Data Off? \n\nOptions:\n1) Local configuration from the PCF.\n2) The list(s) of 3GPP Data Off Exempt Services provisioned in the UE.\n3) The ATSSS feature.\n4) The IMS domain policy.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3236, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Local configuration from the PCF.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the S8HR architecture for VoLTE roaming? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable local breakout in VoLTE roaming\n2) To improve voice quality in VoLTE roaming\n3) To reduce latency in VoLTE roaming\n4) To locate all entities in the HPLMN\n5) To establish emergency calls in VoLTE roaming\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3249, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To locate all entities in the HPLMN", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Network Broadcast Geographic Area Coverage Management? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide privacy and non-identification of users outside of the MNO\n2) To restrict the reception of Subscribed TV services based on subscriber groups\n3) To ensure quality of experience for the TV service throughout the coverage area\n4) To support network capacity assignment for TV services\n5) To enable the MNO to authenticate subscribers before providing TV transport services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3251, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To ensure quality of experience for the TV service throughout the coverage area", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can UE power saving be enabled by relaxing measurements for RLM/BFD? \n\nOptions:\n1) By reducing PDCCH monitoring in connected mode\n2) By reducing UE power consumption during synchronization\n3) By reducing UE power consumption during idle/inactive mode\n4) By reducing UE power consumption during RAR/MsgB window monitoring\n5) By reducing UE power consumption during data scheduling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3256, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By reducing UE power consumption during idle/inactive mode", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does SN-DU indicate in the UE CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE message if SCG activation is requested? \n\nOptions:\n1) SCG deactivated\n2) SCG activated\n3) UE scheduling stopped\n4) UE context released\n5) Source cell group configuration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3259, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  SCG activated", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the definition of OTA Adjacent Channel Leakage Power Ratio (ACLR)? \n\nOptions:\n1) The measure of the difference between the actual SAN transmit frequency and the assigned frequency.\n2) The difference between the power of an RE and the average RE power for a SAN at maximum output power.\n3) The difference between the maximum and the minimum transmit power of an OFDM symbol for a specified reference condition.\n4) The ratio of the filtered mean power centered on the assigned channel frequency to the filtered mean power centered on an adjacent channel frequency.\n5) The difference between the DL RS power indicated on the DL-SCH and the DL RS power of each E-UTRA carrier within the OTA coverage range.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3265, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The ratio of the filtered mean power centered on the assigned channel frequency to the filtered mean power centered on an adjacent channel frequency.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich flow directions should have configurable absolute cyclic time boundaries for infrastructure dedicated to high performance Ethernet applications? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) DL direction only\n2) UL direction only\n3) DL and UL directions\n4) IEEE 802.1Qbv\n5) Routing based on Ethernet header information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3270, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  DL and UL directions", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat should happen to the traffic on a cell in energy saving state? \n\nOptions:\n1) It should be drained to other cells before the cell moves to energySaving state\n2) It should be doubled to increase coverage\n3) It should be terminated to create a coverage hole\n4) It should be redirected to a different frequency band\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3271, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  It should be drained to other cells before the cell moves to energySaving state", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat services can modify the originating network's caller identity information? \n\nOptions:\n1) IMS Multimedia Telephony service\n2) OIP service and eCNAM service\n3) Additional timing information services\n4) User configuration services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3273, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  OIP service and eCNAM service", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of CC5 in the 3GPP release 14? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support extended access burst formats\n2) To improve coverage in downlink traffic channels\n3) To increase the number of bits for channel estimation\n4) To increase the number of physical layer transmissions\n5) To improve coverage in uplink traffic channels\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3281, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To improve coverage in uplink traffic channels", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich feature enhances the granularity of RSTD reporting? \n\nOptions:\n1) OTDOA enhancements in shared physical cell identity scenario\n2) PRS based Beacon\n3) PRS plus CRS measurement for OTDOA\n4) Multipath Time of Arrival (ToA)\n5) Reduced quantization error\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3284, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Reduced quantization error", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the IM-GSN in a GLR-equipped VPLMN? \n\nOptions:\n1) To handle location management of roaming subscribers\n2) To relay messages between home network and serving MSC\n3) To handle GTP signalling messages\n4) To optimize signalling traffic between PLMNs\n5) To provide IMS services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3294, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To handle GTP signalling messages", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the impact of mobility between a 5G core network and an EPC (4G) on the user experience? \n\nOptions:\n1) Significant impact on the user experience\n2) No impact on the user experience\n3) Minimal impact on the user experience\n4) Negative impact on the user experience\n5) Neutral impact on the user experience\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3297, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Minimal impact on the user experience", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specification defines Lawful Interception functionality? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 22.261\n2) TS 23.401\n3) TS 24.501\n4) TS 33.126\n5) TS 38.300\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3309, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  TS 33.126", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can the lists of 3GPP PS Data Off Exempt Services be provided to the UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through PCO during the inter-RAT mobility.\n2) Through HPLMN via Device Management or UICC provisioning.\n3) Through the ATSSS feature.\n4) Through a specific standard defined in TS\u00a023.503.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3312, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Through HPLMN via Device Management or UICC provisioning.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn addition to 5G-based Ethernet links, what other ethernet transports should the 3GPP system support clock synchronization for high performance Ethernet applications? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Coexistence of hard-RT and lower priority traffic\n2) Time-sensitive networking defined by IEEE 802.1Q\n3) IEEE 802.1AS\n4) Wired and optical (EPON)\n5) Routing based on Ethernet header information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3316, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Wired and optical (EPON)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the NotificationMessageSidelink message? \n\nOptions:\n1) To request UE sidelink capabilities\n2) To include the system information transmitted by a UE via SL-BCH\n3) To indicate the failure of a PC5 RRC AS reconfiguration\n4) To include sidelink DRX assistance information used to determine the sidelink DRX configuration\n5) To send notification message from U2N Relay UE to the connected U2N Remote UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3318, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To send notification message from U2N Relay UE to the connected U2N Remote UE", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does a UE determine the number of repetitions and MCS for a PUSCH transmission scheduled by a RAR UL grant? \n\nOptions:\n1) By the number of RBs in the initial UL BWP\n2) By the SCS for the PUSCH transmission\n3) By the MCS field in the RAR UL grant\n4) By the PUSCH repetition type\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3319, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By the MCS field in the RAR UL grant", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Nmfaf_3caDataManagement_Fetch service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To configure the MFAF to map data or analytics received by the MFAF to out-bound notification endpoints\n2) To configure the MFAF to stop mapping data or analytics received by the MFAF to out-bound notification endpoints\n3) To supply data or analytics from the MFAF to notification endpoints\n4) To fetch data or analytics from the MFAF based on fetch instructions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3336, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To fetch data or analytics from the MFAF based on fetch instructions", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which case is the HARQ-ACK message transmitted on PUCCH? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the first uplink symbol of the PUCCH starts no earlier than at symbol L1\n2) When the PUCCH resource is overlapping with another PUCCH or PUSCH resource\n3) When the UE is configured with multiple active component carriers\n4) When the PDSCH DM-RS position for the additional DM-RS is 0\n5) When the uplink switching gap is triggered for the PUCCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3342, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  When the PUCCH resource is overlapping with another PUCCH or PUSCH resource", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does TsteeringWLAN represent? \n\nOptions:\n1) The timer value during which the rules should be fulfilled for traffic steering between E-UTRAN and WLAN.\n2) The RSRP threshold for traffic steering from WLAN to E-UTRAN.\n3) The WLAN channel utilization threshold used by the UE for traffic steering.\n4) The WLAN RSSI threshold used by the UE for traffic steering from WLAN to E-UTRAN.\n5) The backhaul available uplink bandwidth threshold used by the UE for traffic steering from E-UTRAN to WLAN.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3349, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The timer value during which the rules should be fulfilled for traffic steering between E-UTRAN and WLAN.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the UE determine the p0-PUCCH-Value value if it is not provided any of pdsch-HARQ-ACK-Codebook? \n\nOptions:\n1) From the pathlossReferenceRSs value\n2) From the pucch-PathlossReferenceRS-Id value\n3) From the p0-Set value\n4) From the pucch-PowerControl value\n5) From the p0-nominal value\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3352, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  From the p0-Set value", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does TSC stand for in the context of integration with IEEE TSN? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transport Service Capability\n2) Traffic Support Coordination\n3) Time-Synchronized Control\n4) Time-Sensitive Communication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3358, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Time-Sensitive Communication", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nDoes a UE support a secure mechanism for the home operator to disallow selection of one or more of its radio technologies, regardless of PLMNs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes\n2) No\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3367, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Yes", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nUnder high network load conditions, how does the network protect itself? \n\nOptions:\n1) By restricting access attempts from UEs\n2) By increasing resource allocation\n3) By encrypting all data traffic\n4) By prioritizing certain services\n5) By disabling identification and authentication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3377, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  By restricting access attempts from UEs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are charges for roaming traffic settled between operators? \n\nOptions:\n1) By means of the GSM Association's Transferred Account Procedure (TAP)\n2) Through credit pooling and balance management\n3) Based on the charges calculated for home subscribers\n4) By exchanging TAP records with each HPLMN\n5) By performing bulk settlement with fixed network operators\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3385, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  By means of the GSM Association's Transferred Account Procedure (TAP)", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the NWDAF collect input information for PDU Session traffic analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) By querying the SMF for input data.\n2) By querying the UPF for input data.\n3) By subscribing to UPF event exposure and collecting data indirectly via the SMF or directly from the UPF.\n4) By monitoring the location of UEs where PDU Session traffic is analyzed.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3387, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By subscribing to UPF event exposure and collecting data indirectly via the SMF or directly from the UPF.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the N2 interface in 5G-AN and 5G Core? \n\nOptions:\n1) To manage the N2 interface configuration\n2) To manage NAS transport procedures\n3) To manage resources for PDU Sessions\n4) To manage handover procedures\n5) To manage the connection of multiple types of 5G-AN to the 5GC\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3388, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To manage the connection of multiple types of 5G-AN to the 5GC", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich power saving scheme can potentially reduce the UE power consumption by reducing the number of PDCCH blind decoding? \n\nOptions:\n1) Triggering of PDCCH monitoring\n2) PDCCH skipping\n3) Go-to-sleep signaling\n4) Dynamic DRX configuration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3389, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  PDCCH skipping", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the NWDAF provide new analytics to the NF in continuous reporting? \n\nOptions:\n1) By invoking OAM or NRF or UE Input data notification\n2) By using Nnrf_NFManagement_NFStatusNotify service operation\n3) By invoking Nnef_EventExposure_Subscribe or Naf_EventExposure_Subscribe service\n4) By providing the Validity Period\n5) By generating new analytics periodically\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3391, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  By invoking OAM or NRF or UE Input data notification", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the optional inputs for the Nadrf_DataManagement_StorageRequest service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Formatting Instructions, Processing Instructions, DataSetTag, Data Deletion Notification Endpoint\n2) Formatting Instructions, Processing Instructions, DataSetTag, Storage Handling Information\n3) DataSetTag, DSC information, Data Deletion Notification Endpoint\n4) DataSetTag, Storage Handling Information, Data Deletion Notification Endpoint\n5) DataSetTag, DSC information, Storage Handling Information, Data Deletion Notification Endpoint\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3392, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  DataSetTag, DSC information, Storage Handling Information, Data Deletion Notification Endpoint", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens if non-SDT data appears in a buffer during the SDT procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE stops the SDT procedure and transitions to RRC_IDLE state.\n2) The UE initiates a transmission of a non-SDT data arrival indication to the network.\n3) The UE continues with the SDT procedure and ignores the non-SDT data.\n4) The UE transitions to RRC_CONNECTED state.\n5) The UE transitions to RRC_RELEASE state.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3397, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The UE initiates a transmission of a non-SDT data arrival indication to the network.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich service areas are considered for eMBB deployments in 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) Outdoor and indoor areas\n2) Urban and rural areas\n3) Office and home areas\n4) Local and wide areas connectivity\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3399, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the interfering signal for the in-channel selectivity requirement? \n\nOptions:\n1) An AWGN signal\n2) A CW signal\n3) An E-UTRA signal\n4) An interfering signal with a positive offset\n5) An interfering signal with a negative offset\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3405, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  An E-UTRA signal", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specifications describe the access technologies offered by the BSS? \n\nOptions:\n1) 36-series\n2) 25-series\n3) 45-series\n4) 48-series\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3409, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  45-series", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of a flexible and dynamic allocation of radio resources between unicast and multicast services within the network? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable efficient delivery of real-time and streaming multicast/broadcast content over wide geographic areas.\n2) To enable efficient delivery of voice, data, and video group communication.\n3) To enable efficient delivery of UHD streaming video.\n4) To enable efficient delivery of the same UE-originated data in a resource-efficient manner.\n5) To enable efficient delivery of broadcast/multicast via a 5G satellite access network.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3416, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable efficient delivery of real-time and streaming multicast/broadcast content over wide geographic areas.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the definition of Radiated transmit power? \n\nOptions:\n1) The maximum power that the SAN is declared to radiate during the transmitter ON period.\n2) The difference between the power of an RE and the average RE power for a SAN at maximum output power.\n3) The difference between the maximum and the minimum transmit power of an OFDM symbol for a specified reference condition.\n4) The measure of the difference between the actual SAN transmit frequency and the assigned frequency.\n5) The ratio of the filtered mean power centered on the assigned channel frequency to the filtered mean power centered on an adjacent channel frequency.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3427, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The maximum power that the SAN is declared to radiate during the transmitter ON period.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the LTE Measurement Gap Enhancement work item specify? \n\nOptions:\n1) LTE measurement gap configurations with shorter measurement gap length (MGL=3ms).\n2) LTE measurement gap configurations with longer measurement gap length (MGL=5ms).\n3) LTE measurement gap configurations with variable measurement gap length.\n4) LTE measurement gap configurations with fixed measurement gap length (MGL=1ms).\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3428, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  LTE measurement gap configurations with shorter measurement gap length (MGL=3ms).", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow should users be able to obtain service and use chargeable services with networks they have no direct commercial agreement with? \n\nOptions:\n1) By interworking directly with the serving network operators.\n2) By negotiating commercial roaming agreements with serving network operators.\n3) By using a trusted third party for interworking with serving network operators.\n4) By routing registration requests through the home environment.\n5) By using fraud and cost control mechanisms to ensure charges do not exceed credit limits.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3430, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By using a trusted third party for interworking with serving network operators.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the demodulation enhancement feature in LTE enable the UE to do? \n\nOptions:\n1) Increase the number of SFNs that can be handled by the UE\n2) Handle the Doppler shift issue in SFN scenario caused by opposite Doppler shifts associated with separate paths on the UE\n3) Improve the demodulation performance under 350km/h and 30km/h in SFN scenario\n4) Reduce the impact of opposite Doppler shifts on the UE demodulation under high speed\n5) No improvements were made to UE demodulation in LTE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3434, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Handle the Doppler shift issue in SFN scenario caused by opposite Doppler shifts associated with separate paths on the UE", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich evaluation method is considered as the baseline? \n\nOptions:\n1) Numerical analysis\n2) SLS (Symbol Level Simulation)\n3) LLS (Link Level Simulation)\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3439, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  SLS (Symbol Level Simulation)", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the New GPRS algorithms for EASE? \n\nOptions:\n1) To introduce new algorithms for cyphering and integrity protection of GSM CIoT data\n2) To optimize the RRC for UMTS\n3) To enhance positioning capabilities in GERAN\n4) To improve UPH reporting in UMTS\n5) To enable simultaneous RAB/RB setup and release in UMTS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3442, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To introduce new algorithms for cyphering and integrity protection of GSM CIoT data", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the typical height at which the BSs are mounted in the indoor scenario? \n\nOptions:\n1) 10m\n2) 25m\n3) 2-3m\n4) 1.5-2.5m\n5) 3m\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3447, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  2-3m", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when the BWP inactivity timer expires? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE goes back to sleep\n2) The UE switches to the default BWP\n3) The UE starts the inactivity timer\n4) The UE restarts PDCCH decoding\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3450, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The UE switches to the default BWP", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Wake-up signalling feature in NB-IoT? \n\nOptions:\n1) To instruct the UE to regularly check for paging messages\n2) To reduce UE power consumption by allowing the UE to skip paging procedures\n3) To enhance the Rel-13/14 NB-IoT air interface and protocol layers\n4) To support small cells and extensions to NB-IoT standalone operation mode\n5) To increase the accuracy of narrowband measurement\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3451, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To reduce UE power consumption by allowing the UE to skip paging procedures", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information does IEAF need to determine the S-NSSAI for the AIML Application Service Provider? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE IP address\n2) Analytics ID\n3) Application ID\n4) DNN\n5) Network consent\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3459, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Application ID", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of CDRs in offline charging? \n\nOptions:\n1) To reserve credit from the subscriber account\n2) To furnish charging information to the OCS/CCS for Credit-Control\n3) To determine the amount of resources a user will consume\n4) To supervise the actual network resource consumption\n5) To transform charging information into CDRs for generating bills\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3465, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To transform charging information into CDRs for generating bills", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the granularity of the 5GS TSN bridge? \n\nOptions:\n1) Per UPF\n2) Per UE\n3) Per TSN network\n4) Per TSN AF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3466, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Per UPF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following physical signals are used by the physical layer but do not carry information originating from higher layers? \n\nOptions:\n1) Phase-tracking reference signals (PT-RS)\n2) Channel-state information reference signals (CSI-RS)\n3) Demodulation reference signals (DM-RS)\n4) Sidelink primary synchronization signal (S-PSS)\n5) Sidelink secondary synchronization signal (S-SSS)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3473, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Demodulation reference signals (DM-RS)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich protocol stack is used for the S5 interface? \n\nOptions:\n1) S1AP protocol stack\n2) X2AP protocol stack\n3) SGi protocol stack\n4) S5 protocol stack\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3474, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  None of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the common charging architecture provide? \n\nOptions:\n1) Physical mapping of charging functions\n2) Logical view of charging functions\n3) Actual implementation of charging functions\n4) Detailed specifications for charging functions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3480, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Logical view of charging functions", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich bearer option supports the SeNB being directly connected with the S-GW via S1-U? \n\nOptions:\n1) MCG bearer\n2) SCG bearer\n3) Split bearer\n4) Primary bearer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3483, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  SCG bearer", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of scenarios can be applied in the map-based hybrid model? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only LOS scenarios\n2) Only NLOS scenarios\n3) Both LOS and NLOS scenarios\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3484, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both LOS and NLOS scenarios", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the work item 5G_HYPOS? \n\nOptions:\n1) To specify functional requirements and KPIs for enhanced positioning services in 5G systems\n2) To define the service-based architecture and procedures for location services in the 5G system\n3) To support accurate UE positioning in NR technology by utilizing RAT-dependent and RAT-independent solutions\n4) To specify the framework for NR based positioning of UEs\n5) To enable enhanced and more accurate positioning in 5G systems\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3488, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To specify functional requirements and KPIs for enhanced positioning services in 5G systems", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is the Connection Resume procedure used by a UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the UE is in CM-CONNECTED with RRC_INACTIVE state and upper layers or the AS requests the resumption of a suspended RRC connection\n2) When the UE is in CM-IDLE with Suspend and user data transmission is required\n3) When the UE is disconnected from the network and needs to establish a secure connection\n4) When the UE is in CM-CONNECTED with RRC_CONNECTED state and the AMF requests the resumption of a secure connection\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3519, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  When the UE is in CM-CONNECTED with RRC_INACTIVE state and upper layers or the AS requests the resumption of a suspended RRC connection", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information triggers the activation or deactivation of access stratum time distribution for a UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Start and stop times\n2) Clock quality detail level\n3) Coverage area information\n4) Uu time synchronization error budget\n5) UE reconnection indication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3527, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Coverage area information", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the ground truth data represent? \n\nOptions:\n1) Predictions generated based on a ML model\n2) Actual measured data observed at the time of prediction\n3) Analytics accuracy using multiple ML models\n4) Analytics output triggered by the ML model\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3530, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Actual measured data observed at the time of prediction", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does CFI stand for? \n\nOptions:\n1) Carrier Frequency Indicator\n2) Control Format Indicator\n3) Channel Frame Initialization\n4) Converged Frequency Indicator\n5) Codebook Feedback Indicator\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3531, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Control Format Indicator", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of segmentation of RRC messages? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support sidelink communication\n2) To improve the reliability of NAS message delivery\n3) To enable inter-frequency handovers\n4) To reduce the size of encoded RRC messages\n5) To allow efficient resource allocation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3543, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To reduce the size of encoded RRC messages", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is the SN Modification Confirm message sent to the MN? \n\nOptions:\n1) After the SCG is activated or deactivated\n2) After the UE context is released\n3) After the SN Modification Request message\n4) After the BEARER CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE message\n5) After the UE context setup\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3547, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  After the SCG is activated or deactivated", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich methodology was selected as the reference methodology for MIMO OTA testing in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Multi-probe anechoic chamber (MPAC)\n2) Radiated two-stage (RTS)\n3) Radiated performance requirements (RPR)\n4) MPAC and RTS combined\n5) Semi-anechoic chamber (SAC)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3552, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Multi-probe anechoic chamber (MPAC)", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the SNR used for simulation of REFSENS? \n\nOptions:\n1) -82.8 dBm/50 MHz\n2) 0.7 dB\n3) 6 dB\n4) -1 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3553, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  -1 dB", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich protocol(s) crossing the Rf reference point should support real-time transactions? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reliability mechanisms\n2) Statefull mode\n3) Stateless mode\n4) Retransmission of charging events\n5) Changeover to secondary destination\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3558, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Stateless mode", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the definition of a resource unit for multi-tone NPUSCH with UL-SCH transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) A single 3.75kHz sub-carrier for 8ms\n2) A single 15kHz sub-carrier for 2ms\n3) 3 sub-carriers for 4ms\n4) 6 sub-carriers for 2ms\n5) 12 sub-carriers for 1ms\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3559, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  3 sub-carriers for 4ms", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many radio frame structures are supported for downlink and uplink transmissions? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1\n2) 2\n3) 3\n4) 4\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3560, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  3", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIf a location request fails due to barring, what happens? \n\nOptions:\n1) The request is postponed\n2) An error cause is returned to the LCS Requestor\n3) A notification is sent to the target UE\n4) The request is cancelled\n5) The request is forwarded to the PLMN operator\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3562, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  An error cause is returned to the LCS Requestor", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are charges paid to the adjacent party in the settlement of charges? \n\nOptions:\n1) Each party determines the lowest cost to the end user.\n2) Each party authorizes charges up to a maximum credit limit with the adjacent party.\n3) Each party negotiates commercial roaming agreements with the adjacent party.\n4) Each party routes subscription identity back to its Home Environment.\n5) Funds are passed between each party for the services supplied by the network operator in a serial fashion.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3569, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Funds are passed between each party for the services supplied by the network operator in a serial fashion.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the duration of radio frame structure type 1? \n\nOptions:\n1) 5ms\n2) 10ms\n3) 20ms\n4) 0.5ms\n5) 1ms\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3570, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  10ms", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich SAN classes are defined for SAN type 1-O and SAN type 1-H? \n\nOptions:\n1) LEO and GEO\n2) Transceiver unit array and composite antenna\n3) RIB and RDN\n4) Conducted and radiated reference points\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3571, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  LEO and GEO", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the 5G LAN VN group service charging specify? \n\nOptions:\n1) Charging architecture and principles for LAN-type services\n2) Charging management for 5G data connectivity domain\n3) Charging support for 5G Virtual Network group management\n4) Charging of management services for UEs in a specified area\n5) Charging data record parameter description for LAN VN group service\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3572, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Charging support for 5G Virtual Network group management", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does determinism refer to in communication? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) The stability of the delay between transmission and receipt of messages\n2) The periodicity of communication intervals\n3) The time-criticality of communication\n4) The availability of communication services\n5) The bounded variation of transmission intervals\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3579, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The stability of the delay between transmission and receipt of messages", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich services have high priority for support at the II-NNI? \n\nOptions:\n1) Basic Voice\n2) Originating Identification Presentation (OIP)\n3) Malicious Communication Identification (MCID)\n4) Communication Waiting (CW)\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3584, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NWDAF notify in the procedure of providing PDU Session traffic analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) PCF\n2) URSP\n3) UPF\n4) SMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3585, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  URSP", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich documents specify the information to be pre-configured or stored in USIM for Disaster Roaming service? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 31.102 and TS 31.111\n2) TS 22.261 and TS 23.502\n3) TS 38.304 and TS 38.331\n4) TS 33.501 and TS 29.509\n5) TS 29.503 and TS 31.102\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3586, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  TS 31.102 and TS 31.111", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the behavior of a half-duplex UE (HD-UE) in paired spectrum with regards to simultaneous transmissions and receptions? \n\nOptions:\n1) It supports simultaneous transmissions and receptions on a serving cell\n2) It supports simultaneous transmissions and receptions on all cells\n3) It does not support simultaneous transmissions and receptions on a serving cell\n4) It does not support simultaneous transmissions and receptions on any cell\n5) It supports simultaneous transmissions and receptions on unpaired spectrum cells but not on paired spectrum cells\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3591, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  It does not support simultaneous transmissions and receptions on a serving cell", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the duration of a frame? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1 ms\n2) 5 ms\n3) 10 ms\n4) 14 ms\n5) 20 ms\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3597, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  10 ms", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information does a consumer of NWDAF analytics need to indicate in the request or subscription? \n\nOptions:\n1) Area of Interest\n2) List of NF types\n3) Load Level Threshold value\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3604, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the relative increase in free space path loss from 43.5 GHz to 71 GHz? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.33 dB\n2) 0.9 dB\n3) 3.5 dB\n4) 7.7 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3605, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  7.7 dB", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat architecture is primarily used for MC service UE to obtain access to a MC service? \n\nOptions:\n1) IMS architecture\n2) EPS architecture\n3) ProSe architecture\n4) MC_ARCH architecture\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3607, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  EPS architecture", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich enhancement is applicable to 'on-network' operation in MCPTT service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ambient listening call\n2) Updating the selected MC service user profile\n3) KMS (Key Management Server) URI for security domain\n4) V2X communication over PC5 interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3608, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Ambient listening call", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information shall be provided to the LCS client? \n\nOptions:\n1) Originating party's serving cell id\n2) Diverse positioning techniques\n3) Quality of service parameters\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3615, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Originating party's serving cell id", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the different types of EE KPIs in telecommunication networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) Whole networks\n2) Sub-networks\n3) Single network elements\n4) Telecommunication sites\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3628, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat release cause is indicated when the UE fails the mobility from NR procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) 'Handover failure'\n2) 'RRC connection release'\n3) 'RRC connection failure'\n4) 'Mobility failure'\n5) 'Other'\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3630, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  'RRC connection failure'", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of allocating UEs into different Access Classes? \n\nOptions:\n1) To differentiate between CS and PS domains\n2) To determine the home and visited PLMNs\n3) To bar UEs from network access\n4) To specify the categories of subscribers who are barred from network access\n5) To assign specific priorities to UEs based on their special categories\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3634, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To assign specific priorities to UEs based on their special categories", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the measure of power for DL RS power? \n\nOptions:\n1) Resource element power of the Downlink Reference Symbol\n2) Received Signal Strength Indicator (RSSI)\n3) Carrier-to-Interference plus Noise Ratio (CINR)\n4) Absolute accuracy deviation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3642, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Resource element power of the Downlink Reference Symbol", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UPF do in response to the N4 Session Establishment request from the SMF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Updates the N4 session context at the SMF\n2) Creates a new N4 session context for the PDU Session\n3) Sends an N4 session establishment response to the SMF\n4) Removes the N4 session context at the SMF\n5) Modifies the N4 session context at the SMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3649, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Creates a new N4 session context for the PDU Session", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens if an SeNB change is performed within the coverage area of the MeNB towards another hybrid HeNB with the same CSG ID? \n\nOptions:\n1) The MeNB performs another membership verification\n2) The MeNB re-uses the result of the membership verification performed for the first HeNB\n3) The MeNB releases all radio and control plane resources\n4) The MeNB initiates the SeNB Modification Preparation procedure\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3651, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The MeNB re-uses the result of the membership verification performed for the first HeNB", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UE generate as HARQ-ACK information when it correctly decodes a transport block? \n\nOptions:\n1) CRC value\n2) NACK value\n3) ACK value\n4) ID value\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3657, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  ACK value", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of cyber-physical control applications in vertical domains? \n\nOptions:\n1) To control physical processes over a network\n2) To facilitate communication for V2X applications\n3) To provide network and application enablement for verticals\n4) To enhance the location and positioning capabilities in the 5G system\n5) To enable third party Application Servers/Functions to access 3GPP network services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3664, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To control physical processes over a network", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of intra-level correlation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To include IOI identities within SIP signalling.\n2) To combine charging events belonging to the same service generated by different CTFs.\n3) To uniquely identify each operator for inter operator accounting purposes.\n4) To enable operators involved in IMS sessions to identify each other.\n5) To aggregate charging events belonging to the same charging session over a time period.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3673, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To aggregate charging events belonging to the same charging session over a time period.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is QoE measurement collection activated? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through direct configuration from the OAM system\n2) Through signalling from the OAM via the 5GC\n3) Both option 1 and option 2\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3679, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both option 1 and option 2", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NEF check before performing a PFD management request? \n\nOptions:\n1) Authentication status of the AF\n2) Authorization status of the NEF\n3) Provisioning status of the PFD data\n4) Authorization status of the AF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3688, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Authorization status of the AF", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the requirement for interruption time during handover of RT and NRT services in the Evolved Packet System? \n\nOptions:\n1) No interruption time allowed\n2) Minimum interruption time as defined in TR 25.913\n3) Maximum interruption time of 30 ms\n4) Maximum interruption time of 1 ms\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3693, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Minimum interruption time as defined in TR 25.913", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat UL BWP does a RedCap UE expect if its maximum UL BWP is smaller than the UL BWP indicated in UplinkConfigCommonSIB? \n\nOptions:\n1) The maximum UL BWP supported by the UE\n2) The initial UL BWP\n3) The UL BWP indicated in initialUplinkBWP-RedCap\n4) The UL BWP indicated in initialUplinkBWP\n5) The UL BWP indicated in initialUplinkBWP-RedCap or initialUplinkBWP\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3697, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The UL BWP indicated in initialUplinkBWP-RedCap", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat message does the gNB-CU send to the AMF after receiving the UE CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST message? \n\nOptions:\n1) INITIAL CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST\n2) INITIAL UE MESSAGE\n3) UE CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST\n4) INITIAL CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE\n5) DL RRC MESSAGE TRANSFER\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3701, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  INITIAL CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many DL HARQ processes are introduced for UEs supporting full-duplex FDD operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) 6\n2) 8\n3) 10\n4) 12\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3722, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  10", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does PDCP packet duplication allow in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Duplicating the transport blocks for uplink transmission\n2) Sending the same PDCP Protocol Data Unit (PDU) on two independent transmission paths\n3) Reordering the received packets on the receiving side\n4) Ensuring synchronization between multiple devices\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3726, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Sending the same PDCP Protocol Data Unit (PDU) on two independent transmission paths", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat codec should be preferred over a narrowband codec during codec negotiation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Opus\n2) G.711\n3) AMR\n4) G.729\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3727, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Opus", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the capacity of Cell-ID in an eNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1.04 million\n2) 2.04 million\n3) 1024\n4) 256\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3740, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  256", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat triggers AF-requested Edge Relocation? \n\nOptions:\n1) EAS load balance\n2) Maintenance of EAS\n3) Both EAS load balance and maintenance of EAS\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3742, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both EAS load balance and maintenance of EAS", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of fraud and cost control mechanisms in the context of roaming agreements? \n\nOptions:\n1) To negotiate commercial roaming agreements with serving network operators.\n2) To ensure that charges incurred for 3GPP services do not exceed the credit limits set.\n3) To route subscription identity back to its Home Environment.\n4) To determine the lowest cost route to reach a given Home Environment.\n5) To settle charges on a wholesale basis between the different parties involved in the registration link.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3744, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To ensure that charges incurred for 3GPP services do not exceed the credit limits set.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can a UE be indicated to transmit a PSFCH with HARQ-ACK information? \n\nOptions:\n1) By an SCI format indicating resource pool enabling\n2) By an SCI format scheduling a PSCCH transmission\n3) By an SCI format indicating resource pool disabling\n4) By an SCI format scheduling a PSSCH reception\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3751, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  By an SCI format scheduling a PSSCH reception", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere are the security aspects on the UE authentication during the authentication procedure specified? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 29.509\n2) TS 31.111\n3) TS 33.501\n4) TS 22.011\n5) TS 23.122\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3761, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS 33.501", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the carrier frequency designated in the uplink and downlink? \n\nOptions:\n1) Channel raster\n2) E-UTRA Absolute Radio Frequency Channel Number (EARFCN)\n3) Channel spacing\n4) Nominal channel spacing\n5) Channel bandwidth\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3766, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  E-UTRA Absolute Radio Frequency Channel Number (EARFCN)", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the minimum cell throughput capacity required on DL in the 5G system? \n\nOptions:\n1) 10 Mbit/s/cell\n2) 100 Mbit/s/cell\n3) 1 Gbit/s/cell\n4) 10 Gbit/s/cell\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3783, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  10 Mbit/s/cell", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat modulation schemes are used for the downlink physical-layer processing? \n\nOptions:\n1) QPSK, 16QAM, 64QAM, 256QAM, 1024QAM\n2) BPSK, QPSK, 16QAM, 64QAM\n3) QPSK, 64QAM, 256QAM\n4) QPSK, 16QAM, 64QAM\n5) QPSK, 16QAM, 256QAM\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3785, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  QPSK, 16QAM, 64QAM, 256QAM, 1024QAM", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Work Item 'Enhancement of Private Network support for NG-RAN'? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support non-public and private networks\n2) To enhance the location and positioning capabilities in the 5G system\n3) To improve the efficiency of Northbound Interfaces and APIs\n4) To improve the support for non-public networks\n5) To support IMS voice and emergency services for SNPN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3787, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To support IMS voice and emergency services for SNPN", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main purpose of the 5G system in supporting cyber-physical control applications using wireless indirect network connection? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) To support multicast communication between UEs in a group\n2) To provide service to out-of-coverage UEs using relay UEs\n3) To ensure clock synchronization for UEs using indirect network connection\n4) To minimize service disruption for UEs moving between networks\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3788, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To provide service to out-of-coverage UEs using relay UEs", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen a UE performs simultaneous SL and UL transmissions, which link has higher priority? \n\nOptions:\n1) Depends on the SCI formats scheduling the transmissions\n2) SL link\n3) Depends on the priority values of the transmissions\n4) UL link\n5) Depends on the power allocated for each link\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3793, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  UL link", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identity is used to control the power of SRS? \n\nOptions:\n1) SFI-RNTI\n2) TPC-PUCCH-RNTI\n3) TPC-PUSCH-RNTI\n4) TPC-SRS-RNTI\n5) RA-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3794, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  TPC-SRS-RNTI", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of redundant transmission for high reliability communication in URLLC? \n\nOptions:\n1) To establish two independent user plane paths for increased reliability.\n2) To support dual connectivity between the UE and the SMF.\n3) To ensure time-sensitive networking for URLLC services.\n4) To provide redundancy in the RAN and UPF deployment.\n5) To guarantee the physical network topology and function distribution support.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3806, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To establish two independent user plane paths for increased reliability.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich field is ignored by UEs supporting crs-IntfMitig while crs-IntfMitigEnabled is included in SIB1? \n\nOptions:\n1) cellBarred-5GC\n2) cellReservedForOperatorUse\n3) cellBarred-CRS\n4) cellBarred\n5) cellReservedForOperatorUse-CRS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3813, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  cellBarred", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the high-speed interface between the UICC and the ME? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide security features\n2) To host multiple applications\n3) To address applications via the radio interface\n4) To allow fast access and retrieval of data from the UICC\n5) To update UICC-specific information via the radio interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3816, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To allow fast access and retrieval of data from the UICC", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the physical layer interface in the LTE radio interface protocol architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) MAC sub-layer of Layer 2\n2) RLC sub-layer of Layer 2\n3) RRC Layer of Layer 3\n4) PDCCH\n5) PHICH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3819, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  MAC sub-layer of Layer 2", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a UE configured for operation in bandwidth parts (BWPs) receive from higher layers? \n\nOptions:\n1) Frequency domain resource allocation\n2) Scheduling cell information\n3) Parameter configurations for DL and UL BWPs\n4) PDCCH and PDSCH transmissions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3822, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Parameter configurations for DL and UL BWPs", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the function of the DeNB in the architecture supporting RNs? \n\nOptions:\n1) To wirelessly connect to the RN\n2) To terminate the radio protocols of the E-UTRA radio interface\n3) To provide S1 and X2 proxy functionality between the RN and other network nodes\n4) To support PWS towards UEs\n5) To configure and reconfigure the RN subframe configuration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3825, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To provide S1 and X2 proxy functionality between the RN and other network nodes", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich physical channels are defined in the downlink? \n\nOptions:\n1) PDSCH, PUCCH, PHICH\n2) PBCH, PDCCH, PUSCH\n3) PDSCH, PMCH, PBCH\n4) PRACH, PDCCH, PUSCH\n5) PCFICH, PHICH, PBCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3828, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  PDSCH, PMCH, PBCH", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the I-SMF Context Transfer procedure involve? \n\nOptions:\n1) Sending a transfer indication from AMF to New SMF\n2) Triggering a new service transaction\n3) Resuming a new service transaction\n4) Selecting the I-SMF from the indicated SMF set\n5) Sending a transfer indication from the Old I-SMF to AMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3836, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Sending a transfer indication from the Old I-SMF to AMF", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of providing an ID in NAS signalling that represents a UE's radio capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) To assign UE capabilities by the manufacturer\n2) To reduce signalling overhead\n3) To store UE Radio Capabilities in the AMF\n4) To request UE capabilities for NR, EUTRA, UTRA-FDD\n5) To support intra-band non-contiguous CA\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3837, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To reduce signalling overhead", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the three typical traffic classes or communication patterns in industrial environments? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Deterministic periodic communication, deterministic aperiodic communication, and non-deterministic communication\n2) Mixed traffic, event-driven actions, and logging information\n3) Deterministic periodic communication, non-deterministic communication, and mixed traffic\n4) Event-driven actions, periodic non-real time traffic, and aperiodic non-real time traffic\n5) Reliable communication, available communication, and maintainable communication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3841, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Deterministic periodic communication, deterministic aperiodic communication, and non-deterministic communication", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the indication for a restriction on emergency calls? \n\nOptions:\n1) ac-EmergencyCallRestriction\n2) ac-RestrictionForEmergency\n3) ac-AccessForEmergency\n4) ac-CallRestrictionForEmergency\n5) ac-BarringForEmergency\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3844, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  ac-BarringForEmergency", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the EEC Context ID? \n\nOptions:\n1) To identify an EEC\n2) To identify an EES\n3) To identify a specific application\n4) To identify a group of UE\n5) To identify a set of parameters associated with an EEC\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3845, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To identify a set of parameters associated with an EEC", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the feature 'Enhanced status (on-network)' enable for the MCData service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Temporary storage of data communications\n2) Real-time updates of changes to group dynamic data\n3) Sharing the current MCData system defined status\n4) Sending an application level message to MCData clients\n5) Extending the MCData application identifier\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3846, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Sharing the current MCData system defined status", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat basic requirements are supported for MMS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Real-time character by character text conversation\n2) Store-and-forward multimedia messaging service\n3) Automatic device detection\n4) IP multimedia session control\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3847, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Store-and-forward multimedia messaging service", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of EAS Relocation on Release 16 capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable roaming PDU Sessions\n2) To provide low packet loss in the network\n3) To support Edge Relocation involving AF change\n4) To describe example procedures for EAS Relocation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3853, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To describe example procedures for EAS Relocation", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the UE report a change in its 3GPP PS Data Off status? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through the ATSSS Control procedure.\n2) Through the non-Allowed Area reporting procedure.\n3) Through the UE requested PDU Session Modification procedure.\n4) Through the IMS domain enforcement procedure.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3854, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Through the UE requested PDU Session Modification procedure.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich sublayer is responsible for routing and next-hop determination on the backhaul link? \n\nOptions:\n1) MAC sublayer\n2) RLC sublayer\n3) PDCP sublayer\n4) BAP sublayer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3857, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  BAP sublayer", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the enhancements in the feature VoIMS via Trusted and Untrusted WLAN access? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable QoS differentiation and better user experience\n2) To extend the reach of ProSe Direct Discovery\n3) To enforce operator policy on the use of unlicensed spectrum\n4) To enhance LTE operation in unlicensed spectrum\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3871, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable QoS differentiation and better user experience", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the NWDAF with accuracy checking capability decide to initiate analytics accuracy monitoring? \n\nOptions:\n1) Based on a request from an analytics accuracy consumer\n2) Based on feedback information from an Analytics Consumer NF\n3) Both option 1 and option 2\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3878, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both option 1 and option 2", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the inter RAT mobility characteristic of handover from E-UTRA to NR? \n\nOptions:\n1) Radio resources are prepared in the source RAT before the handover\n2) In-sequence and lossless handover is supported\n3) Both Xn and NG based inter-RAT handover are not supported\n4) The source RAT configures Target RAT measurement and reporting\n5) Inter RAT measurements are limited to E-UTRA\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3883, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The source RAT configures Target RAT measurement and reporting", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the dispatchable location accuracy refer to? \n\nOptions:\n1) Horizontal accuracy\n2) Vertical accuracy\n3) Civic location granularity\n4) Reliability\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3887, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Civic location granularity", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does SIPTO@LN stand for? \n\nOptions:\n1) Signaling Transport Protocol Over Local Network\n2) Secure Internet Protocol Tunneling Over Local Network\n3) Session Initiation Protocol Transfer Option for Local Network\n4) Service Implementation for Public Telephony Over Local Network\n5) System Integration for Private Telecommunications Operators\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3906, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Secure Internet Protocol Tunneling Over Local Network", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of clock synchronization should the 3GPP system support across 5G-based Ethernet links with PDU-session type Ethernet? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) IEEE 802.1AS\n2) IEEE 802.1Qbv\n3) Better than 1\u00b5s accuracy\n4) Coexistence of hard-RT and lower priority traffic\n5) Routing based on Ethernet header information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3909, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  IEEE 802.1AS", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the fundamental characteristics for QoS in the Streaming class? \n\nOptions:\n1) Preserve time relation\n2) Stringent and low delay\n3) Low bit error rate\n4) Transparent payload transfer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3917, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Preserve time relation", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the redundancy version number used for the initial transmission or autonomous retransmission of an initial transport block for a PUSCH transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0\n2) 1\n3) 2\n4) 3\n5) repK-RV\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3918, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  0", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich 3GPP system entities are impacted by MUSIM? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE\n2) MME / AMF\n3) RAN / NG-RAN\n4) SGW-C / SMF\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3920, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UE do if it is unable to comply with any part of the configuration included in the MobilityFromNRCommand message? \n\nOptions:\n1) Revert back to the configuration used in the source PCell\n2) Stop all timers and release radio resources\n3) Initiate the connection re-establishment procedure\n4) Store handover failure information in VarRLF-Report\n5) Attempt to select an E-UTRA cell\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3928, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Revert back to the configuration used in the source PCell", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the formula to compute the angle between the unit vectors of the GCS and the LCS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Angle = acos(u1*u2 + v1*v2 + w1*w2)\n2) Angle = atan2(v2, v1)\n3) Angle = atan2(u2, u1)\n4) Angle = asin(w1*w2)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3931, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Angle = acos(u1*u2 + v1*v2 + w1*w2)", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is specified in TS 24.588 related to V2X services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Architecture enhancements for V2X services\n2) User Equipment (UE) policies for V2X services\n3) Vehicle-to-Everything (V2X) services in 5G System (5GS); Stage 3\n4) Characteristics of the Universal Subscriber Identity Module (USIM) application\n5) VAS layer supported V2X communication using local MBMS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3937, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  User Equipment (UE) policies for V2X services", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does AMF Load Re-Balancing functionality allow? \n\nOptions:\n1) Stopping redirection of UEs served by one of its GUAMI(s)\n2) Moving UEs from CM-IDLE state to CM-CONNECTED state\n3) Increasing the weight factor of an AMF after installation\n4) Moving UEs registered on an AMF to another AMF within the same AMF set\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3938, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Moving UEs registered on an AMF to another AMF within the same AMF set", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens in the EAP-based Network Slice-Specific authentication procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) The AAA Server exchanges AAA protocol messages with a potential external AAA Server\n2) The UE is authorized for a network slice or re-allocated to a different one\n3) The AUSF exchanges AAA protocol messages with a potentially external AAA Server\n4) The AAA Server triggers a re-authentication and re-authorization procedure\n5) The AAA Proxy exchanges AAA protocol messages with the AUSF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3946, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The AUSF exchanges AAA protocol messages with a potentially external AAA Server", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the supported service type for QoE Measurement Collection? \n\nOptions:\n1) QoE Measurement Collection for DASH streaming services\n2) QoE Measurement Collection for MTSI services\n3) QoE Measurement Collection for VR services\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3954, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich CIoT features have been introduced in Rel-16? \n\nOptions:\n1) Control Plane CIoT 5GS Optimisation (CP CIoT 5GS Optimisation)\n2) User Plane CIoT 5GS Optimisation (UP CIoT 5GS Optimisation)\n3) Non-IP Data Delivery (NIDD)\n4) Reliable Data Service (RDS)\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3957, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich Work Item targets inter-cell interference cancellation in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) LTE_MUST\n2) LTE_FNBID\n3) NAICS\n4) LTE_PERF\n5) LTE_TR\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3962, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  NAICS", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when a call undergoes voice call continuity and becomes barred in the target domain/system? \n\nOptions:\n1) The call continues in the target domain/system\n2) The call terminates\n3) Voice call continuity is not executed for the call\n4) The call is put on hold\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3964, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Voice call continuity is not executed for the call", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nDoes the 3GPP PS Data Off status affect data transfer over non-3GPP access? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes, it completely blocks data transfer over non-3GPP access.\n2) No, it has no impact on data transfer over non-3GPP access.\n3) It depends on the specific services being used.\n4) It depends on the type of non-3GPP access.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3965, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  No, it has no impact on data transfer over non-3GPP access.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the relationship between the spherical angles of the GCS and the LCS? \n\nOptions:\n1) The spherical angles of the GCS are equal to the spherical angles of the LCS\n2) The spherical angles of the GCS are related to the spherical angles of the LCS through a set of equations\n3) The spherical angles of the GCS are perpendicular to the spherical angles of the LCS\n4) The spherical angles of the GCS depend on the orientation of the array\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3969, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The spherical angles of the GCS are related to the spherical angles of the LCS through a set of equations", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Notification Control parameter indicate? \n\nOptions:\n1) The GFBR for a QoS flow\n2) The QoS parameter sets\n3) Whether notifications are requested for GFBR fulfillment\n4) The QoS flow ID\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3972, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Whether notifications are requested for GFBR fulfillment", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following principles apply when 5GS assists AI/ML operations in the application layer? \n\nOptions:\n1) AF requests to the 5G System shall be authorized by the 5GC\n2) Application AI/ML decisions reside at the AF and UE application client\n3) AF can decide when to request assistance from 5GC\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3974, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is VarMeasConfig used for? \n\nOptions:\n1) To configure the mobility behavior of the UE\n2) To configure the reporting of measurements performed by the UE\n3) To configure the logging of measurements performed by the UE\n4) To configure the measurements to be performed by the UE\n5) To configure the random-access procedure of the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3987, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To configure the measurements to be performed by the UE", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the minimum value of the uniformly distributed variables used for UMa and UMi-Street Canyon? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0\n2) 10\n3) 25\n4) 60\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 3988, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  0", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are charges settled between the different parties involved in the registration link? \n\nOptions:\n1) Charges are levied and paid directly between the user and serving network operators.\n2) Charges are paid by each party to the network operator on a wholesale basis.\n3) Charges are paid by the roaming broker to the network operator on a wholesale basis.\n4) Charges are settled on a retail basis between the user and home environment.\n5) Charges are settled through a clearing house between the user and serving network operators.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4001, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Charges are paid by each party to the network operator on a wholesale basis.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following is NOT a type of V2X application? \n\nOptions:\n1) Vehicle-to-Vehicle (V2V)\n2) Vehicle-to-Infrastructure (V2I)\n3) Vehicle-to-Network (V2N)\n4) Vehicle-to-Human (V2H)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4011, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Vehicle-to-Human (V2H)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the NF instances (AMF and SMF) serving a specific UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) SUPI and S-NSSAI\n2) NF Instance IDs and NF Set IDs\n3) Analytics ID and Target of Analytics Reporting\n4) Area of interest and list of analytics subsets\n5) Preferred order of results and Reporting Threshold\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4012, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  SUPI and S-NSSAI", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Fixed Reception for TV services? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable unicast TV content delivery\n2) To ensure privacy and non-identification of users\n3) To support network capacity assignment\n4) To deliver media content via unicast and broadcast\n5) To allow the use of existing TV antenna equipment for broadcast TV\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4013, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To allow the use of existing TV antenna equipment for broadcast TV", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich CDR types include the information about the selected or allocated core network operator? \n\nOptions:\n1) MSC, SGSN, Serving GW and GGSN/PDN GW\n2) MSC and SGSN only\n3) Serving GW and GGSN/PDN GW only\n4) MSC, SGSN, and Serving GW only\n5) GGSN/PDN GW only\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4019, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  MSC, SGSN, Serving GW and GGSN/PDN GW", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the correlation function used to describe the autocorrelation of shadow fading? \n\nOptions:\n1) Gaussian\n2) Linear\n3) Exponential\n4) Sigmoid\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4029, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Exponential", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the range of frequencies for the transmitter spurious emission limits? \n\nOptions:\n1) From 30 MHz to the fifth harmonic of the upper frequency edge of the DL operating band, excluding \u0394fOBUE\n2) From the channel edge up to frequencies separated from the channel edge by 200% of the necessary bandwidth\n3) From the channel edge up to frequencies separated from the channel edge by 100% of the necessary bandwidth\n4) From the assigned channel frequency to an adjacent channel frequency\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4033, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  From 30 MHz to the fifth harmonic of the upper frequency edge of the DL operating band, excluding \u0394fOBUE", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Nchf_ConvergedCharging service Create Operation achieve for SMS Charging in the 5G System Architecture Phase 1? \n\nOptions:\n1) Event-based charging mode\n2) Service-based charging architecture\n3) SMS charging information\n4) IP-SM-GW and SMS-SC\n5) 5GS RAT Type and User Location\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4036, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Event-based charging mode", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the TSCTSF control the (g)PTP-based time synchronization service without AF request? \n\nOptions:\n1) During UE registration\n2) During PDU Session Establishment\n3) During PCF policy authorization\n4) During TSCTSF initialization\n5) During UDM retrieval\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4037, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  During PDU Session Establishment", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specification defines the overall 5GS Stage 2? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.502\n2) TS 23.503\n3) TR 23.799\n4) TS 23.501\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4043, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  TS 23.501", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of signal is used for wake-up in NB-IoT? \n\nOptions:\n1) Cell-specific reference signal\n2) Synchronization signal\n3) Discovery signal\n4) Wake-up signal\n5) Reference signal\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4046, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Wake-up signal", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the RedCap UE type? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable carrier aggregation and dual connectivity in NR\n2) To support high data rate requirements for IoT devices\n3) To reduce UE complexity and power consumption for IoT use cases\n4) To enable messaging communication in the 5G System\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4047, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To reduce UE complexity and power consumption for IoT use cases", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the objectives of the schemes introduced in the MUSIM work item for LTE/NR? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support multiple frequencies of USIM cards.\n2) To address the paging occasion collision issue for MUSIM UE.\n3) To notify the network of a switch from one network to another for MUSIM purpose.\n4) To indicate to the MUSIM UE whether an incoming paging is for voice service.\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4055, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat category do the V2X configuration parameters fall under? \n\nOptions:\n1) V2X provisioning\n2) V2X communication over PC5\n3) V2X communication over LTE-Uu\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4058, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of indicating a VCC event in charging information? \n\nOptions:\n1) To apply appropriate ratings for the CS and IMS parts of the continued voice call\n2) To track the location of the user during voice call continuity\n3) To determine the billing address for the continued voice call\n4) To enable the transfer of charging information between operators\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4063, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To apply appropriate ratings for the CS and IMS parts of the continued voice call", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of standardising service capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) To make it difficult for operators to differentiate their services\n2) To reduce the complexity of providing services across different operators' networks\n3) To limit the types of services that can be introduced\n4) To increase the cost of introducing new services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4064, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To reduce the complexity of providing services across different operators' networks", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat kind of charging architecture does the 5G Data Connectivity domain charging rely on? \n\nOptions:\n1) Generic converged charging architecture\n2) Unified charging architecture\n3) Distributed charging architecture\n4) Separate charging architecture\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4079, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Generic converged charging architecture", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat message is sent by the MS to the network to request the release of a GMM context? \n\nOptions:\n1) Detach request (mobile terminated detach)\n2) Detach request (mobile originating detach)\n3) Detach accept (mobile terminated detach)\n4) Detach accept (mobile originating detach)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4081, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Detach request (mobile terminated detach)", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can the V2X Application Server address be determined for V2X communication over LTE-Uu? \n\nOptions:\n1) By configuring V2X Application Server information\n2) By using TCP transport\n3) By using downlink multicast and non-GBR bearer\n4) By using the UDP/IP transport\n5) By using the V3 interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4082, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  By configuring V2X Application Server information", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the UE negotiate with the AF for analytics subscription? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through the network layer\n2) Through the NWDAF\n3) Through the SMF\n4) Through the application layer\n5) Through the NRF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4083, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Through the application layer", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich document specifies the MUSIM-specific rejection cause for EPS? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.501\n2) TS 27.007\n3) TS 29.518\n4) TS 24.501\n5) TS 29.274\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4089, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  TS 29.274", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich document specifies the protocols for V2X authorization between the V2X Control Function and the HSS over the V4 interface? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.203\n2) TS 24.386\n3) TS 29.116\n4) TS 29.061\n5) TS 29.388\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4090, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  TS 29.388", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of file management in network management? \n\nOptions:\n1) To store and transfer data between network functions and management functions\n2) To provide basic connectivity information to a NE after it is powered up\n3) To support management of MDT measurement collection in UMTS, LTE, and 5G networks\n4) To control and discover management data production and collection\n5) To enable charging for roaming local breakout scenario\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4093, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To store and transfer data between network functions and management functions", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Scheduling request feature in NB-IoT allow a connected mode UE to do? \n\nOptions:\n1) Trigger a random access procedure for UL resource allocation\n2) Configure periodic NPUSCH resources for BSR transmission\n3) Send a request to the eNB to be granted NPUSCH resources\n4) Receive a grant for EDT if pending data is smaller than a maximum permitted size\n5) Reduce the system acquisition time for the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4103, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Send a request to the eNB to be granted NPUSCH resources", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is used to carry HARQ feedback over the sidelink? \n\nOptions:\n1) Physical Sidelink Control Channel (PSCCH)\n2) Physical Sidelink Broadcast Channel (PSBCH)\n3) Physical Sidelink Shared Channel (PSSCH)\n4) Physical Sidelink Feedback Channel (PSFCH)\n5) DM-RS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4113, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Physical Sidelink Feedback Channel (PSFCH)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does EARFCN stand for? \n\nOptions:\n1) EARly Frequency Channel Number\n2) Early Frequency Resource Channel Number\n3) E-UTRA Absolute Radio Frequency Channel Number\n4) Ethernet Absolute Radio Frequency Channel Number\n5) Eventual Absolute Radio Frequency Channel Number\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4114, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  E-UTRA Absolute Radio Frequency Channel Number", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the required inputs for the Nadrf_DataManagement_RetrievalSubscribe service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Service Operation, Analytics Specification or Data Specification, Time Window\n2) DataSetTag, Service Operation, Time Window\n3) Service Operation, Analytics Specification or Data Specification, Fetch flag\n4) DataSetTag, Time Window, Fetch flag\n5) Service Operation, Fetch flag\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4115, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Service Operation, Analytics Specification or Data Specification, Time Window", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich feature was introduced in Rel-15 to improve transmission reliability in Carrier Aggregation (CA) for mode-4? \n\nOptions:\n1) Support for 64-QAM\n2) Reduction of the maximum time between packet arrival and resource selection\n3) Transmit diversity\n4) Radio resource pool sharing\n5) Short Transmission Time Interval (TTI)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4117, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Transmit diversity", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the granularity of the time reference provided by the network to end user equipment in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.25 microseconds\n2) 1 microsecond\n3) 10 microseconds\n4) 100 microseconds\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4132, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  0.25 microseconds", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the SDAP sublayer in Layer 2? \n\nOptions:\n1) Mapping between logical channels and transport channels\n2) Transfer of upper layer PDUs\n3) Transfer of data radio bearers\n4) Marking QoS flow ID in packets\n5) Error correction through ARQ\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4136, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Marking QoS flow ID in packets", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are examples of management services that can be produced by an entity in a mobile network? \n\nOptions:\n1) Network slicing and performance management services\n2) Configuration management services and fault supervision services\n3) NF and network management functions\n4) Performance management services and fault supervision services\n5) Network Functions and NFV MANO interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4146, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Configuration management services and fault supervision services", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nCan subscribers' access be restricted to only GERAN or UTRAN in a visited network that has not separated the Location/Routing area categories? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes\n2) No\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4159, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  No", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat additional function does the MME support in case of SIPTO@LN with stand-alone gateway? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transfer of the collocated L-GW IP address to the eNB\n2) Support for MME-triggered P-GW relocation\n3) Activation of SIPTO@LN PDN for requested APN\n4) Release of SIPTO@LN PDN connection for idle-mode UE\n5) S-GW relocation without UE mobility\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4181, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  S-GW relocation without UE mobility", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can the MDA MnS consumer expect from the MDA producer regarding the network context? \n\nOptions:\n1) Complete network context\n2) Partial network context\n3) No network context\n4) Real-time network context\n5) Network context based on consumer's usage\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4184, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  No network context", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of user data congestion analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) To collect measurements from the OAM\n2) To determine the area where a specific UE is located\n3) To provide statistics or predictions or both related to congestion experienced while transferring user data\n4) To subscribe to user data congestion analytics\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4186, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To provide statistics or predictions or both related to congestion experienced while transferring user data", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich layers are described in the 36.300 series? \n\nOptions:\n1) Layer 1 and Layer 2\n2) Layer 2 and Layer 3\n3) Layer 1 and Layer 3\n4) Only Layer 1\n5) Only Layer 3\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4200, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Layer 2 and Layer 3", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich SRB is used for RRC messages using the CCCH logical channel? \n\nOptions:\n1) SRB0\n2) SRB1\n3) SRB2\n4) SRB3\n5) SRB4\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4211, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  SRB0", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the main operations that can be performed using the ADRF service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Store data or analytics, retrieve data or analytics, delete data or analytics\n2) Store data or analytics, retrieve data or analytics, update data or analytics\n3) Store data or analytics, retrieve data or analytics, delete ML models\n4) Store data or analytics, retrieve ML models, delete data or analytics\n5) Store ML models, retrieve data or analytics, delete data or analytics\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4212, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Store data or analytics, retrieve data or analytics, delete data or analytics", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nUnder what conditions does the UE ignore PDCCH skipping? \n\nOptions:\n1) When SR is sent and is pending on all serving cells of the Cell Group\n2) During monitoring of the RAR/MsgB window on SpCell\n3) While contention resolution timer is running on SpCell\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4222, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the MBMSAPI_MCS in the MBMS APIs for Mission Critical Services? \n\nOptions:\n1) To implement the logic of MBMS operations for Mission Critical applications\n2) To provide decoupling between the platform MBMS functions and the mission critical application call control functions\n3) To enable easy development of Mission Critical Services across different phone platforms\n4) To provide secured storage area for MCData communication history\n5) To enable interworking between Mission Critical systems and Land Mobile Radio systems\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4230, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To provide decoupling between the platform MBMS functions and the mission critical application call control functions", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat measurements does the UE need to make in RRC_IDLE mode for E-CID? \n\nOptions:\n1) NRSRP and NRSRQ measurements\n2) DL and UL power measurements\n3) RSRP and RSRQ measurements\n4) Signal strength and signal quality measurements\n5) RSSI and SNR measurements\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4234, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  NRSRP and NRSRQ measurements", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat mechanism allows an NG-RAN node to request activation of certain deactivated SSB beams? \n\nOptions:\n1) Inter-node Beam Activation\n2) Dynamic Beam Allocation\n3) Beamforming Adaptation\n4) Enhanced Synchronization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4240, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Inter-node Beam Activation", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the SN-DU send to the SN-CU after receiving the UE CONTEXT RELEASE message from the SN-CU? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE\n2) UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION REQUEST\n3) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND\n4) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMPLETE\n5) UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4241, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMPLETE", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is power saving enabled during active-time? \n\nOptions:\n1) Cross-slot scheduling\n2) PDCCH monitoring adaptation mechanisms\n3) BWP switching\n4) DRX configuration\n5) RLM and BFD relaxation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4242, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Cross-slot scheduling", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following services and capabilities can be exposed to 3rd party service providers? \n\nOptions:\n1) Support of 3rd party requested MTC Device triggering\n2) Support of 3rd party interaction for 3GPP resource management for background data transfer\n3) Support of 3rd party interaction on information for predictable communication patterns of a UE\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4248, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of classifying UEs as fixed, camper or traveller? \n\nOptions:\n1) To identify the top contributors to data volume dispersion\n2) To predict QoS attributes for UEs\n3) To limit access to certain areas or slices\n4) To rank hot locations based on UE activity\n5) To analyze the location of UEs during a period of interest\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4250, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To limit access to certain areas or slices", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich entity controls the 5G Access Stratum-based Time Distribution for a UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE\n2) AMF\n3) NG-RAN\n4) PCF\n5) TSCTSF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4254, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  AMF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a Customer Premises Network (CPN)? \n\nOptions:\n1) A network located within a residence, office or shop that provides connectivity to the 5G network.\n2) A network owned, installed, and configured by a public network operator.\n3) A network that consists of PIN Elements and communicates using PIN Direct Connection.\n4) A network that supports mechanisms for identifying a PIN, PIN Element, eRG, and PRAS.\n5) A network that supports regulatory requirements for emergency calls, PWS, and eCall for UEs connected via 3GPP access.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4268, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  A network located within a residence, office or shop that provides connectivity to the 5G network.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the MPS system? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide preferential treatment based on the subscription for MPS\n2) To enable access and core network resources for MPS sessions\n3) To assign priority levels to Service Users\n4) To support Priority Data Bearer Service\n5) To provide MPS for roaming Service Users\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4282, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide preferential treatment based on the subscription for MPS", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich carrier has the highest cell reselection priority for sidelink operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) The carrier pre-configured for sidelink communication\n2) The carrier pre-configured for V2X sidelink communication\n3) The carrier providing inter-carrier V2X sidelink configuration\n4) The serving carrier\n5) The carrier providing inter-carrier NR sidelink configuration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4293, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The carrier pre-configured for sidelink communication", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere should the position information be provided to? \n\nOptions:\n1) Location services applications existing within the PLMN\n2) Location services applications external to the PLMN\n3) Location services applications in Mobile Equipment\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4298, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is VarRLF-Report used for? \n\nOptions:\n1) To store the radio link failure or handover failure information\n2) To store the successful handover information\n3) To store the random-access related information\n4) To store the mobility history information\n5) To store the connection establishment failure and/or connection resume failure information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4299, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To store the radio link failure or handover failure information", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the capability of the 5G system in managing communication across multi-path indirect network connections? \n\nOptions:\n1) It cannot manage multi-path connections\n2) It can manage only single-path connections\n3) It can manage both single-path and multi-path connections\n4) No specific capability mentioned\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4300, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  It can manage both single-path and multi-path connections", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the number of consecutive OFDM symbols per subframe? \n\nOptions:\n1) depends on the subcarrierSpacing\n2) 10\n3) 15\n4) 20\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4303, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  depends on the subcarrierSpacing", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the number of logical slots for a reservation period determined? \n\nOptions:\n1) By multiplying the resource pool size by the sub-carrier spacing\n2) By counting the number of slots in a resource pool\n3) By converting the resource reservation period from milliseconds to logical slots\n4) By dividing the resource reservation interval by the number of sub-channels\n5) By subtracting the resource reservation interval from the total number of slots in a resource pool\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4308, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By converting the resource reservation period from milliseconds to logical slots", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich group focuses on defining and parameterizing emerging usage scenarios for mmWave propagation channels? \n\nOptions:\n1) Steering Committee\n2) Modelling Methodology Group\n3) Measurement Methodology Group\n4) Indoor Group\n5) Outdoor Group\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4314, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Outdoor Group", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the three connectivity models supported by 5GC to enable Edge Computing? \n\nOptions:\n1) Distributed Anchor Point, Session Breakout, DNN Steering\n2) Anchor Point, Session Breakout, DNN Steering\n3) Distributed Connectivity, Session Breakout, Multiple PDU Sessions\n4) Distributed Anchor Point, Session Breakout, Multiple PDU Sessions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4321, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Distributed Anchor Point, Session Breakout, Multiple PDU Sessions", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information can a 3rd party service provider provide about predictable communication patterns of UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Time and traffic volume related patterns\n2) Location and mobility related patterns\n3) Both time and traffic volume related patterns, and location and mobility related patterns\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4322, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both time and traffic volume related patterns, and location and mobility related patterns", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of the Master RAN Node in Dual Connectivity? \n\nOptions:\n1) Terminate the N2 connection with the UE\n2) Relay NAS signaling between the UE and the core network\n3) Handle the user plane connection for the UE\n4) Exchange User Plane traffic of the UE with the Secondary RAN node\n5) Set up a Dual Connectivity for the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4328, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Handle the user plane connection for the UE", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Policy Control functionality in the MPS system? \n\nOptions:\n1) To assign priority levels to Service Users\n2) To handle MPS interactions with supplementary services\n3) To retain MPS invoked during transient network degradation\n4) To make and enforce policy decisions for MPS application services\n5) To support MPS during and after handover\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4329, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To make and enforce policy decisions for MPS application services", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NAS protocol on N1 comprise of? \n\nOptions:\n1) NAS-MM and NAS-SM\n2) NAS-LTE and NAS-3GPP\n3) NAS-RAN and NAS-AN\n4) NAS-UPF and NAS-SMF\n5) NAS-NSA and NAS-SA\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4333, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  NAS-MM and NAS-SM", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich services may require accurate cell identification for NG-RAN location reporting? \n\nOptions:\n1) Emergency services\n2) Lawful intercept\n3) Charging\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4337, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the impact on line identification services during voice call continuity? \n\nOptions:\n1) The line identity of the calling party is not available during voice call continuity\n2) The line identity of the calling party remains unchanged during voice call continuity\n3) The line identity of the calling party is restricted during voice call continuity\n4) The line identity of the calling party is replaced with IMS information during voice call continuity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4338, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The line identity of the calling party remains unchanged during voice call continuity", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does session-based charging involve? \n\nOptions:\n1) Supervising the actual network resource consumption\n2) Debiting the subscriber account immediately for each chargeable event\n3) Blocking a certain amount of units on the subscriber's account\n4) Reserving credit from the subscriber account\n5) Matching a user session with a charging session\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4341, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Matching a user session with a charging session", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum number of configured CCs for a UE in Carrier Aggregation (CA)? \n\nOptions:\n1) 8\n2) 12\n3) 16\n4) 20\n5) 24\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4348, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  16", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can the DCCF do in the 5G system architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Retrieve management data from OAM\n2) Collect data from NWDAF\n3) Collect data from NF using Nnf services\n4) Collect data using a messaging framework\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4351, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the EVS Floating-point Conformance for Non Bit-Exact work item? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable the network to delay or reduce handoffs of a Multimedia Telephony Service for IMS terminal by providing additional information about packet losses\n2) To specify the support of single radio voice call continuity from 5GS to UTRAN in RAN\n3) To investigate potential charging requirements and mechanisms to support volume based charging for VoLTE\n4) To specify the enhancements to enable conformance testing for non bit-exact floating-point implementations of the EVS codec\n5) To enhance the media handling aspects of conversational services in 5G\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4365, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To specify the enhancements to enable conformance testing for non bit-exact floating-point implementations of the EVS codec", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat criteria are considered for network broadcast capacity assignment? \n\nOptions:\n1) OTT provider request and available network capacity\n2) OTT provider request and number of users under broadcast coverage\n3) Network unicast/broadcast capacity and location information of UE\n4) Static allocation and dynamic allocation of radio resources\n5) Regulatory requirements and network broadcast geographic area coverage\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4372, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  OTT provider request and available network capacity", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich message is used for the sidelink transfer of Paging message and System Information messages? \n\nOptions:\n1) NotificationMessageSidelink\n2) RRCReconfigurationSidelink\n3) UECapabilityEnquirySidelink\n4) UuMessageTransferSidelink\n5) MeasurementReportSidelink\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4378, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  UuMessageTransferSidelink", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of a codeword in the context of Target UE privacy? \n\nOptions:\n1) To determine which Requestors are allowed to request location information\n2) To ensure that only the intended requestor or LCS client can use the codeword\n3) To secure the codeword from being misused\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4386, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the relationship between radiation field and power pattern defined in general? \n\nOptions:\n1) As a linear equation\n2) As a quadratic equation\n3) As an exponential equation\n4) As a mathematical function\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4397, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  As a quadratic equation", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the SMF in a 5G VN group? \n\nOptions:\n1) To manage the UE subscription data\n2) To configure the External Group ID\n3) To handle the user plane paths\n4) To establish N19 tunnels between UPFs\n5) To create VLAN tags for Ethernet PDU Sessions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4399, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To handle the user plane paths", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the eNodeB use the selected core network information for? \n\nOptions:\n1) To indicate the PLMN-index to the SGSN\n2) To transmit in broadcast system information\n3) To indicate the PLMN-id to the MME\n4) To select target cells for future handovers\n5) To select the GERAN/UTRAN target network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4401, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To select target cells for future handovers", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the basic UE measurement quantities for measurements within E-UTRAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) RSRP and RSRQ\n2) RSSI and RS-SINR\n3) RSRP and RSSI\n4) RSSI and RSRQ\n5) RS-SINR and RSRQ\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4415, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  RSRP and RSRQ", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of an eRG in a CPN? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide access to 5G network services for UEs and non-3GPP devices on the CPN.\n2) To provide a means for an authorized administrator to configure and manage a PIN.\n3) To support mechanisms for identifying a PIN, PIN Element, eRG, and PRAS.\n4) To provide connectivity to the 5G network via wireline, wireless, or hybrid access.\n5) To provide a base station installed in a CPN for UEs to access the CPN and/or 5G network services.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4418, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide access to 5G network services for UEs and non-3GPP devices on the CPN.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the TRMS metric in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) To measure the radiated performance of a handheld UE\n2) To verify the performance of UE antenna subsystem\n3) To quantify the throughput levels for each UE testing condition\n4) To measure the fading profile within certain scope and conditions\n5) To test the sensitivity levels over the air at different UE angular rotations\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4431, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To measure the radiated performance of a handheld UE", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Xn-C interface in the NG-RAN architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transport of user plane data between two NG-RAN nodes\n2) Transport of control plane information between two NG-RAN nodes\n3) Transport of NAS messages\n4) Dual connectivity management\n5) UE mobility management\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4432, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Transport of control plane information between two NG-RAN nodes", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum number of configured CCs for a UE in carrier aggregation? \n\nOptions:\n1) 2 for DL and 2 for UL\n2) 4 for DL and 4 for UL\n3) 8 for DL and 8 for UL\n4) 16 for DL and 16 for UL\n5) Unlimited\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4440, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  16 for DL and 16 for UL", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich media transport protocols are supported for MCVideo service? \n\nOptions:\n1) RTP and SRTP\n2) H.264 (AVC) and H.265 (HEVC)\n3) TS 26.281 and TS 24.482\n4) TS 22.281 and TS 22.282\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4446, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  RTP and SRTP", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when there are no more data packets to be forwarded for an E-RAB in indirect data forwarding from EPS to 5GS? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UPF/PGW-U sends one or several end marker packets to the SGW\n2) The source NG-RAN node forwards the received end markers in the EPS bearer tunnel to the SGW\n3) The SGW forwards the end markers to the UPF\n4) The target NG-RAN node starts to transmit the data packets of all QoS flows mapped to the corresponding E-RAB\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4451, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat transmission technique is used to multiplex transport channels using MBSFN and non-MBSFN transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) Single-User MIMO\n2) Multi-User MIMO\n3) Spatial division multiplexing\n4) Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing\n5) Space frequency block coding\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4468, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Spatial division multiplexing", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the NWDAF collect data for Collective Behaviour attributes? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through OAM services\n2) Through NRF services\n3) Through AF services\n4) Through NEF services\n5) Through UE Input Data Collection Procedure\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4480, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Through AF services", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens if the QCI=1 bearer setup request for VoLTE is rejected due to weak LTE coverage in originating session? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE performs UL asynchronous HARQ transmission\n2) UE performs SRVCC\n3) UE performs HARQ\n4) UE performs MU-MIMO\n5) UE performs CSFB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4493, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  UE performs CSFB", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is included in the final SIP response for tracking applications generating charging information? \n\nOptions:\n1) P-GW address and EPC Charging ID\n2) MSC address and Call Reference Number\n3) Address or specific NE identifier of each IMS NE\n4) Address or identifier of the hosting AS and its application identifier\n5) IOI identities received in the session signalling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4499, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Address or identifier of the hosting AS and its application identifier", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the two types of CLI measurements? \n\nOptions:\n1) SRS-RSRP measurement and CLI-ULI measurement\n2) CLI-RSSI measurement and SRS-CSI measurement\n3) RSRP measurement and RSSI measurement\n4) SRS-RSRP measurement and CLI-RSSI measurement\n5) ULI measurement and CSI measurement\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4503, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  SRS-RSRP measurement and CLI-RSSI measurement", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information does the MSC retrieve from another MSC/VLR or the UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Core network operator\n2) PLMN-id\n3) TAI/RAI\n4) Anchor PLMN\n5) IMSI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4511, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  IMSI", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of specifying common codecs and preferred codecs in MMCMH? \n\nOptions:\n1) Optimizing resource usage\n2) Ensuring security and privacy\n3) Supporting different types of services\n4) Handling potential network failures\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4512, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Optimizing resource usage", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum delay for control plane latency in the Evolved Packet System? \n\nOptions:\n1) 5 ms\n2) 10 ms\n3) 30 ms\n4) 1 ms\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4513, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  10 ms", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat session can be supported in real time for an Evolved ProSe Remote UE using Indirect 3GPP Communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) Non-real time data services\n2) Real-time video\n3) Small data services\n4) Multimedia telephony\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4519, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Multimedia telephony", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many consecutive sub-carriers during one slot correspond to one downlink resource block? \n\nOptions:\n1) 6\n2) 12\n3) 24\n4) 50\n5) 110\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4520, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  12", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does CBR stand for in the context of V2X communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) Channel Broadcast Ratio\n2) Carrier Bandwidth Resource\n3) Control and Data Periods\n4) Channel Busy Ratio\n5) Cell Point To Multi-point\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4523, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Channel Busy Ratio", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the exemption provided for prioritized services during Control Plane Congestion and Overload Control? \n\nOptions:\n1) Exemption from RRC Connection Establishment prioritization\n2) Exemption from session management congestion controls\n3) Exemption from mobility management congestion controls\n4) Exemption from QoS Flow load rebalancing\n5) Exemption from IMC prioritization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4524, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Exemption from session management congestion controls", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow should the UE handle an error regarding the conditionality of a field in an extension addition group? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ignore the extension addition group\n2) Ignore just the field in error\n3) Ignore the entire itemInfo entry\n4) Apply the generic error handling to the subsequent 'parent' field(s)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4525, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Ignore the entire itemInfo entry", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the work item on Flexible eNB-ID and Cell-ID in E-UTRAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support more than 1.04 million eNBs in a PLMN and cells beyond 256 in an eNB\n2) To enable operation of an LAA SCell on the UL in unlicensed spectrum\n3) To define the requirements and signaling support for a new UE category with a single receiver\n4) To improve mobility and throughput performance under high speed scenarios\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4530, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To support more than 1.04 million eNBs in a PLMN and cells beyond 256 in an eNB", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich scenario requires very high connection density and the ability to share what the users see and hear? \n\nOptions:\n1) Urban macro\n2) Rural macro\n3) Indoor hotspot\n4) Broadband access in a crowd\n5) Dense urban\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4538, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Broadband access in a crowd", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the ECM Work Item and the resulting specification in TS 28.538? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide management provisions and solutions for edge computing\n2) To support dynamic availability of Edge and EAS\n3) To define the architecture for enabling Edge Applications\n4) To specify the security aspects of application layer support of the Edge Applications\n5) To support service provisioning for UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4547, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide management provisions and solutions for edge computing", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the potential impact of UE/TRP PCO errors on NR carrier phase positioning accuracy? \n\nOptions:\n1) PCO errors only impact carrier phase measurements but not positioning accuracy\n2) PCO errors have a significant impact on positioning accuracy\n3) PCO errors have a larger impact when using carrier phases from multiple carriers\n4) PCO errors have a larger impact when using carrier phases from multiple subcarriers\n5) PCO errors have a negligible impact on positioning accuracy\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4548, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  PCO errors have a negligible impact on positioning accuracy", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWho is the consumer of the PFD Determination analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) SMF\n2) NWDAF\n3) UPF\n4) NEF(PFDF)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4561, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  NEF(PFDF)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does EN-DC stand for? \n\nOptions:\n1) Evolved Non-Standalone Dual Connectivity\n2) Evolved Network Data Center\n3) Enhanced Non-Standalone Double Coverage\n4) Evolved Network-Device Communication\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4562, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Evolved Non-Standalone Dual Connectivity", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Enhanced Closed loop SLS Assurance solution? \n\nOptions:\n1) To continuously deliver the expected level of communication service quality\n2) To optimize the services provided over an NG-RAN and 5GC network\n3) To improve the QoE measurement collection in UMTS, LTE, and 5G networks\n4) To enable plug and connect support for management of network functions\n5) To enhance support for 5G network sharing scenarios\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4564, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To continuously deliver the expected level of communication service quality", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the eNA (Enablers for Network Automation for 5G) feature? \n\nOptions:\n1) To improve the NWDAF data collection and output\n2) To enhance the architecture of the V2X Application Server\n3) To support network data analytics in 4G networks\n4) To facilitate roaming reference architecture for data analytics\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4572, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To improve the NWDAF data collection and output", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich reference point supports interaction between the OCF and a Rating Function (RF)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Gy\n2) Rc\n3) Gyn\n4) Re\n5) CAP\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4576, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Re", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat inputs are required for the Nmfaf_3daDataManagement_Deconfigure service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Data Consumer or Analytics Consumer Information, Transaction Reference Id\n2) Notification Correlation Information\n3) Requested Data with timestamp or Analytics with timestamp, Fetch Instructions\n4) Set of Fetch Correlation ID(s)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4579, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Data Consumer or Analytics Consumer Information, Transaction Reference Id", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the TDL models used for? \n\nOptions:\n1) To represent different channel profiles for NLOS\n2) To represent different channel profiles for LOS\n3) To generate channel coefficients\n4) To evaluate directional algorithms\n5) To apply spatial filters\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4581, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To generate channel coefficients", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is withdrawal in the context of the Target UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) An action to make the privacy exception list with its privacy classes available to a Target UE\n2) An action taken by the service provider to remove an available privacy class from a target UE\u2019s PEL\n3) An action to invoke the LCS feature\n4) An action to bar the Location Service of a specific user\n5) An action to remove an available LCS feature from a target UE\u2019s subscription profile\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4585, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  An action taken by the service provider to remove an available privacy class from a target UE\u2019s PEL", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a roaming broker enabled Home Environment? \n\nOptions:\n1) A home environment that has a direct commercial agreement with different serving networks.\n2) A home environment that interworks with one or more serving network operators and negotiates a commercial roaming agreement.\n3) A home environment that uses fraud and cost control mechanisms to ensure charges do not exceed credit limits.\n4) A home environment that is capable of operating as a roaming broker.\n5) A home environment that routes registration requests to its serving networks.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4588, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  A home environment that interworks with one or more serving network operators and negotiates a commercial roaming agreement.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the definition of OTA modulation quality? \n\nOptions:\n1) The measure of the difference between the actual SAN transmit frequency and the assigned frequency.\n2) The difference between the power of an RE and the average RE power for a SAN at maximum output power.\n3) The difference between the maximum and the minimum transmit power of an OFDM symbol for a specified reference condition.\n4) The ratio of the filtered mean power centered on the assigned channel frequency to the filtered mean power centered on an adjacent channel frequency.\n5) The difference between the measured carrier signal and an ideal signal.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4590, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The difference between the measured carrier signal and an ideal signal.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a subscription in the context of service delivery? \n\nOptions:\n1) A commercial relationship between a subscriber and a service provider\n2) A set of services provided by a network operator\n3) A domain to which a user has access\n4) The identity of a subscriber within a domain\n5) The radio access systems available to a subscriber\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4602, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  A commercial relationship between a subscriber and a service provider", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of power headroom reports in MAC in gNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allocate physical layer resources for downlink and uplink\n2) To measure radio conditions at the gNB\n3) To provide support for power-aware packet scheduling\n4) To configure the parameters of gNB and UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4613, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To provide support for power-aware packet scheduling", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Ndccf_ContextManagement_Deregister service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To register collected data or analytics with the DCCF\n2) To update a registration of data or analytics in the DCCF\n3) To delete a registration of data or analytics from the DCCF\n4) To fetch data or analytics from the DCCF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4614, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To delete a registration of data or analytics from the DCCF", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat security mechanism is used for UE initiated messages in V2X communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) PKI TLS with SSL\n2) PSK TLS with SSL\n3) PKI TLS with GBA\n4) PSK TLS with GBA\n5) VPN with SSL\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4616, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  PSK TLS with GBA", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are PDCCH monitoring occasions for MCCH message determined when searchspaceMCCH is set to zero? \n\nOptions:\n1) They are the same as PDCCH monitoring occasions for SIB1\n2) They are determined based on search space indicated by searchspaceMCCH\n3) They are determined based on UL symbols\n4) They are sequentially numbered in the MCCH transmission window\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4619, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  They are the same as PDCCH monitoring occasions for SIB1", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used to forward short messages in the network with the GLR in case of SMS transfer over GPRS? \n\nOptions:\n1) GLb-interface\n2) GLg-interface\n3) GLe-interface\n4) GLf-interface\n5) GLj-interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4620, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  GLf-interface", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich signaling procedure is introduced to support SL Positioning? \n\nOptions:\n1) SL Access Request\n2) SL Location Information Transfer\n3) SL Power Control Mechanism\n4) SL Measurement Report\n5) SL Positioning Capability Transfer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4632, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  SL Positioning Capability Transfer", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich message is used to transfer UE radio access capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) MeasurementReportSidelink\n2) UECapabilityEnquirySidelink\n3) UECapabilityInformationSidelink\n4) RRCReconfigurationSidelink\n5) RRCReconfigurationCompleteSidelink\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4643, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  UECapabilityInformationSidelink", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identity is used for indicating an alternative MCS table for PDSCH and PUSCH? \n\nOptions:\n1) C-RNTI\n2) CI-RNTI\n3) CS-RNTI\n4) MCS-C-RNTI\n5) P-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4646, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  MCS-C-RNTI", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich work item introduces a new protocol value FAILURE_CAUSE for the SIP Reason header? \n\nOptions:\n1) eMBMS enhancements for LTE\n2) Evolution to and Interworking with eCall in IMS\n3) Password-based service activation for IMS Multimedia Telephony service\n4) Media Handling Extensions of IMS-based Telepresence\n5) SIP Reason header extension\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4650, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  SIP Reason header extension", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does FL server NWDAF do in the FL procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) Discovers and selects FL client NWDAFs to participate in the FL procedure\n2) Requests FL client NWDAFs to report local model information\n3) Generates global ML model by aggregating local model information\n4) Initiates FL procedure and provides initial model to FL client NWDAFs\n5) Receives the global ML model feedback from FL client NWDAFs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4651, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Initiates FL procedure and provides initial model to FL client NWDAFs", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can a Service User initiate MPS for an MMTEL voice call with a UE that does not have an MPS subscription? \n\nOptions:\n1) By using a specialized MPS application on the UE\n2) By including an MPS-unique identifier or feature code in the request\n3) By using a predetermined access number\n4) By using a predetermined method recognized by the visited PLMN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4652, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By using a predetermined access number", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NWDAF provide to the consumer in PFD Determination analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) Confidence level of the statistics\n2) PFD Information\n3) Preferred level of accuracy\n4) Data analytics results\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4666, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  PFD Information", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the DCCF do when a requested data is already being collected from a Data Source? \n\nOptions:\n1) Send a new subscription/request towards the Data Source\n2) Modify existing subscriptions with the Data Source\n3) Create new subscription(s) to new Data Source\n4) Continue collecting the data from the Data Source\n5) Send a request to stop collecting the data\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4669, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Continue collecting the data from the Data Source", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the main control functions of automated control systems? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Taking measurements, comparing results, and correcting errors\n2) Sensing processes, feeding measurements back into a controller, and manipulating processes\n3) Sending messages to actuators and monitoring device states\n4) Monitoring thresholds, diagnosing malfunctions, and performing maintenance work\n5) Updating positions periodically and monitoring characteristic parameters\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4677, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Taking measurements, comparing results, and correcting errors", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the UE-assistance indication in load-balancing steering mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allow the UE to decide on split percentages based on its internal state\n2) To dictate fixed split percentages for load balancing\n3) To optimize network performance measurements\n4) To provide guidelines to the UPF on load balancing\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4680, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To allow the UE to decide on split percentages based on its internal state", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich TS specifies the charging solution for 5G System Architecture Phase 1? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.503\n2) TS 32.255\n3) TS 38.300\n4) TS 37.340\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4682, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  TS 32.255", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of MBMS-APIs? \n\nOptions:\n1) To simplify the integration of third-party MBMS-aware applications\n2) To define APIs for MBMS User Services\n3) To establish connections between MBMS clients and media servers\n4) To provide access to MBMS broadcast bearers\n5) To control the media delivery format\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4683, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To simplify the integration of third-party MBMS-aware applications", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does BA stand for in the context of RRC? \n\nOptions:\n1) Base Station Antenna\n2) Baseband Alliance\n3) Broadcast Authorization\n4) Backoff Algorithm\n5) Bandwidth Adaptation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4687, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Bandwidth Adaptation", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat mobility is supported in handover with SRVCC operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Inter RAT mobility\n2) NR-E-UTRA mobility\n3) NR-UTRA mobility\n4) Intra 5GC mobility\n5) Handover from 5GC to EPC\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4688, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  NR-UTRA mobility", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following is a requirement for ranging-based services in the 5G system? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ability to authorize ranging for a UE or a group of UEs when using licensed spectrum.\n2) Ability to support energy efficient UE ranging operation.\n3) Ability to enable or disable ranging as per application layer demand.\n4) Ability to start and stop ranging according to the operator's control.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4704, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Ability to authorize ranging for a UE or a group of UEs when using licensed spectrum.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does EES service area specify? \n\nOptions:\n1) Access to the EEC\n2) Access to the EAS\n3) Access to the EDN\n4) The location of the UE within the network\n5) The location of the EES within the PLMN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4713, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The location of the EES within the PLMN", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is withdrawal in the context of the LCS client? \n\nOptions:\n1) An action to make the LCS feature available to a subscriber\n2) An action taken by the service provider to remove an available LCS feature from a LCS Client\u2019s subscription profile\n3) An action to invoke the LCS feature\n4) An action to bar the Location Service of a specific user\n5) An action to remove a privacy class from a target UE\u2019s PEL\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4714, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  An action taken by the service provider to remove an available LCS feature from a LCS Client\u2019s subscription profile", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the limitation of indirect data forwarding for the user plane in inter-System data forwarding from EPS to 5GS? \n\nOptions:\n1) It is only supported for downlink data\n2) It is only supported for uplink data\n3) End marker packets are not supported\n4) The QFI value is not added to the forwarded data\n5) End marker packets are not forwarded to the target NG-RAN node\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4718, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  End marker packets are not supported", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is provisioning in the context of the LCS client? \n\nOptions:\n1) An action to remove a privacy class from a target UE\u2019s PEL\n2) An action taken by the service provider to remove an available LCS feature from a LCS Client\u2019s subscription profile\n3) An action to invoke the LCS feature\n4) An action to bar the Location Service of a specific user\n5) An action to make the LCS feature available to a subscriber\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4725, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  An action to make the LCS feature available to a subscriber", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the Determination of Completeness of Charging Information in IMS? \n\nOptions:\n1) A method to identify all network elements generating CDR in IMS\n2) A method to determine the charging information collected from IMS entities\n3) A SIP parameter for tracking Network Elements and Application Servers in IMS\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4737, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main function of the NWDAF with Federated Learning (FL) capability? \n\nOptions:\n1) To discover and select FL client NWDAFs to participate in an FL procedure\n2) To train ML models and expose new training services\n3) To provide analytics to 5GC NFs and OAM\n4) To generate global ML models by aggregating local model information\n5) To discover and select NWDAFs containing MTLF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4755, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To discover and select FL client NWDAFs to participate in an FL procedure", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich reference point replaces the Gz reference point within the common charging architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Gy\n2) Rf\n3) Gzn\n4) Ro\n5) Ga\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4759, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Ga", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a UE monitor for detection of DCI format 0_0 or DCI format 1_0 with CRC scrambled by C-RNTI for scheduling respective PUSCH transmissions or PDSCH receptions? \n\nOptions:\n1) PDCCH according to Type1-PDCCH CSS set\n2) PRACH with SS/PBCH block index associated with the PUSCH transmission\n3) SS/PBCH block with the same index as the PRACH transmission\n4) PDCCH according to sdt-SearchSpace CSS set\n5) PDCCH according to the same CSS set as for PRACH transmission\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4762, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  PDCCH according to sdt-SearchSpace CSS set", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat do radiated performance requirements specify for the SAN type 1-O? \n\nOptions:\n1) The ability to correctly transmit and receive radiated signals in various conditions and configurations\n2) The ability to transmit radiated signals only\n3) The ability to receive radiated signals only\n4) The ability to detect radiated signals in various conditions and configurations\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4767, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The ability to correctly transmit and receive radiated signals in various conditions and configurations", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich transmission mode does the RLC sublayer use for SRB0, paging, and broadcast system information? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transparent Mode (TM)\n2) Unacknowledged Mode (UM)\n3) Acknowledged Mode (AM)\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4770, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Transparent Mode (TM)", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the uplink transmission scheme used for FDD and TDD? \n\nOptions:\n1) Single-tone transmission\n2) Multi-tone transmission\n3) DFTS-OFDM\n4) SC-FDMA\n5) OFDMA\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4784, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  SC-FDMA", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn network interconnection and protocol interworking, which cases require the use of MPS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Voice, video, and data services over EPS or 5GS\n2) Only voice services over EPS or 5GS\n3) Only data services over EPS or 5GS\n4) Data and video services over EPS or 5GS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4785, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Voice, video, and data services over EPS or 5GS", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of UE adaptation to BWP switching? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enhance the UE mobility\n2) To increase the data throughput\n3) To improve the network coverage\n4) To reduce the UE power consumption\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4789, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To reduce the UE power consumption", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is included in the cancellation of a PUSCH transmission for a serving cell? \n\nOptions:\n1) All symbols from the earliest symbol of the PUSCH transmission\n2) Symbols from the last symbol of the PDCCH reception\n3) Symbols indicated by delta_Offset\n4) Only symbols that are in one or more groups of symbols having corresponding bit values of '1'\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4803, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  All symbols from the earliest symbol of the PUSCH transmission", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Network notification objective introduced by MUSIM for LTE/NR? \n\nOptions:\n1) To address the paging occasion collision issue.\n2) To notify the network of a switch from one network to another for MUSIM purpose.\n3) To support indicating to the MUSIM UE whether an incoming paging is for voice service.\n4) To notify the network of a switch from network A for MUSIM purpose.\n5) To address the issue of network congestion during paging.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4812, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To notify the network of a switch from network A for MUSIM purpose.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat entity can be used for inference in the MDA process? \n\nOptions:\n1) NWDAF\n2) Data analytics function\n3) Network function\n4) Management function\n5) AI/ML inference function\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4813, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  AI/ML inference function", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identity is used for identification of Broadcast and System Information in the downlink? \n\nOptions:\n1) C-RNTI\n2) CI-RNTI\n3) CS-RNTI\n4) SI-RNTI\n5) P-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4817, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  SI-RNTI", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Traffic management requirements in the application layer architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support AF influence on traffic routing over N6 interface\n2) To be able to monitor the network status that may impact the application KPIs\n3) To support interactions with a lifecycle management system\n4) To provide mechanisms for the EAS to publish its KPIs or application level requirements\n5) To provide mechanisms to support service continuity such that the Application Context with a S-EAS is transferred to a T-EAS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4821, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To be able to monitor the network status that may impact the application KPIs", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Closed loop SLS Assurance solution in TS 28.535 and TS 28.536 provide? \n\nOptions:\n1) Advanced monitoring solutions for providing communication service quality\n2) Predictive analytics for optimizing network performance\n3) Provisioning capabilities for adjusting and optimizing services\n4) Configuring assurance goal based on network characteristics\n5) Collecting assurance goal status based on location\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4834, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Advanced monitoring solutions for providing communication service quality", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIs it possible for more than one LCS client to activate requests for the same target UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only for asset management services\n2) No, it is not possible\n3) Only in emergency scenarios\n4) Only if requested by the PLMN operator\n5) Yes, it is possible\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4837, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Yes, it is possible", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the distribution of the shadow fading? \n\nOptions:\n1) Uniform\n2) Exponential\n3) Log-normal\n4) Gaussian\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4840, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Log-normal", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Session-AMBR? \n\nOptions:\n1) To limit the aggregate bit rate of GBR flows\n2) To limit the aggregate bit rate of non-GBR flows\n3) To limit the aggregate bit rate across all non-GBR flows in a PDU session\n4) To limit the aggregate bit rate of all QoS flows in a PDU session\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4850, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To limit the aggregate bit rate across all non-GBR flows in a PDU session", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the TSCTSF do if a PTP instance does not exist for a matching PTP instance configuration? \n\nOptions:\n1) Configures a PTP port in DS-TT\n2) Activates or modifies the 5G access stratum time distribution\n3) Initializes the PTP instance in 5GS\n4) Stores the information in the UE Context\n5) Releases the AF-session with the PCF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4856, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Initializes the PTP instance in 5GS", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich services can support Data Collection Coordination and Delivery? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ndccf_DataManagement\n2) Nnwdaf_DataManagement\n3) Nmfaf_3daDataManagement\n4) Nmfaf_3caDataManagement\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4864, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is the SDT procedure initiated? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the network sends an RRCReject message.\n2) When the DL RSRP is below a configured threshold.\n3) When there is no valid SDT resource available.\n4) When the UE is in RRC_CONNECTED state.\n5) When there is a configured amount of UL data awaiting transmission across all radio bearers for which SDT is enabled.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4871, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  When there is a configured amount of UL data awaiting transmission across all radio bearers for which SDT is enabled.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of uncertainty assessment is performed for the measurement uncertainty budget of UE RF testing methodology? \n\nOptions:\n1) Static propagation conditions\n2) Multi-path fading propagation conditions\n3) Uncertainty assessment\n4) Polarization basis mismatch between the TE and DUT\n5) Inter-band (FR2+FR2) CA\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4873, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Uncertainty assessment", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following is NOT supported by PDCP packet duplication? \n\nOptions:\n1) Signalling Radio Bearers (SRBs) using RLC AM\n2) Data Radio Bearers (DRBs) using RLC UM\n3) Data Radio Bearers (DRBs) using RLC AM\n4) Carrier Aggregation (CA) scenarios\n5) Dual Connectivity (DC) scenarios\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4881, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Data Radio Bearers (DRBs) using RLC AM", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of Management Data Analytics Service (MDAS) in the MDA? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide analytics output\n2) To process and analyze data\n3) To consume data from AFs\n4) To enable resource provisioning\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4893, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide analytics output", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich uncertainty element is applicable to the CFFdeltaNF methodology? \n\nOptions:\n1) DUT antenna location estimation\n2) Probe antenna pattern\n3) EIRP measurement error in NF\n4) TRP measurement error in NF\n5) Influence of noise\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4903, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Influence of noise", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat options are available for deploying non-public networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) Completely standalone networks\n2) Hosted by a PLMN\n3) Offered as a slice of a PLMN\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4906, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen should a UE adjust the contention window size and the backoff counter for Type 1 channel access procedures? \n\nOptions:\n1) After sensing the channel to be busy\n2) After receiving an UL grant or an AUL-DFI with DCI format 0A\n3) After receiving an UL grant or an AUL-DFI with DCI format 1A\n4) After transmitting a PUCCH transmission\n5) After transmitting a PUSCH transmission\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4908, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  After receiving an UL grant or an AUL-DFI with DCI format 0A", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich entity takes precedence in determining the User Plane Security Policy? \n\nOptions:\n1) SMF\n2) PGW-C\n3) AMF\n4) UDM\n5) UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4918, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  UDM", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the SDP attribute 'ccc_list' allow for? \n\nOptions:\n1) Communication and negotiation of concurrent codec capabilities\n2) Enforcement of priority levels\n3) Authentication of users\n4) Management of network resources\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4921, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Communication and negotiation of concurrent codec capabilities", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the capability of the 5G system regarding an indirect network connection when the UE is in E-UTRAN or NG-RAN coverage? \n\nOptions:\n1) Unable to support an indirect network connection\n2) Able to support an indirect network connection only when the UE is in E-UTRAN coverage\n3) Able to support an indirect network connection only when the UE is in NG-RAN coverage\n4) Able to support an indirect network connection regardless of the type of coverage\n5) Able to support an indirect network connection only when the UE is in 5G coverage\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4924, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Able to support an indirect network connection regardless of the type of coverage", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich delivery option(s) are available in Data Delivery via the DCCF or NWDAF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Delivery via DCCF or NWDAF\n2) Delivery via Messaging Framework\n3) Delivery via both DCCF/NWDAF and Messaging Framework\n4) Delivery via Ndccf services\n5) Delivery via Nnwdaf services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4931, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Delivery via DCCF or NWDAF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich physical channel carries data from a UE for sidelink communication and V2X sidelink communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) PSBCH\n2) PSDCH\n3) PSCCH\n4) PSSCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4933, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  PSSCH", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does NWDAF provide to consumer NF or OAM based on the collected network data? \n\nOptions:\n1) QoS profile\n2) Service Experience predictions\n3) Service data\n4) Performance data\n5) Service Experience statistics\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4946, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Service Experience statistics", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does DNN stand for in the 5G System? \n\nOptions:\n1) Distinct Network Name\n2) Direct Network Node\n3) Default Network Node\n4) Dynamic Networking Node\n5) Data Network Name\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4955, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Data Network Name", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of mapping rules in the QoS architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) To map QoS flows to DRBs\n2) To establish PDU sessions\n3) To differentiate GBR and non-GBR flows\n4) To guarantee flow bit rate\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4957, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To map QoS flows to DRBs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the behavior of a mobile station in the MM IDLE state with service state NO IMSI? \n\nOptions:\n1) Perform normal location updating when a new location area is entered\n2) Perform default cell selection\n3) Not perform IMSI detach if powered down\n4) Reject any request from CM entities for MM connections except for emergency calls\n5) Only perform periodic updating\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4958, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Perform default cell selection", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the function of the Gateway GPRS Support Node (GGSN)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide support for interworking between a PLMN and fixed networks.\n2) To terminate the interface towards the E-UTRAN.\n3) To provide support for mobility between 3GPP access networks.\n4) To provide support for the control plane entity within EPS.\n5) To handle circuit switched services to and from mobile stations.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4959, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide support for interworking between a PLMN and fixed networks.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the uplink buffer status reports (BSR)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide support for QoS-aware packet scheduling\n2) To allocate resources for the initial HARQ transmissions to UEs\n3) To enable coordination of TDM and FDM cell resources between MAC in the gNB and the corresponding entity in the ng-eNB\n4) To enable fast SCell activation when CA is configured\n5) To provide support for power-aware packet scheduling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4972, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide support for QoS-aware packet scheduling", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere can additional information about the regional provision of service be found? \n\nOptions:\n1) 3GPP TS 24.008\n2) 3GPP TS 24.301\n3) 3GPP TS 24.501\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4977, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is not required in the roaming architecture for interworking between 5GS and EPC? \n\nOptions:\n1) N26 interface\n2) S9 interface\n3) N9 interface\n4) S10 interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4981, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  S9 interface", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the minimum requirement for OTA occupied bandwidth for each carrier? \n\nOptions:\n1) It must be greater than the SAN channel bandwidth.\n2) It must be less than the SAN channel bandwidth.\n3) It must be equal to the SAN channel bandwidth.\n4) It must be within \u00b12 dB of the rated carrier TRP output power.\n5) It must be accurate to within 0.05 ppm observed over 1 ms.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 4992, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  It must be less than the SAN channel bandwidth.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of mutual ranging in the 5G system? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable roaming UEs to perform ranging.\n2) To determine if another ranging enabled UE is stationary or mobile.\n3) To start and stop ranging according to the application layer demand.\n4) To enable two UEs to initiate ranging to each other.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5001, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To enable two UEs to initiate ranging to each other.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich state exists when the network has received an answer but the network has not yet awarded the call? \n\nOptions:\n1) Connect request (N8)\n2) Mobile terminating call confirmed (N9)\n3) Active (N10)\n4) Disconnect indication (N12)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5003, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Connect request (N8)", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of charging data correlation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To identify the charging events generated by CTF.\n2) To aggregate charging information for the same charging session.\n3) To collect charging data for supplementary service activity.\n4) To provide an association of charging information for the mobile subscriber's resource usage.\n5) To combine the charging events generated by different CTFs for the same service.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5008, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To provide an association of charging information for the mobile subscriber's resource usage.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich entity is responsible for providing the Candidate-UE filtering policy to the AF? \n\nOptions:\n1) AMF\n2) UPF\n3) eNEF\n4) SMF\n5) AF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5010, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  eNEF", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can UE power saving be achieved in RRC_IDLE/RRC_INACTIVE? \n\nOptions:\n1) By configuring TRS with CSI-RS\n2) By relaxing RLM/BFD measurements\n3) By utilizing PDCCH skipping\n4) By enabling cross-slot scheduling\n5) By configuring low mobility state\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5034, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  By relaxing RLM/BFD measurements", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich measurements are performed for intra- and inter-frequency handover? \n\nOptions:\n1) Inter-RAT handover measurements\n2) Radio characteristics measurements\n3) Timing measurements\n4) Measurements for RRM\n5) Measurements for positioning\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5056, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Radio characteristics measurements", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the key functionality introduced for scheduling enhancements in the 5G Core network? \n\nOptions:\n1) Support for multiple active configured grant configurations for a BWP\n2) Support for accurate reference timing delivery\n3) Support for prioritization between overlapping uplink resources of one UE\n4) Support for up to eight simultaneously active semi-persistent scheduling (SPS) configurations\n5) Support for PDCP packet duplication enhancements\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5060, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Support for up to eight simultaneously active semi-persistent scheduling (SPS) configurations", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat 5G system feature allows utilization of new functionalities provided by the 5G-CN using the LTE radio interface? \n\nOptions:\n1) EPC enhancements to support 5G New Radio via Dual Connectivity\n2) LTE connectivity to 5G-CN\n3) Security aspects of the 5G System - Phase 1\n4) Charging and OAM aspects of 5G System - Phase 1\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5062, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  LTE connectivity to 5G-CN", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is handed over to the target RAT in handover with SRVCC operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) All bearers except the voice bearer\n2) All data bearers\n3) Control plane data\n4) User plane data\n5) Only voice bearer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5065, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Only voice bearer", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn what market sector are 3GPP networks expected to become an important tool? \n\nOptions:\n1) Global revenues\n2) AV content production\n3) Mass audiences\n4) Mobile consumption\n5) Custom-tailored services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5067, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  AV content production", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of EXT_UED? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide a regulatory framework for sharing spectrum between Mobile Network Operators and Incumbents\n2) To provide a charging architecture for proximity-based services\n3) To test the delay of mobile terminals\n4) To define security assurance requirements for network elements\n5) To extend terminal delay test methods and requirements\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5075, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To extend terminal delay test methods and requirements", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Permanent Equipment Identifier (PEI)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support user confidentiality protection\n2) To enable roaming scenarios\n3) To address a 3GPP subscription in different data networks\n4) To uniquely identify the UE within the AMF\n5) To identify the user equipment accessing the 5G System\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5079, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To identify the user equipment accessing the 5G System", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the NWDAF discovery and selection process? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide analytics information to 5GC NFs and OAM\n2) To train ML models and expose new training services\n3) To select an NWDAF instance based on required analytics capabilities\n4) To register NWDAF profiles in the NRF\n5) To determine the accuracy of analytics output\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5083, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To select an NWDAF instance based on required analytics capabilities", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat identifiers can be used by the LCS client to identify a target UE for value-added services? \n\nOptions:\n1) MSISDN\n2) SIP URL\n3) IMSI\n4) An identifier internal to the PLMN\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5084, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does NEF translate into a SUPI or Internal-Group-Id? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE location information\n2) GPSI or External-Group-Id\n3) Service Experience Contribution Weight\n4) Network Slice instance\n5) Area of Interest\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5085, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  GPSI or External-Group-Id", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following is true about cell reselection between NR RRC_IDLE and E-UTRA RRC_IDLE? \n\nOptions:\n1) It is not supported\n2) It is supported for handover to UTRA only\n3) It is supported for both handover to UTRA and NR\n4) It is supported for handover to NR only\n5) It is supported for handover to E-UTRA only\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5087, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  It is supported for both handover to UTRA and NR", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat message does the UE respond with after receiving the RRCSetup message? \n\nOptions:\n1) RRC_CONNECTION_SETUP_COMPLETE\n2) SecurityModeCommand\n3) SecurityModeComplete\n4) RRCReconfiguration\n5) UE CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5091, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  SecurityModeComplete", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is AKMA in the context of 5G security? \n\nOptions:\n1) A secure tunnel between the end user and the application server\n2) A cellular network-based authentication system\n3) A tamper-resistant smart card\n4) A delegated authentication system\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5108, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  A cellular network-based authentication system", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used for inter-eNB control plane signaling in Dual Connectivity? \n\nOptions:\n1) X2 interface\n2) S1 interface\n3) S5 interface\n4) SGi interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5112, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  X2 interface", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is notification of SC-MCCH change indicated in NB-IoT? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through a separate change notification message\n2) Through a specific SC-N-RNTI\n3) Directly in the DCIs which schedule SC-MCCH and SC-MTCH\n4) Through explicit signaling in the PRACH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5114, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Directly in the DCIs which schedule SC-MCCH and SC-MTCH", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of collecting and processing charging data in the serving network? \n\nOptions:\n1) To establish inter-network settlement\n2) To enable real-time charging for users\n3) To prevent fraud in the network\n4) To allow further processing by the billing system in the Home Environment\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5128, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To allow further processing by the billing system in the Home Environment", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of steering of roaming for a multi-mode terminal? \n\nOptions:\n1) To select a specific VPLMN as the highest priority\n2) To search for a higher prioritized PLMN that does not offer CS voice service\n3) To direct the UE to register on a different VPLMN\n4) To ensure compliance with 3GPP specifications\n5) To avoid ping-pong between systems\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5129, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To direct the UE to register on a different VPLMN", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the SMF do before retrieving PFDs from the NEF (PFDF)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Checks if PFDs are available in SMF\n2) Subscribes to PFD notifications\n3) Fetches PFD information from UDR\n4) Invokes Nnef_PFDManagement_Create/Update/Delete service\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5135, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Subscribes to PFD notifications", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main service and function of the SDAP sublayer? \n\nOptions:\n1) Mapping between logical channels and transport channels\n2) Error correction through HARQ\n3) Compression and decompression of headers\n4) Mapping between a QoS flow and a data radio bearer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5145, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Mapping between a QoS flow and a data radio bearer", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nDuring which network life cycle phase do mobile network operators compare network elements from various vendors for EE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Buy phase\n2) Design/Build phase\n3) Run phase\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5150, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Buy phase", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does redundant transmission at the transport layer in URLLC require? \n\nOptions:\n1) Support for IEEE FRER protocol in the application layer.\n2) Redundant GTP-U tunnel over N3 between UPF and NG-RAN.\n3) Two disjoint transport paths between UPF and NG-RAN.\n4) Synchronization between NG-RAN and PSA UPF.\n5) Specific 3GPP protocol impact.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5151, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Two disjoint transport paths between UPF and NG-RAN.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used to carry packet data transmission and mobility management between the SGSN and BSS? \n\nOptions:\n1) A-interface\n2) Iu_CS interface\n3) Gb-interface\n4) Um-interface\n5) Iu_PS-interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5155, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Gb-interface", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the main functionalities of the Enhancement of support for Edge Computing feature in the 5G Core network? \n\nOptions:\n1) Discovery and re-discovery of Edge Application Server, Edge relocation, Network exposure to EAS, Support of 3GPP application layer architecture, AF guidance to PCF determination of URSP rules\n2) Discovery and re-discovery of Edge Application Server, Network exposure to EAS, Support of 3GPP application layer architecture\n3) Edge relocation, Network exposure to EAS, AF guidance to PCF determination of URSP rules\n4) Network exposure to EAS, Support of 3GPP application layer architecture, AF guidance to PCF determination of URSP rules\n5) Discovery and re-discovery of Edge Application Server, Edge relocation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5156, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Discovery and re-discovery of Edge Application Server, Edge relocation, Network exposure to EAS, Support of 3GPP application layer architecture, AF guidance to PCF determination of URSP rules", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of DNN based congestion control? \n\nOptions:\n1) To avoid and handle NAS SM signalling congestion for UEs with a back-off timer associated with or without a DNN\n2) To restrict requests from UEs for data transmission via Control Plane CIoT 5GS Optimization\n3) To balance the load between UEs associated with an Internal-Group Identifier\n4) To restrict requests from UEs for Session Management procedures\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5162, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To avoid and handle NAS SM signalling congestion for UEs with a back-off timer associated with or without a DNN", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the abilities provided by subscription-related priority mechanisms? \n\nOptions:\n1) Invoking, modifying, and maintaining QoS Flows with priority\n2) Classifying and differentiating specific services\n3) Delivering QoS Flow packets according to the QoS characteristics\n4) Establishing prioritized QoS Flows\n5) Preserving differentiated treatment for prioritized QoS Flow and resource distribution prioritization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5165, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Invoking, modifying, and maintaining QoS Flows with priority", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich reference signals can be used for NR carrier phase positioning? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only MIMO SRS\n2) Existing DL PRS and UL SRS\n3) DL PRS of a target TRP\n4) DL PRS of a reference TRP\n5) Only UL SRS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5174, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Existing DL PRS and UL SRS", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is expected in terms of unauthorized UEs accessing non-public networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) Unauthorized UEs are expected to attempt to access non-public networks\n2) Unauthorized UEs are expected not to attempt to access non-public networks\n3) Unauthorized UEs are expected to access non-public networks after being rejected\n4) Unauthorized UEs are expected to access non-public networks after being authorized\n5) Unauthorized UEs are expected to access non-public networks after being restricted\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5183, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Unauthorized UEs are expected not to attempt to access non-public networks", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat was the initial purpose of 3GPP Public Warning Systems specified in Release 8? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide a platform for MBMS capabilities in UEs\n2) To enhance the comprehension of Warning Notifications for users with disabilities\n3) To support Mission Critical Services\n4) To improve the language-dependent Warning Notifications\n5) To allow for direct warnings to be sent to mobile users\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5195, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To allow for direct warnings to be sent to mobile users", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the conclusion regarding PRS/SRS bandwidth aggregation for intra-band contiguous carriers? \n\nOptions:\n1) It is not feasible for single chain Tx/Rx architectures at both the UE and gNB.\n2) It is feasible for single chain Tx/Rx architectures at both the UE and gNB.\n3) It is feasible only for gNB but not for UE.\n4) It is feasible only for UE but not for gNB.\n5) It is feasible for multi-chain Tx/Rx architectures at both the UE and gNB.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5197, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  It is feasible for single chain Tx/Rx architectures at both the UE and gNB.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat security mechanism is used for securing the V3 interface between the UE and the V2X Control Function? \n\nOptions:\n1) PKI TLS with GBA\n2) PSK TLS with SSL\n3) PSK TLS with GBA\n4) PKI TLS with SSL\n5) VPN with SSL\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5198, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  PSK TLS with GBA", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWho can the AF belong to? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only the operator\n2) Only a third party\n3) Both the operator and a third party\n4) Only the PCF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5204, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both the operator and a third party", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does CFI stand for in the context of LTE_HRLLC? \n\nOptions:\n1) Controlled Format Indicator\n2) Controlled Frequency Indicator\n3) Control Format Indicator\n4) Control Frequency Indicator\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5210, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Control Format Indicator", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the meaning of the tag 'Otherwise, the field is absent, Need R'? \n\nOptions:\n1) The field should not be configured when this part of the condition applies\n2) The field is released if absent when this part of the condition applies\n3) The UE retains the field if it was already configured when this part of the condition applies\n4) The field is not relevant and should be absent in this part of the condition\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5219, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The field is released if absent when this part of the condition applies", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of AnLF in analytics accuracy monitoring? \n\nOptions:\n1) To determine ML Model degradation\n2) To provide ground truth data\n3) To provide or notify accuracy information to analytics consumers\n4) To generate updated analytics\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5228, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To provide or notify accuracy information to analytics consumers", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the time-domain structure of an SS/PBCH block? \n\nOptions:\n1) An SS/PBCH block consists of 4 OFDM symbols numbered from 0 to 3.\n2) An SS/PBCH block consists of 6 OFDM symbols numbered from 0 to 5.\n3) An SS/PBCH block consists of 8 OFDM symbols numbered from 0 to 7.\n4) An SS/PBCH block consists of 10 OFDM symbols numbered from 0 to 9.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5232, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  An SS/PBCH block consists of 4 OFDM symbols numbered from 0 to 3.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat control does the UE subscriber have over privacy for value-added services? \n\nOptions:\n1) No control\n2) Partial control\n3) Full control\n4) Control only for emergency services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5244, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Full control", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich type of PRAs information is provisioned by the PCRF/OCS to the MME each time the IP-CAN session is established? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE dedicated PRA\n2) Predefined PRA\n3) PRA set\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5246, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  UE dedicated PRA", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NWDAF provide in the response or notification on 'QoS Sustainability'? \n\nOptions:\n1) QoS requirements\n2) QoS statistics\n3) QoS change statistics and Reporting Threshold(s)\n4) Predictions for potential QoS changes\n5) Both QoS statistics and predictions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5247, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  QoS change statistics and Reporting Threshold(s)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION REQUEST message include in the intra-CU topology adaptation procedure in SA? \n\nOptions:\n1) A generated RRCReconfiguration message and indications to stop data transmission to the UE.\n2) Full configuration information and stop data transmission indications to the UE.\n3) A HandoverPreparationInformation and RRCReconfiguration message.\n4) Full configuration information and Downlink Data Delivery Status frame.\n5) A generated RRCReconfiguration message and Downlink Data Delivery Status frame.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5255, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  A generated RRCReconfiguration message and indications to stop data transmission to the UE.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is UE-Assisted Location Calculation based upon? \n\nOptions:\n1) Network resources based on Wi-Fi signal strength\n2) Network resources based on GPS measurements\n3) Network resources based on cellular tower triangulation\n4) Network resources based on radio ranging measurements provided by the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5259, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Network resources based on radio ranging measurements provided by the UE", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the mapping process for non-interleaved VRB-to-PRB mapping? \n\nOptions:\n1) Virtual resource block V is mapped to physical resource block P\n2) Virtual resource block V is mapped to physical resource block P+V\n3) Virtual resource block V is mapped to physical resource block P+2V\n4) Virtual resource block V is mapped to physical resource block P+3V\n5) Virtual resource block V is mapped to physical resource block P+4V\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5262, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Virtual resource block V is mapped to physical resource block P", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does Invocation-to-Release Priority Treatment include? \n\nOptions:\n1) Priority treatment during session release only\n2) Priority treatment during session invocation only\n3) Priority treatment during both session invocation and release\n4) Priority treatment during network interconnection\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5264, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Priority treatment during both session invocation and release", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does MnS component type B refer to? \n\nOptions:\n1) Generic operations and notifications\n2) Performance information of the managed entity and fault information\n3) Management information represented by information models\n4) Management services provided by an MnS producer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5275, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Management information represented by information models", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of charging data transfer in converged charging? \n\nOptions:\n1) To transfer charging events from CTF to CDF via Rf.\n2) To transfer charging events from CGF to BD via Bx.\n3) To transfer charging events from CTF to OCF via Ro.\n4) To transfer charging events from CTF or CEF to CHF via Nchf.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5282, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To transfer charging events from CTF or CEF to CHF via Nchf.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information is included in the request for PDU Session traffic analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) SUPI or a list of SUPIs or an Internal-Group-Id or any UE.\n2) Application Identifier, IP Descriptions or Domain Descriptors.\n3) Area of Interest, S-NSSAI, DNN.\n4) All of the above.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5317, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the enhancement of the 3GPP management system? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enhance the network slicing interworking support from EPC to 5GC\n2) To enhance the performance assurance for 5G networks\n3) To enable a 3GPP system to support various business role models for network slicing\n4) To provide multi-tenancy support in the 3GPP management system\n5) To enhance the performance measurements and KPIs in 5G networks\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5318, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To provide multi-tenancy support in the 3GPP management system", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the physical layer signals used for RAT-dependent positioning solutions in NR? \n\nOptions:\n1) DL Positioning Reference Signals (DL PRS) and UL Sounding Reference Signals (SRS)\n2) DL Positioning Reference Signals (DL PRS) and UL Sounding Reference Signals (SRS) for positioning\n3) UL Sounding Reference Signals (SRS) and Downlink Time Difference of Arrival (DL TDOA)\n4) Uplink Time Difference of Arrival (UL TDOA) and Uplink Angle of Arrival (UL AoA)\n5) Uplink Time Difference of Arrival (UL TDOA) and Downlink Angle of Departure (DL AoD)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5320, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  DL Positioning Reference Signals (DL PRS) and UL Sounding Reference Signals (SRS) for positioning", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UE assume about the DL PRS from the serving cell? \n\nOptions:\n1) It is mapped to symbols that contain SS/PBCH block from the serving cell\n2) It is not mapped to symbols that contain SS/PBCH block from the serving cell\n3) It is mapped to all symbols within a slot\n4) It is mapped to specific PRBs\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5325, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  It is not mapped to symbols that contain SS/PBCH block from the serving cell", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when an IP packet arrives at the UPF for a UE that is CM-IDLE? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE sends a Data Notification to the SMF.\n2) The SMF sends a Paging Priority to the AMF.\n3) The UPF sends a Data Notification to the SMF.\n4) The AMF updates the ARP for the Signalling QoS Flows.\n5) The SMF updates the ARP for the Signalling QoS Flows.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5329, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The UPF sends a Data Notification to the SMF.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the three factors that govern the PDCCH monitoring activity of the UE in RRC connected mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) DRX, BA, and DCP\n2) RRC_IDLE, RRC_INACTIVE, and RRM\n3) MIMO, PUSCH, and CSI-RS\n4) SSSG, BWP, and TRS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5341, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  DRX, BA, and DCP", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the enhancements for high capacity stationary wireless link and introduction of 1024 QAM for LTE DL? \n\nOptions:\n1) To improve network efficiency in small cell settings with higher SINR\n2) To enhance spectral efficiency and peak data rates for DL channels\n3) To support advanced antenna configurations for high capacity wireless connections\n4) To reduce interference and improve link adaption in non-coherent joint transmission\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5359, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To enhance spectral efficiency and peak data rates for DL channels", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the key principles of user plane handling for inter-System data forwarding from 5GS to EPS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Direct data forwarding of uplink data is supported\n2) Only forwarding of uplink data is supported\n3) PDU session information at the serving NG-RAN node contains mapping information per QoS Flow to a corresponding DRB\n4) Handling of end marker packets is not supported\n5) Data forwarding tunnel is established only when there is FR1 cell\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5369, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  PDU session information at the serving NG-RAN node contains mapping information per QoS Flow to a corresponding DRB", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of network exposure to the Edge Application Server (EAS)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To bypass the SMF and the PCF and report QoS monitoring directly to the EAS\n2) To support low latency network exposure to local AF\n3) To enable the local NEF to report QoS monitoring results to the AF\n4) To trigger UE mobility and AF relocation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5370, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To support low latency network exposure to local AF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere is the PCI Optimization Function specified? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.501\n2) TS 36.300\n3) TS 38.300\n4) TS 38.305\n5) TS 38.400\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5379, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS 38.300", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich component provides the Nudr_DM_Query response? \n\nOptions:\n1) AF\n2) NEF\n3) UDR\n4) SMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5380, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  UDR", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich work item specifies the use cases and requirements for management of measurements for cross-operator accounting? \n\nOptions:\n1) OAM14-MAMO_VNF-CM\n2) OAM14-MAMO_VNF-FM\n3) OAM14-MAMO_VNF-PM\n4) OAM14-FILMEAS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5387, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  OAM14-FILMEAS", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the key features for LTE to provide voice service over 2/3G CS domain? \n\nOptions:\n1) VoLTE/ViLTE signaling optimization\n2) UL asynchronous HARQ transmission\n3) RAN-assisted codec adaptation\n4) Bundle frequency hopping\n5) Robust Call Setup for VoLTE subscriber in LTE (RobVoLTE)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5389, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Robust Call Setup for VoLTE subscriber in LTE (RobVoLTE)", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is used for power control in sidelink? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transmit power control commands\n2) Pathloss between communicating UEs\n3) Received signal strength\n4) Pathloss from the gNB\n5) Timing Advance\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5392, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Pathloss from the gNB", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the main services and functions of the RRC sublayer over the Uu interface? \n\nOptions:\n1) Broadcast of System Information related to AS and NAS\n2) Paging initiated by 5GC or NG-RAN\n3) Establishment, maintenance and release of an RRC connection between the UE and NG-RAN\n4) Security functions including key management\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5409, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the X2 interface in Dual Connectivity? \n\nOptions:\n1) To establish control plane signaling between eNBs\n2) To transfer user plane data from the MeNB to the SeNB\n3) To support communication between the MeNB and the MME\n4) To handle UEs independently\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5416, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To establish control plane signaling between eNBs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the HandoverCommand message? \n\nOptions:\n1) To transfer the SCG radio configuration for one or more candidate cells for Conditional PSCell Addition (CPA) or Conditional PSCell Change (CPC)\n2) To transfer the handover command as generated by the target gNB\n3) To transfer the NR RRC information used by the target gNB during handover preparation or UE context retrieval\n4) To transfer the radio paging information, covering both upload to and download from the 5GC, and between gNBs\n5) To transfer UE radio access capability information, covering both upload to and download from the 5GC\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5420, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To transfer the handover command as generated by the target gNB", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is slice specific RACH configuration? \n\nOptions:\n1) The allocation of resources to a slice in case of slice resources shortage\n2) The configuration of RACH partitioning and prioritization parameters per NSAG\n3) The NSAG mechanism for slice aware cell reselection\n4) The support of service continuity for specific slice(s)\n5) The enforcement of Slice MBR and usage of Target NSSAI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5427, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The configuration of RACH partitioning and prioritization parameters per NSAG", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NAS-SM support in the control plane between the UE and the SMF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Handling of Session Management between the UE and the SMF\n2) Interpretation of SM signalling messages by the AMF\n3) Creating and processing of SM signalling messages by the AMF\n4) Transport of SM signalling messages between the UE and the AMF\n5) Decryption and encryption of SM signalling messages by the AMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5435, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Handling of Session Management between the UE and the SMF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich state exists when the mobile station has received an indication that remote user alerting has been initiated? \n\nOptions:\n1) Call delivered (U4)\n2) Call present (U6)\n3) Call received (U7)\n4) Connect Request (U8)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5445, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Call delivered (U4)", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the term for the interference between UL and DL transmissions in different cells due to atmospheric ducting? \n\nOptions:\n1) RIM interference\n2) Backhaul-based interference\n3) CLI interference\n4) Remote interference\n5) Semi-static interference\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5451, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Remote interference", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich legacy protocols can be used for the interfaces between SMSF/UDM and SMS-GMSC/SMS-IWMSC/IP-SM-GW/SMS Router? \n\nOptions:\n1) MAP and TSN\n2) Diameter and Ethernet\n3) MAP and Diameter\n4) SMS and IP\n5) TSN and Ethernet\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5452, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  MAP and Diameter", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum value for the false alarm probability for NPRACH detection? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.1%\n2) 1%\n3) 5%\n4) 10%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5454, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  0.1%", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does reliability measure in positioning requests? \n\nOptions:\n1) Positioning accuracy\n2) Response time\n3) Success rate of positioning requests\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5458, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Success rate of positioning requests", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many user priority levels are supported by the 3GPP network? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1\n2) 3\n3) 5\n4) 10\n5) n\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5459, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  5", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does NF stand for in the context of 5G architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) New Frame\n2) Network Function\n3) Non-Functional\n4) Next Generation System\n5) Network Fragmentation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5462, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Network Function", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the reference point for measurement of EVM? \n\nOptions:\n1) Before the FFT processing window in the receiver\n2) After the FFT processing window and a zero-forcing (ZF) equalizer in the receiver\n3) After the FFT processing window and a filtering operation in the receiver\n4) Before the FFT processing window and a zero-forcing (ZF) equalizer in the receiver\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5463, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  After the FFT processing window and a zero-forcing (ZF) equalizer in the receiver", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow long can the SDT procedure last? \n\nOptions:\n1) As long as there is data to transmit.\n2) Until the DL RSRP goes below a configured threshold.\n3) Until a SDT failure detection timer expires.\n4) Until the UE transitions to RRC_IDLE state.\n5) Until the network sends an RRCRelease message.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5467, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Until a SDT failure detection timer expires.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when a remote non-PLMN user initiates call rearrangements? \n\nOptions:\n1) The network sends a MODIFY message to the mobile station\n2) The network informs the mobile station by means of a NOTIFY message\n3) The network initiates an inter-system handover to UTRAN Iu mode\n4) The network releases the call\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5476, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The network informs the mobile station by means of a NOTIFY message", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the function of an eNodeB? \n\nOptions:\n1) Control of one or more Node B\n2) Communicating with Mobile Stations in a certain area\n3) Serve one cell\n4) Serve one or more E-UTRAN cells\n5) Provide the E-UTRA user plane and control plane protocol terminations towards the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5477, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Serve one or more E-UTRAN cells", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the N4 Session Establishment procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) To create the initial N4 session context for a PDU Session at the SMF\n2) To create the initial N4 session context for a PDU Session at the UPF\n3) To modify the N4 session context of an existing PDU Session at the SMF\n4) To modify the N4 session context of an existing PDU Session at the UPF\n5) To remove the N4 session context of an existing PDU Session at the SMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5485, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To create the initial N4 session context for a PDU Session at the UPF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich modulation scheme is used for the single codeword on the Physical Sidelink Broadcast Channel (PSBCH)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Frequency Shift Keying (FSK)\n2) Binary Phase Shift Keying (BPSK)\n3) Quadrature Amplitude Modulation (QAM)\n4) Orthogonal Frequency Division Multiplexing (OFDM)\n5) Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5486, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Quadrature Phase Shift Keying (QPSK)", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information is broadcasted in the system information for slice aware cell reselection? \n\nOptions:\n1) S-NSSAI\n2) NSAG\n3) NSSRG\n4) S-MBR\n5) Slice-Maximum Bit Rate\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5490, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  NSAG", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat capability should the 5G system provide for a UE to assist another UE in ranging of a third UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Capability to determine if another ranging enabled UE is stationary or mobile.\n2) Capability to provision and manage ranging operation and configurations.\n3) Capability to perform distance and/or angle measurement.\n4) Capability to support roaming UEs in performing ranging.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5491, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Capability to perform distance and/or angle measurement.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the recommended bitrate conveyed from the eNB to the UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Via RRC signaling\n2) Through SR counters\n3) Using a MAC Control Element (CE)\n4) By direct modulation\n5) Via S1 interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5493, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Using a MAC Control Element (CE)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the symbol duration determined by a UE for PDCCH monitoring? \n\nOptions:\n1) The smallest SCS configuration provided in scs-SpecificCarrierList\n2) The SCS configuration of the PDCCH\n3) The number of contiguous RBs in frequencyRegionforCI\n4) The number of symbols per slot\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5496, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The smallest SCS configuration provided in scs-SpecificCarrierList", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the IMS Multimedia Telephony service? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide multimedia conversational communications between two or more users\n2) To support roaming and time/date association of services\n3) To allow users to add and delete identities for outgoing communications\n4) To deliver identity information based on the originating network's caller identity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5502, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide multimedia conversational communications between two or more users", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many consecutive sub-carriers form a Physical Resource Block (PRB)? \n\nOptions:\n1) 6\n2) 8\n3) 10\n4) 12\n5) 14\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5518, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  12", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich types of emergency calls are possible? \n\nOptions:\n1) Police\n2) Ambulance\n3) Fire Brigade\n4) Marine Guard\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5531, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich synchronization signals does a UE receive to perform cell search? \n\nOptions:\n1) Primary synchronization signal (PSS) only\n2) Secondary synchronization signal (SSS) only\n3) Both primary and secondary synchronization signals\n4) Physical broadcast channel (PBCH) only\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5542, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both primary and secondary synchronization signals", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat should be supported for end-to-end codec negotiation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Compression\n2) Decoding\n3) Encoding\n4) Transcoding\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5547, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Transcoding", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich document specifies the system procedures for EPS? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS\u00a023.003\n2) TS\u00a023.401\n3) TS\u00a023.501\n4) TS\u00a024.301\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5548, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  TS\u00a023.401", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the size of a PDCP SDU in E-UTRA? \n\nOptions:\n1) 8188 octets\n2) 9000 octets\n3) 10000 octets\n4) 12000 octets\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5551, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  8188 octets", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is priority treatment applied in MPS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only after the MPS session is released\n2) During the invocation and session establishment and until the MPS session is released\n3) Before the invocation\n4) Only during the invocation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5557, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  During the invocation and session establishment and until the MPS session is released", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat accuracy of relative lateral positioning does the 3GPP system support according to requirement R.5.1-007? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.1 m\n2) 0.5 m\n3) 1 m\n4) 5 m\n5) 10 m\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5581, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  0.1 m", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when a gNB intends to transmit a transmission(s) on a set of channels at the same time? \n\nOptions:\n1) The gNB cannot transmit a transmission(s) on multiple channels simultaneously.\n2) The gNB performs sensing on each channel independently.\n3) The gNB combines the channels into a single channel for transmission.\n4) The gNB performs channel access procedures on each channel independently.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5582, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The gNB performs channel access procedures on each channel independently.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Nadrf_MLModelManagement_StorageRequest service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To request the ADRF to store or update ML models\n2) To request the ADRF to retrieve stored ML models\n3) To request the ADRF to delete stored ML models\n4) To request the ADRF to retrieve stored ML model addresses\n5) To request the ADRF to delete stored ML model addresses\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5592, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To request the ADRF to store or update ML models", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is supported for handover between gNB and ng-eNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) In-sequence and lossless handover\n2) Security procedures for handover to E-UTRA/EPC\n3) Xn and NG based inter-RAT handover\n4) Direct data forwarding path\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5601, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Xn and NG based inter-RAT handover", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich layer of NR is split into sublayers such as MAC, RLC, PDCP, and SDAP? \n\nOptions:\n1) Layer 1\n2) Layer 2\n3) Layer 3\n4) Layer 4\n5) Layer 5\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5606, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Layer 2", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the measurement period for EVM in E-UTRA? \n\nOptions:\n1) 10 ms\n2) 1 subframe (1 ms)\n3) 1 millisecond\n4) 1 second\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5607, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  10 ms", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nBesides the short service definition and description of normal operation, what other information is provided for each supplementary service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Exceptional operation or unsuccessful outcome\n2) Interworking with other supplementary services\n3) Interaction with PSTN/ISDN and CS mobile networks\n4) Consideration for interworking with CS mobile and fixed services\n5) Mandatory or optional support based on regulations\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5608, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Consideration for interworking with CS mobile and fixed services", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Physical Downlink Shared Channel (PDSCH)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transmit data themselves\n2) Carry HARQ feedback over the sidelink\n3) Carry control information for HARQ procedures\n4) Carry CSI measurement\n5) Indicate resource and other transmission parameters\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5611, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Transmit data themselves", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWill the UE configuration of enabled/disabled radio technologies remain the same after a power-cycle or when the USIM is disabled? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes\n2) No\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5613, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Yes", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the spatial filter in generating TDL channel models? \n\nOptions:\n1) To generate channel coefficients\n2) To represent different channel profiles for NLOS\n3) To evaluate directional algorithms\n4) To apply beamforming\n5) To calculate the K-factor\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5614, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To apply beamforming", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many consecutive sub-carriers correspond to one uplink resource block? \n\nOptions:\n1) 2\n2) 3\n3) 6\n4) 12\n5) 24\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5620, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  12", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the total layer 2 buffer size for NR SL? \n\nOptions:\n1) MaxSLtxDataRate * RLC RTT + MaxSLrxDataRate * RLC RTT\n2) MaxULDataRate_SN * RLCRTT_SN + MaxDLDataRate_SN * RLCRTT_SN + MaxDLDataRate_MN * (RLCRTT_SN + X2/Xn delay + Queuing in SN)\n3) MaxULDataRate_MN * RLCRTT_MN + MaxULDataRate_SN * RLCRTT_SN + MaxDLDataRate_SN * (RLCRTT_MN + X2/Xn delay + Queuing in MN)\n4) MaxULDataRate_MN * RLCRTT_MN + MaxULDataRate_SN * RLCRTT_SN + MaxDLDataRate_MN * RLCRTT_MN + MaxDLDataRate_SN * (RLCRTT_MN + X2/Xn delay + Queuing in MN)\n5) MaxSLtxDataRate * RLCRTT_SN + MaxSLrxDataRate * RLCRTT_SN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5624, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  MaxSLtxDataRate * RLC RTT + MaxSLrxDataRate * RLC RTT", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich sectors or industries can use the 5G system? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transport and logistics\n2) Automotive and other transport\n3) Public Safety\n4) Health and wellness\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5625, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the HSNA Slot Configuration List in gNB-DU Cell Resource Configuration? \n\nOptions:\n1) Indicate the availability of hard, soft, or unavailable symbols in a slot\n2) Configure the slot format for an IAB-DU\n3) Provide indicators for inter-donor NR-DC operation\n4) Configure the transmission power of an IAB-DU\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5630, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Indicate the availability of hard, soft, or unavailable symbols in a slot", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat modulation schemes are supported for the PUCCH format 1? \n\nOptions:\n1) BPSK and QPSK.\n2) BPSK and 16-QAM.\n3) QPSK and 16-QAM.\n4) QPSK and 64-QAM.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5632, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  BPSK and QPSK.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Federated Learning (FL) in the NWDAF? \n\nOptions:\n1) To discover and select NWDAFs containing MTLF\n2) To provide ML models to FL client NWDAFs\n3) To perform local model training without sharing local data set\n4) To generate global ML models by aggregating local model information\n5) To request analytics or input data from RE-NWDAF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5638, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To perform local model training without sharing local data set", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich release of the 3GPP system contains substantial enhancements for delivering TV services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Release 14\n2) Release 10\n3) Release 6\n4) Release 12\n5) Release 8\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5644, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Release 14", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the steps needed to generate TDL models? \n\nOptions:\n1) Choose a CDL model, transform the spatial filter into GCS, calculate TDL cluster power values\n2) Choose a CDL model, generate departure and arrival angles, generate the cross polarization power ratios\n3) Choose a TDL model, generate departure and arrival angles, generate the cross polarization power ratios\n4) Choose a TDL model, transform the spatial filter into GCS, calculate TDL cluster power values\n5) Choose a CDL model, generate departure and arrival angles, generate the cross polarization power ratios\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5650, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Choose a CDL model, transform the spatial filter into GCS, calculate TDL cluster power values", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn the context of cell status and cell reservations, what does the field 'cellBarred' indicate? \n\nOptions:\n1) If the cell is barred for connectivity to 5GC\n2) If the cell is reserved for operator use\n3) If the cell is barred for connectivity to EPC\n4) If the cell supports network-based CRS interference mitigation\n5) If the cell is barred for emergency calls\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5655, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  If the cell is barred for connectivity to EPC", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a UE prepends to an information field in a DCI format if its size is smaller than required? \n\nOptions:\n1) Zeros\n2) Ones\n3) The last value in the field\n4) Nothing, it discards the information field\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5657, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Zeros", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Multi-device and Multi-Identity feature in the IMS Multimedia Telephony service? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allow users to use any public user identities for outgoing and incoming calls\n2) To support synchronization of communication logs between multiple devices\n3) To enable the addition and deletion of identities for outgoing communications\n4) To provide information about potential risks associated with the caller identity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5664, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To allow users to use any public user identities for outgoing and incoming calls", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is provisioning in the context of the Target UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) An action to remove an available LCS feature from a target UE\u2019s subscription profile\n2) An action taken by the service provider to remove an available privacy class from a target UE\u2019s PEL\n3) An action to invoke the LCS feature\n4) An action to bar the Location Service of a specific user\n5) An action to make the privacy exception list with its privacy classes available to a Target UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5669, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  An action to make the privacy exception list with its privacy classes available to a Target UE", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the gNB do with the UE UTRA-FDD capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) Upload them to the AMF\n2) Send them to the UE\n3) Signal them to the network\n4) Store them in the gNB\n5) Skip uploading them\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5675, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Skip uploading them", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of steering of access in the Evolved Packet System? \n\nOptions:\n1) To optimize routing for user plane traffic\n2) To support mobility within and across access systems\n3) To minimize packet loss during inter- and/or intra-access technology changes\n4) To provide continuous service during and following changes of access systems\n5) To enable the operator to request the use of a specific access technology\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5681, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To enable the operator to request the use of a specific access technology", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the impact of voice call continuity on the quality of the voice service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Voice call continuity may adversely impact the voice service quality\n2) Voice call continuity improves the voice service quality\n3) Voice call continuity has no impact on the voice service quality\n4) Voice call continuity reduces the voice service quality\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5684, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Voice call continuity has no impact on the voice service quality", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen are channel access procedures applied? \n\nOptions:\n1) When a gNB provides UE(s) with higher layer parameters channelAccessMode2-r17.\n2) When a gNB senses a channel for availability to perform DL/UL transmission(s).\n3) When a gNB intends to transmit a DL transmission(s) across multiple transmission beams.\n4) When a UE is scheduled to transmit a set of consecutive UL transmissions.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5686, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  When a gNB provides UE(s) with higher layer parameters channelAccessMode2-r17.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nFor which operation does the requirement for spurious emissions apply? \n\nOptions:\n1) E-UTRA FDD operation\n2) NB-IoT operation\n3) Single carrier operation\n4) Multi-carrier operation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5694, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  E-UTRA FDD operation", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat additional information is reported to the NAS if the UE supports E-UTRA connected to 5GC? \n\nOptions:\n1) Associated RSRP value\n2) Associated PLMN identity\n3) Associated CN type\n4) Associated CSG ID\n5) Associated cell parameters\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5697, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Associated CN type", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can the AMF do if it accepts the Paging Restriction Information requested by the UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Store the Paging Restriction Information in the UE context\n2) Reject the Paging Restriction Information\n3) Trigger the AN release procedure\n4) Provide the UE with a new 5G-GUTI\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5698, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Store the Paging Restriction Information in the UE context", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can analytics be exchanged between HPLMN and VPLMN in the roaming architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Via SEPPs\n2) Via H-RE-NWDAF in HPLMN and V-RE-NWDAF in VPLMN\n3) Via Nnwdaf interface\n4) Via Nadrf service\n5) Via Nmfaf_3daDataManagement interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5706, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Via H-RE-NWDAF in HPLMN and V-RE-NWDAF in VPLMN", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of UL asynchronous HARQ transmission in the LTE network? \n\nOptions:\n1) To improve UL/DL bitrate recommendation\n2) To support multi-subframe channel estimation\n3) To utilize transmission time efficiently\n4) To enable PUSCH enhancement mode\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5719, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To utilize transmission time efficiently", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat action should the UE take if a cell is indicated as 'barred' for cell selection/reselection? \n\nOptions:\n1) Exclude the barred cell as a candidate for cell selection/reselection for 300 seconds\n2) Select another cell on the same frequency if the selection criteria are fulfilled\n3) Select the same cell in normal coverage if able to acquire necessary information\n4) Select the same cell in enhanced coverage if able to acquire necessary information\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5725, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of transmissions are defined for ProSe Direct Discovery and ProSe Direct Communication between UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Uplink transmissions\n2) Downlink transmissions\n3) Sidelink transmissions\n4) Point-to-point transmissions\n5) Random access transmissions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5727, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Sidelink transmissions", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich scenario is intended to capture various typical indoor deployment scenarios including office environments and shopping malls? \n\nOptions:\n1) UMi\n2) UMa\n3) Indoor\n4) Backhaul\n5) D2D/V2V\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5729, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Indoor", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the NR Coverage and Capacity Optimization (CCO) function? \n\nOptions:\n1) To detect and mitigate coverage and cell edge interference issues\n2) To enable inter-system load balancing\n3) To optimize 2-step RACH procedure\n4) To enhance mobility optimization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5736, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To detect and mitigate coverage and cell edge interference issues", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many energy saving states can cells, network elements, and network functions be in? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1\n2) 2\n3) 3\n4) 4\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5739, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  2", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the optional output for the Ndccf_ContextManagement_Deregister service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transaction Reference ID(s)\n2) Subscription Correlation ID\n3) Notification Correlation ID\n4) None\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5750, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  None", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the L-PSA UPF send the Nupf_EventExposure_Notify? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the AF initiates an AF session\n2) When the PCF makes the policy decision\n3) When the L-PSA UPF detects a QoS monitoring event\n4) When the AF revokes the AF session\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5752, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  When the L-PSA UPF detects a QoS monitoring event", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does Layer 3 filtering apply to in CLI measurement results? \n\nOptions:\n1) TDD DL-UL configurations\n2) Signal strengths\n3) Aggressor UE(s)\n4) RSSI resources\n5) CLI measurement results\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5753, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  CLI measurement results", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the PUCCH transmission with a link recovery request (LRR)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To request a link recovery from the network.\n2) To transmit PUCCH on a different cell than the PRACH transmission.\n3) To indicate the presence of periodic CSI-RS configuration or SS/PBCH block.\n4) To monitor PDCCH in all CORESETs on the SCell(s).\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5760, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To request a link recovery from the network.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is EN-DC in the context of 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) 3G and 4G Dual Connectivity\n2) 4G and 5G Dual Connectivity\n3) Enhanced Non-Standalone Deployment Capability\n4) Evolved Non-Standalone Dual Connectivity\n5) Extended Network-Device Connectivity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5787, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  4G and 5G Dual Connectivity", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does Dual Connectivity allow the Master RAN Node to do? \n\nOptions:\n1) Direct all DL User Plane traffic of a PDU Session to either the Master RAN Node or the Secondary RAN Node\n2) Direct all DL Control Plane traffic of a PDU Session to either the Master RAN Node or the Secondary RAN Node\n3) Direct all UL User Plane traffic of a PDU Session to either the Master RAN Node or the Secondary RAN Node\n4) Direct all UL Control Plane traffic of a PDU Session to either the Master RAN Node or the Secondary RAN Node\n5) Direct all User Plane and Control Plane traffic of a PDU Session to either the Master RAN Node or the Secondary RAN Node\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5788, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Direct all DL User Plane traffic of a PDU Session to either the Master RAN Node or the Secondary RAN Node", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich access class value is assigned to Multimedia Priority Service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Access Class 10\n2) Access Class 11\n3) Access Class 12\n4) Access Class 13\n5) Access Class 14\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5791, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Access Class 14", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following network functions is responsible for session management? \n\nOptions:\n1) AMF\n2) SMF\n3) NRF\n4) NSSF\n5) UDM\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5794, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  SMF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a network slice in the context of 3GPP?\n\nOptions:\n1) A physical network with specific network characteristics and capabilities\n2) A set of virtual/logical network functions that run on top of network resources\n3) A network function that is shared among different slices\n4) An identifier for a network slice\n5) A type of PDU session\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5795, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  A set of virtual/logical network functions that run on top of network resources", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich test method uses the fixed TPMI index for EIRP measurement? \n\nOptions:\n1) Static propagation conditions\n2) Multi-path fading propagation conditions\n3) DUT antenna location estimation\n4) TRP measurement error in NF\n5) Polarization basis mismatch between the TE and DUT\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5797, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Polarization basis mismatch between the TE and DUT", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is PSCell information reported by the NG-RAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only when requested by the AMF\n2) Only when Dual Connectivity is activated\n3) Both when requested by the AMF and when Dual Connectivity is activated\n4) PSCell information is never reported by the NG-RAN\n5) PSCell information is always reported by the NG-RAN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5802, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Only when requested by the AMF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the SN-DU send to the SN-CU after receiving the UE CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST message? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE\n2) UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION REQUEST\n3) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND\n4) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMPLETE\n5) UE CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5804, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  UE CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat do the angles bearing, downtilt, and slant represent? \n\nOptions:\n1) Rotation angles of the LCS with respect to the GCS\n2) Unit vectors of the GCS\n3) Polarized field components in the LCS\n4) Zenith and azimuth angles of the GCS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5810, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Rotation angles of the LCS with respect to the GCS", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum data channel bandwidth supported in CE modes A and B in DL? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1.4 MHz\n2) 5 MHz\n3) 10 MHz\n4) 20 MHz\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5819, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  20 MHz", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the minimum number of grid points required for the TRP Measurement Grid with constant density? \n\nOptions:\n1) 40\n2) 50\n3) 62\n4) 86\n5) 100\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5821, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  62", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information does the Home Subscriber Server (HSS) hold? \n\nOptions:\n1) User identification and numbering information.\n2) User security information.\n3) User location information.\n4) User profile information.\n5) All of the above.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5825, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when an MPS session request cannot be immediately processed in the originating network? \n\nOptions:\n1) The session request is dropped\n2) The session request is terminated\n3) The session request is queued\n4) The session request is ignored\n5) The session request is delayed\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5826, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The session request is queued", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does redundant transmission on N3/N9 interfaces in URLLC aim to enhance? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reliability of the NG-RAN node and UPF.\n2) Reliability of the backhaul network.\n3) Reliability of the single N3 tunnel.\n4) Reliability of the transport layer path.\n5) Reliability of the GTP-U tunnel over N3.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5827, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Reliability of the backhaul network.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the power components recommended to be considered for RRM measurement power saving evaluation in the IDLE/INACTIVE state? \n\nOptions:\n1) Loop convergence (AGC, TTL & FTL) / time-frequency tracking\n2) SSB bursts used for Loop convergence\n3) Paging\n4) SIB1 decoding\n5) Sleep\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5832, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Loop convergence (AGC, TTL & FTL) / time-frequency tracking", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the IAB-node in the integrated access and backhaul (IAB) architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Terminate the NR access interface to UEs\n2) Terminate the F1 protocol to the gNB-CU\n3) Support intra-/inter-RAT mobility\n4) Perform QoS handling for user plane\n5) Perform packet forwarding and inspection\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5834, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Terminate the NR access interface to UEs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are EE KPIs for network elements expressed? \n\nOptions:\n1) Data Volume / Energy Consumption\n2) Coverage Area / Energy Consumption\n3) Data Volume * Energy Consumption\n4) Energy Consumption / Data Volume\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5835, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Data Volume / Energy Consumption", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of mapping rules in the QoS architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) To map QoS flows to DRBs\n2) To establish PDU sessions\n3) To differentiate GBR and non-GBR flows\n4) To guarantee flow bit rate\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5838, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To map QoS flows to DRBs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Reliable Data Service (RDS) between UE and SCEF? \n\nOptions:\n1) To handle CN overload from data transmission via Control Plane CIoT EPS Optimization\n2) To enhance location services for CIoT UEs\n3) To enable UE-assisted DCN selection\n4) To prioritize resource allocation between NB-IoT UEs\n5) To provide reliable delivery of NIDD data\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5840, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To provide reliable delivery of NIDD data", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the three levels of services defined for a UE in Idle mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) Limited service, normal service, and operator service\n2) Emergency service, normal service, and reserved service\n3) Basic service, advanced service, and premium service\n4) Public service, private service, and operator service\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5841, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Limited service, normal service, and operator service", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the procedure for notifying a mobile station of an appropriate call-related event during the 'active' state? \n\nOptions:\n1) Sending a MODIFY message to the mobile station\n2) Sending a SETUP message to the mobile station\n3) Sending a CALL CONFIRMED message to the mobile station\n4) Sending a NOTIFY message to the mobile station\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5847, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Sending a NOTIFY message to the mobile station", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the AF request include when invoking the Nnef_DNAIMapping_Subscribe service? \n\nOptions:\n1) EAS address information and DNN\n2) EAS address information and S-NSSAI\n3) EAS address information, DNN, S-NSSAI, and AF Identifier\n4) EAS address information only\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5849, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  EAS address information, DNN, S-NSSAI, and AF Identifier", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the relative increase in cable loss per meter from 43.5 GHz to 48.2 GHz? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.33 dB\n2) 0.9 dB\n3) 3.5 dB\n4) 7.7 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5853, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  0.33 dB", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the starting PRB index of the DL PRS resource? \n\nOptions:\n1) nr-DL-PRS-CombSizeN-AndReOffset\n2) dl-PRS-StartPRB\n3) numSymbols\n4) dl-PRS-ResourceSlotOffset\n5) dl-PRS-ResourceSymbolOffset\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5872, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  dl-PRS-StartPRB", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the expected reliability for remote control for process automation in 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) 99%\n2) 99.9%\n3) 99.99%\n4) 99.999%\n5) 99.9999%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5892, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  99.9999%", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat types of communication can be supported by Indirect 3GPP Communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) ProSe Group Communication only\n2) ProSe Broadcast Communication only\n3) Both ProSe Group Communication and ProSe Broadcast Communication\n4) Multimedia telephony and real-time video only\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5895, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both ProSe Group Communication and ProSe Broadcast Communication", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich sublayer is responsible for mapping between a QoS flow and a data radio bearer? \n\nOptions:\n1) MAC sublayer\n2) RLC sublayer\n3) PDCP sublayer\n4) SDAP sublayer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5896, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  SDAP sublayer", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the responsibilities of the MSC server and Gateway MSC server in charging? \n\nOptions:\n1) Collecting charging relevant information for each MS and PSTN connection\n2) Generating CDRs for calls routed from or into other networks\n3) Storing billing information for Service Providers\n4) Administering on-line charging data stored in the network nodes\n5) Verifying the alternate charged party for IMS offline and online charging\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5903, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Collecting charging relevant information for each MS and PSTN connection", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat drives the need for secure mechanisms to establish or refresh credentials and subscriptions in IoT devices? \n\nOptions:\n1) Long life spans of IoT devices\n2) Dynamic ownership of IoT devices\n3) Introduction of new access technologies\n4) Protection against theft and fraud\n5) Expansion into different markets\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5904, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Long life spans of IoT devices", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the architecture called when the 5G AN is connected to the 4G Core Network? \n\nOptions:\n1) EN-DC\n2) Stand-Alone (SA)\n3) Non-Stand Alone (NSA)\n4) E-UTRA-NR Dual Connectivity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5909, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Non-Stand Alone (NSA)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of an Application Group ID? \n\nOptions:\n1) To identify a group of UE within a PLMN domain\n2) To specify access to a functional entity in the EDN\n3) To identify a specific application\n4) To establish an association between EASs\n5) To establish an association between UE Groups\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5913, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To identify a specific application", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many SSB bursts are used for Loop convergence in the CONNECTED state? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1\n2) 2\n3) 3\n4) 4\n5) 5\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5915, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  2", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Restriction of use of Enhanced Coverage feature? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allocate extensive resources from the network for specific subscribers\n2) To enable the operator to restrict specific subscribers from using Enhanced Coverage\n3) To provide enhanced coverage functionality for both data and voice centric UEs\n4) To prevent the MME from sending the Enhanced Coverage Restricted parameter to the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5919, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To enable the operator to restrict specific subscribers from using Enhanced Coverage", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIs the deployment of a NAT between EASDF and PSA UPF supported? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes, it is supported\n2) No, it is not supported\n3) It depends on the configuration of the EASDF\n4) It depends on the type of UE\n5) Both option 2 and 3\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5920, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  No, it is not supported", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of selecting an appropriate relay UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) To improve energy efficiency\n2) To improve coverage\n3) To improve energy efficiency and coverage\n4) No specific purpose\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5923, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To improve energy efficiency and coverage", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the UE ignore the scheduling DCI for the n-th triggered CSI report? \n\nOptions:\n1) If the first uplink symbol to carry the n-th CSI report starts earlier than at symbol Z'ref(n)\n2) If the PUSCH indicated by the DCI is overlapping with another PUCCH or PUSCH\n3) If the number of triggered reports is one and no HARQ-ACK or transport block is multiplexed on the PUSCH\n4) If the first uplink symbol to carry the corresponding CSI report(s) starts earlier than at symbol Zref\n5) If the PDCCH reception includes two PDCCH candidates from two respective search space sets\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5926, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  If the first uplink symbol to carry the n-th CSI report starts earlier than at symbol Z'ref(n)", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does scheduling the periods of location monitoring and reporting help reduce? \n\nOptions:\n1) Quality of Service (QoS)\n2) Network traffic\n3) Asset management services\n4) Privacy Exception List\n5) PLMN operator services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5947, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Network traffic", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich additional positioning technique is supported in Rel-16 LPP for GNSS SSR? \n\nOptions:\n1) PPP and RTK\n2) Multi-RTT\n3) NR E-CID\n4) DL AoD\n5) DL PRS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5949, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  PPP and RTK", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Edge Enabler Client (EEC) in enabling edge applications? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide configurations to the Edge Configuration Server\n2) To support service provisioning for UE\n3) To expose EES capability as APIs to EAS\n4) To enable service continuity during UE mobility\n5) To enable discovery of the EASs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5952, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To enable discovery of the EASs", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat triggers the deletion of the list of forbidden tracking areas associated with an SNPN? \n\nOptions:\n1) Updating the entry in the 'list of subscriber data'\n2) Removing the USIM\n3) Updating the PLMN subscription\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5962, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following physical channels carries information originating from higher layers? \n\nOptions:\n1) Physical Sidelink Control Channel (PSCCH)\n2) Physical Sidelink Broadcast Channel (PSBCH)\n3) Physical Sidelink Feedback Channel (PSFCH)\n4) Demodulation reference signals (DM-RS)\n5) Sidelink primary synchronization signal (S-PSS)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5963, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Physical Sidelink Broadcast Channel (PSBCH)", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the out-of-band blocking characteristic for SAN type 1-H? \n\nOptions:\n1) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive the wanted signal at its assigned channel frequency in the presence of an interfering signal.\n2) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive a wanted signal in the presence of an adjacent channel signal.\n3) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive the wanted signal at its assigned channel frequency in the presence of a spurious emission.\n4) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive a wanted signal at its assigned channel in the presence of an unwanted interferer out of the operating band.\n5) The measure of the receiver's ability to receive a wanted signal in the presence of an interfering signal in the received SAN channel bandwidth.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5966, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The measure of the receiver's ability to receive a wanted signal at its assigned channel in the presence of an unwanted interferer out of the operating band.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat triggers Edge Relocation in the network? \n\nOptions:\n1) AF request\n2) UE mobility\n3) Both AF request and UE mobility\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5967, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both AF request and UE mobility", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of scrambling in the physical uplink shared channel? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enhance the security of the transmitted data.\n2) To achieve frequency diversity in the channel.\n3) To apply error correction coding to the transmitted bits.\n4) To randomize the bits before modulation.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5974, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To randomize the bits before modulation.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the communication attributes in automation? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Periodicity and determinism\n2) Reliability and availability\n3) Event-driven actions and time-criticality\n4) Logging information and maintenance work\n5) Transmission time and system input\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5981, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Periodicity and determinism", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat capabilities should a Shared E-UTRAN/NG-RAN have? \n\nOptions:\n1) Differentiate traffic associated with individual Participating Operators\n2) Conduct admission control based on allocated resources\n3) Provide monitoring of resource usage\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5982, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum number of additional RACH configurations? \n\nOptions:\n1) 256\n2) 64\n3) 128\n4) 32\n5) 512\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5984, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  256", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of 5G Access Stratum-based Time Distribution? \n\nOptions:\n1) To control the synchronization of 5G Clock\n2) To enable/disable the access stratum time distribution for a UE\n3) To determine the coverage area for time synchronization\n4) To store the 5G access stratum time distribution indication\n5) To perform the registration procedure for a UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5986, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To enable/disable the access stratum time distribution for a UE", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat procedure allows maintaining the S1 connection and retransmissions of the NAS PDUs in case of radio link failure for CIoT EPS optimizations? \n\nOptions:\n1) RRC Connection Re-establishment and S1 eNB CP Relocation Indication procedures\n2) MME CP Relocation procedure\n3) S1 UE Context Release procedure\n4) Handover procedure with data forwarding\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5989, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  RRC Connection Re-establishment and S1 eNB CP Relocation Indication procedures", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich series of documents in 3GPP documentation focus on radio technology beyond LTE?\n\nOptions:\n1) 36.xxx\n2) 37.xxx\n3) 38.xxx\n4) 36.xxx and 37.xxx\n5) 37.xxx and 38.xxx\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 5995, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  38.xxx", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhy do AV production applications call for uncompressed or slightly compressed data? \n\nOptions:\n1) To amplify defects in the transmitted data.\n2) To match or improve upon existing workflows.\n3) To propagate communication errors to the entire audience.\n4) To post-process the transmitted data with filters.\n5) To minimize the probability of errors in the transmitted data.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6001, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To minimize the probability of errors in the transmitted data.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Message Priority header in messages exchanged over service-based interfaces? \n\nOptions:\n1) To prioritize flows based on subscription information\n2) To indicate priority information\n3) To establish prioritized QoS Flows\n4) To fulfill the QoS characteristics of QoS Flows\n5) To differentiate treatment for prioritized QoS Flow\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6003, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To indicate priority information", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat enhancements were introduced for NB-IoT and LTE-MTC in Rel-17? \n\nOptions:\n1) 16QAM for NB-IoT in downlink and uplink\n2) 14 HARQ processes in downlink for HD-FDD Cat. M1 UEs\n3) NB-IoT carrier selection based on coverage level\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6004, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of RAN visible QoE measurements? \n\nOptions:\n1) To evaluate the user experience of a service\n2) To optimize the network\n3) To configure the QoE measurement\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6005, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To optimize the network", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWho subscribes to analytics information of Application AI/ML traffic transmission status from the NWDAF? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE\n2) PCF\n3) AF\n4) SMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6006, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  SMF", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich error response indicates that the requested service option is not authorized in the PLMN? \n\nOptions:\n1) PLMN not allowed\n2) Requested service option not authorized in this PLMN\n3) Serving network not authorized\n4) Temporarily not authorized for this SNPN\n5) IMSI unknown in HLR\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6007, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Requested service option not authorized in this PLMN", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich reference points are included in the logical ubiquitous charging architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Rf, Ga, Bx, ISC, Ro, CAP, Gy, and Gyn\n2) Rf, Ga, Bx, Gy, and Gyn\n3) Rf, Ga, Bx, ISC, and Gy\n4) Ga, Bx, ISC, Ro, CAP, Gy, and Gyn\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6015, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Rf, Ga, Bx, ISC, Ro, CAP, Gy, and Gyn", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nCan multiple MDA instances be deployed? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes, but only for cross-domain MDA\n2) No, MDA is limited to a single instance\n3) Yes, for both cross-domain and domain-specific MDA\n4) Yes, but only for domain-specific MDA\n5) Yes, but only for CN domain MDA\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6017, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Yes, for both cross-domain and domain-specific MDA", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the channel generation process in the map-based hybrid model based on? \n\nOptions:\n1) Deterministic ray-tracing and stochastic components\n2) Randomly generated delays and powers\n3) Large scale parameters\n4) Antenna modeling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6018, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Deterministic ray-tracing and stochastic components", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the priority value for a PSFCH transmission with HARQ-ACK information? \n\nOptions:\n1) Priority value indicated by corresponding SCI format 1-A\n2) Priority value determined by SCI formats 1-A for conflicting resources\n3) Priority value determined by corresponding SCI format 1-A for conflicting resources\n4) Priority value indicated by SCI format 1-A associated with the PSFCH\n5) Smallest priority value among PSSCH receptions with HARQ-ACK information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6023, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Priority value indicated by SCI format 1-A associated with the PSFCH", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nCan a UE disable use of one or more of its radio technologies, regardless of PLMNs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes\n2) No\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6024, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Yes", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat capability does the management service producer responsible for PEE fault supervision have? \n\nOptions:\n1) Collection of PEE measurement data\n2) Modification of PEE related parameters\n3) Notification of PEE related alarms\n4) Sending DV performance data streams\n5) Querying ongoing collection of DV measurement data\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6035, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Notification of PEE related alarms", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines if an IAB-DU cell can transmit or receive on a symbol configured as a soft type? \n\nOptions:\n1) IAB-DU cell's configuration of hard or unavailable symbols\n2) Availability of soft symbols in the slot\n3) Detection of DCI format 2_5 with an AI index field value\n4) Configuration of RB set availability by Frequency-Domain HSNA Configuration List\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6036, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Availability of soft symbols in the slot", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the three factors that govern the PDCCH monitoring activity of the UE in RRC connected mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) DRX, BA, and DCP\n2) BA, DCP, and CA\n3) DRX, DCP, and CA\n4) DRX, BA, and CA\n5) DRX, BA, and DCP\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6037, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  DRX, BA, and DCP", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following situations can lead to the MS being unable to obtain normal service from a PLMN or SNPN? \n\nOptions:\n1) Failure to find a suitable cell of the selected PLMN or SNPN\n2) No SIM in the MS\n3) A PLMN not allowed response in case of PLMN\n4) An illegal ME response when an LR is received\n5) MS supporting CAG is camped on a CAG cell\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6040, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Failure to find a suitable cell of the selected PLMN or SNPN", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a UE configure when provided with UplinkCancellation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Search space sets for monitoring the first PDCCH candidate\n2) Set of serving cell indexes and corresponding locations for fields in DCI format 2_4\n3) Number of fields in DCI format 2_4 for each serving cell\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6042, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nUnder what circumstances would it be desirable to prevent UE users from making access attempts or responding to pages in specified areas of a PLMN? \n\nOptions:\n1) During normal operating conditions\n2) During states of emergency or when one or more co-located PLMNs have failed\n3) When the access channel is overloaded\n4) When the serving network is UTRAN\n5) When broadcast messages are unavailable\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6046, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  During states of emergency or when one or more co-located PLMNs have failed", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specification introduced the mechanism to support single radio voice call continuity (SRVCC) from 5GS to UTRAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS\u00a026.959\n2) TS\u00a036.331\n3) TS\u00a023.756\n4) TS\u00a022.115\n5) TS\u00a026.114\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6051, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS\u00a023.756", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich logical channel can be mapped to DL-SCH in the downlink? \n\nOptions:\n1) BCCH\n2) PCCH\n3) CCCH\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6057, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the periodicity of half frames with SS/PBCH blocks for initial cell selection in an IAB-MT? \n\nOptions:\n1) 4 frames\n2) 8 frames\n3) 12 frames\n4) 16 frames\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6059, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  16 frames", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of the serving core network operator in a shared network? \n\nOptions:\n1) To conditionally accept handover requests\n2) To broadcast multiple PLMN-id lists\n3) To determine the operator selected by a supporting UE\n4) To allocate the core network operator to a non-supporting UE\n5) To allocate the core network operator to any UE in a shared network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6061, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To allocate the core network operator to any UE in a shared network", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich state supports QoE measurement reporting in UMTS networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) CELL_FACH state\n2) CELL_DCH state\n3) CELL_PCH state\n4) CELL_FDD state\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6065, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  CELL_DCH state", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Allowed Delay parameter indicate? \n\nOptions:\n1) The time interval for provisioning PFDs to SMFs\n2) The authorization status of the AF\n3) The list of PFDs in the request\n4) The operator policies for PFD provisioning\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6067, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The time interval for provisioning PFDs to SMFs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich aspect is not covered by the flexible network operations in 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) Network slicing\n2) Network capability exposure\n3) Migration and interworking\n4) Efficient content delivery\n5) Scalability and diverse mobility\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6080, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Efficient content delivery", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat procedure is followed to estimate the energy consumption of VNF/VNFCs based on the vCPU usage of virtual compute resources? \n\nOptions:\n1) Collect PEE measurements from NFVI nodes\n2) Collect vCPU usage of virtual compute resources from VIM\n3) Collect vCPU usage of virtual compute resources from VNFM\n4) Collect vCPU usage of virtual compute resources from VNF/VNFC instances\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6082, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Collect vCPU usage of virtual compute resources from VIM", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can the target UE authorize positioning attempts? \n\nOptions:\n1) Before the target UE is positioned\n2) After the target UE is notified of a positioning request\n3) Before reporting the location to the LCS Client\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6088, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Un interface in E-UTRAN support? \n\nOptions:\n1) Relaying between the RN and the DeNB\n2) S1 and X2 user plane aspects\n3) S1 and X2 control plane aspects\n4) Radio protocol aspects\n5) The termination of the E-UTRA radio protocols\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6097, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Relaying between the RN and the DeNB", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of ciphering in NR connected to 5GC security? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ensures physical protection of data handling\n2) Provides user data integrity protection\n3) Provides signaling data confidentiality\n4) Provides signaling data integrity protection\n5) Provides user data confidentiality\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6099, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Provides user data confidentiality", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Single link polarization measurement? \n\nOptions:\n1) To calculate the CDF of the EIRP/EIS distribution in 3D\n2) To determine the total power radiated by the DUT in the TX beam peak direction\n3) To determine the RX beam peak direction\n4) To measure the EIRP spherical coverage\n5) To reduce the test time for the FR2 2Tx test cases\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6105, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To reduce the test time for the FR2 2Tx test cases", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of link adaptation is performed in uplink transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) Adaptive transmission bandwidth\n2) Transmission power control\n3) Adaptive modulation and channel coding rate\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6109, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich charging architecture is used for 5G Data Connectivity in Phase 1 of the 5G System Architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) NG-RAN\n2) CHF\n3) SMF\n4) Nchf\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6115, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Nchf", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Ndccf_DataManagement_Subscribe service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To subscribe to receive data or analytics via the DCCF\n2) To unsubscribe from receiving data or analytics via the DCCF\n3) To notify the DCCF about the requested data or analytics\n4) To fetch data or analytics from the DCCF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6116, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To subscribe to receive data or analytics via the DCCF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat power value is recommended for loop convergence / time-frequency tracking in the IDLE/INACTIVE state? \n\nOptions:\n1) Depends on the measurement window\n2) Higher than SSB processing power value\n3) Lower than SSB processing power value\n4) Not specified\n5) Same as SSB processing power value\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6124, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Same as SSB processing power value", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of exposing network capabilities to third-party ISPs/ICPs? \n\nOptions:\n1) To customize a dedicated physical or virtual network for diverse use cases\n2) To improve user experience and utilize backhaul and application resources efficiently\n3) To provide suitable APIs to create, modify, and delete network slices\n4) To monitor the network slice used for the third-party\n5) To configure the information which associates a UE to a network slice used for the third-party\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6129, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To customize a dedicated physical or virtual network for diverse use cases", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following is not a feature that can be calibrated? \n\nOptions:\n1) Oxygen absorption\n2) Large bandwidth and large antenna array\n3) Spatial consistency\n4) Blockage\n5) Fast fading modeling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6135, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Fast fading modeling", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nCan the visited network offer additional services or access to content providers? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes\n2) No\n3) Dependent on the subscription options in the home environment\n4) Restricted by the capabilities of the visited network\n5) Restricted by the roaming agreement between the home and visited environment\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6139, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Yes", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the 3GPP management system interacting with NWDAF? \n\nOptions:\n1) To address the slow control loop with broad management scope\n2) To establish a connection for management data streaming\n3) To enable the management service producer to invoke operations\n4) To request a subscription to notifications and receive network events\n5) To authenticate the management service consumer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6147, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To address the slow control loop with broad management scope", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of SCC AS Restoration in IMS? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide continuity of service for incoming session requests in IMS\n2) To ensure Single Radio Voice Call Continuity (SRVCC) in IMS\n3) To store extra SRVCC related information in the HSS\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6151, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the value for the bit in the paging indication field determined? \n\nOptions:\n1) By subgroup index\n2) By paging occasion index\n3) By TRS availability indication field\n4) By validity duration\n5) By multiple of the number of frames\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6152, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  By paging occasion index", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the UE monitor PDCCH skipping duration? \n\nOptions:\n1) During measurement gaps\n2) During cross-slot scheduling\n3) During PDCCH monitoring adaptation mechanisms\n4) During the on-duration\n5) During BWP switching\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6163, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  During PDCCH monitoring adaptation mechanisms", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the composite antenna composed of? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transceiver unit array\n2) Radio distribution network\n3) Antenna array\n4) Satellite payload\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6165, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Antenna array", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat range of transport block sizes can a Category NB2 UE support? \n\nOptions:\n1) 2536 bits on both DL and UL\n2) 680 bits on DL and 1000 bits on UL\n3) 2000 bits on both DL and UL\n4) 1000 bits on DL and 500 bits on UL\n5) 1500 bits on DL and 800 bits on UL\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6171, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  2536 bits on both DL and UL", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can a 3rd party service provider request regarding data sessions with UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Request specified QoS and priority handling\n2) Request data sessions with low latency or jitter\n3) Both request specified QoS and priority handling, and request data sessions with low latency or jitter\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6172, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both request specified QoS and priority handling, and request data sessions with low latency or jitter", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the two deployment scenarios considered for OAM support in LSA? \n\nOptions:\n1) Deployment scenario 1: The LSA controller communicates LSA spectrum resource availability information (LSRAI) received from the LR to the NM. Deployment scenario 2: The LSA controller performs planning decisions based on the LSRAI received from the LR internally and communicates the calculated constraints on configuration attributes to the NM.\n2) Deployment scenario 1: The LSA controller communicates LSA spectrum resource availability information (LSRAI) received from the NM to the LR. Deployment scenario 2: The LSA controller performs planning decisions based on the LSRAI received from the LR internally and communicates the calculated constraints on configuration attributes to the NM.\n3) Deployment scenario 1: The LSA controller communicates LSA spectrum resource availability information (LSRAI) received from the LR to the NM. Deployment scenario 2: The LSA controller performs planning decisions based on the LSRAI received from the NM internally and communicates the calculated constraints on configuration attributes to the LR.\n4) Deployment scenario 1: The LSA controller communicates LSA spectrum resource availability information (LSRAI) received from the NM to the LR. Deployment scenario 2: The LSA controller performs planning decisions based on the LSRAI received from the NM internally and communicates the calculated constraints on configuration attributes to the LR.\n5) Deployment scenario 1: The LSA controller communicates LSA spectrum resource availability information (LSRAI) received from the NM to the NM. Deployment scenario 2: The LSA controller performs planning decisions based on the LSRAI received from the LR internally and communicates the calculated constraints on configuration attributes to the NM.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6173, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Deployment scenario 1 The LSA controller communicates LSA spectrum resource availability information (LSRAI) received from the LR to the NM. Deployment scenario 2 The LSA controller performs planning decisions based on the LSRAI received from the LR internally and communicates the calculated constraints on configuration attributes to the NM.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the three types of bearer options in Dual Connectivity? \n\nOptions:\n1) MCG bearer, SCG bearer, and split bearer\n2) Primary bearer, secondary bearer, and tertiary bearer\n3) Single bearer, multiple bearer, and aggregated bearer\n4) Control bearer, user bearer, and management bearer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6175, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  MCG bearer, SCG bearer, and split bearer", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich physical channel carries Hybrid ARQ ACK/NAKs in response to uplink transmissions? \n\nOptions:\n1) PCFICH\n2) PHICH\n3) PUCCH\n4) PDSCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6187, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  PHICH", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich communication pattern is suitable for event-driven actions? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Deterministic periodic communication\n2) Deterministic aperiodic communication\n3) Non-deterministic communication\n4) Mixed traffic\n5) Closed-loop control\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6189, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Deterministic aperiodic communication", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following is NOT a requirement for the 5G system to support direct device connection? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Supporting direct device connection using different spectrum than 5GC-based communication\n2) Supporting direct device connection for 5G LAN-type private communication\n3) Supporting direct device connection for periodic deterministic communication\n4) Supporting direct device connection for UEs up to 100 m distance\n5) Supporting multicast communication between UEs using direct device connection\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6195, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Supporting direct device connection for UEs up to 100 m distance", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does Indirect 3GPP Communication impact power consumption? \n\nOptions:\n1) It increases power consumption\n2) It decreases power consumption\n3) It has no impact on power consumption\n4) It depends on the PLMN configuration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6196, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  It decreases power consumption", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the definition of a RedCap UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) A UE with reduced capability, supporting a maximum bandwidth of 20 MHz for FR1 and 100 MHz for FR2, and limited features and capabilities.\n2) A UE with enhanced capability, supporting a maximum bandwidth of 100 MHz for FR1 and 800 MHz for FR2, and advanced features and capabilities.\n3) A UE with standard capability, supporting a maximum bandwidth of 100 MHz for FR1 and 100 MHz for FR2, and basic features and capabilities.\n4) A UE with specialized capability, supporting a maximum bandwidth of 20 MHz for FR1 and 20 MHz for FR2, and niche features and capabilities.\n5) A UE with advanced capability, supporting a maximum bandwidth of 1000 MHz for FR1 and 1000 MHz for FR2, and cutting-edge features and capabilities.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6197, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  A UE with reduced capability, supporting a maximum bandwidth of 20 MHz for FR1 and 100 MHz for FR2, and limited features and capabilities.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the primary purpose of MPS for DTS? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide priority voice communication sessions in periods of severe network congestion\n2) To provide priority video communication sessions in periods of severe network congestion\n3) To provide priority data transport service in periods of severe network congestion\n4) To provide priority access to enterprise networks in periods of severe network congestion\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6198, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To provide priority data transport service in periods of severe network congestion", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the uplink rate control function in the UE manage? \n\nOptions:\n1) The sharing of uplink resources between logical channels\n2) The allocation of physical layer resources for the uplink and the downlink\n3) The coordination of TDM and FDM cell resources between MAC in the gNB and the corresponding entity in the ng-eNB\n4) The support for power-aware packet scheduling\n5) The support for QoS-aware packet scheduling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6204, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The sharing of uplink resources between logical channels", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is included in the UE CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST message in the Intra-CU topology adaptation procedure in SA? \n\nOptions:\n1) Full configuration information\n2) MeasurementReport message\n3) UL RRC MESSAGE TRANSFER message\n4) HandoverPreparationInformation\n5) CG-ConfigInfo\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6206, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  CG-ConfigInfo", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn case of 15 kHz sub-carrier spacing, how many cyclic-prefix lengths are there? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1\n2) 2\n3) 3\n4) 4\n5) 5\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6211, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  2", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the duration called that the UE waits for after waking up to receive PDCCHs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Cycle\n2) Active-time\n3) On-duration\n4) Inactivity-timer\n5) Retransmission-timer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6212, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  On-duration", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information is provided by the SMF to the UPF during the N4 Session Establishment procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) N4 Session ID\n2) PDU Session information\n3) Structured control information\n4) Usage report\n5) TSC management information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6216, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Structured control information", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich services apply to UEs using mobile 3GPP access for IMS Multimedia Telephony? \n\nOptions:\n1) Originating Identification Restriction (OIR)\n2) Communication Waiting (CW)\n3) Communication Barring (CB)\n4) Message Waiting Indication (MWI)\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6225, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the RAN visible QoE measurement function do in a split gNB architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) Resolves RACH configuration conflict.\n2) Manages cross-link interference in non-split gNB architecture.\n3) Supports radio access network sharing.\n4) Facilitates consolidation of Remote Interference Management (RIM) information.\n5) May forward the RAN visible QoE measurement report from the UE to the gNB-DU.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6228, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  May forward the RAN visible QoE measurement report from the UE to the gNB-DU.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a UE expect when receiving a DCI format with a BWP indicator field indicating an active UL BWP or DL BWP change? \n\nOptions:\n1) To receive or transmit in the cell during a time duration specified by a delay\n2) To receive or transmit in the cell only in the first slot of a set of slots for the DL SCS\n3) To detect the DCI format within the first 3 symbols of a slot\n4) To monitor PDCCH during RRM measurements\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6233, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To receive or transmit in the cell during a time duration specified by a delay", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the required input for the Ndccf_ContextManagement_Update service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Service Operation\n2) Subscription Correlation ID\n3) Notification Correlation ID\n4) Transaction Reference ID(s)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6237, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Transaction Reference ID(s)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich legacy service is not supported by the 5G system? \n\nOptions:\n1) Voice service continuity from UTRAN to NG-RAN\n2) CS fallback from NG-RAN to GERAN\n3) Seamless handover between NG-RAN and UTRAN\n4) Access to a 5G core network via GERAN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6239, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Access to a 5G core network via GERAN", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the UE CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST message in the inter-gNB-DU mobility procedure for intra-NR? \n\nOptions:\n1) To query the latest configuration from the source gNB-DU.\n2) To create a UE context and setup data bearers in the target gNB-DU.\n3) To send a HandoverPreparationInformation to the gNB-CU.\n4) To respond to the UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE message from the source gNB-DU.\n5) To inform the gNB-CU about the unsuccessfully transmitted downlink data to the UE.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6241, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To create a UE context and setup data bearers in the target gNB-DU.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nFor operation with RTT-based propagation delay compensation, how can the UE be configured? \n\nOptions:\n1) One CSI-RS for tracking and one PRS resource set with usage-PDC\n2) One SRS resource set with usage-PDC and one PRS resource set with usage-PDC\n3) One CSI-RS for tracking with higher layer parameter pdc-Info and one SRS resource set with usage-PDC\n4) One PRS configuration of higher layer parameter nr-DL-PRS-PDC-ResourceSet and one SRS resource set with usage-PDC\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6253, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  One CSI-RS for tracking and one PRS resource set with usage-PDC", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat power saving gain range is observed for the power saving scheme with PDCCH skipping or 'go-to-sleep' signal? \n\nOptions:\n1) 9% - 83%\n2) 2% - 15%\n3) 50% - 85%\n4) 1.4% - 11%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6254, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  9% - 83%", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can an Evolved ProSe Remote UE get information about the PLMN to which a specific Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay connects? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through provisioning of policies in the Evolved ProSe Remote UE and Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay\n2) Through signaling explicitly controlled by the 3GPP network\n3) Through the pre-configuration of Relay UE discovery information in the Evolved ProSe Remote UE\n4) Through preferences stored in the Evolved ProSe Remote UE related to relay UE selection criteria\n5) Both option 1 and option 2\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6258, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Both option 1 and option 2", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the procedures for a Target UE\u2019s privacy exception list? \n\nOptions:\n1) Provisioning and withdrawal\n2) Provisioning and invocation\n3) Invocation and user control\n4) User control and withdrawal\n5) Barring capability and invocation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6268, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Provisioning and withdrawal", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich mode is used for multi-TRP PDCCH transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) PDCCH repetition\n2) SFN based PDCCH transmission\n3) Both 1 and 2\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6272, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both 1 and 2", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn a shared UTRAN/GERAN network, what does a non-supporting UE do after reading the broadcast system information? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE sends an ATTACH REQUEST/ROUTEING AREA UPDATE/LOCATION AREA UPDATE message to the network\n2) The UE decodes the shared network information and supplies the available core network operator PLMN-ids as candidates to the PLMN selection procedure\n3) The UE performs network selection among available PLMNs\n4) The UE reads the system information in the shared RAN\n5) The UE reads the system information in the shared GERAN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6277, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The UE performs network selection among available PLMNs", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of multiple USIMs in a MUSIM UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide security features\n2) To host multiple applications\n3) To access the IMS services\n4) To improve system performance and user experiences\n5) To store provisioning parameters\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6286, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To improve system performance and user experiences", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specification defines IMS support for 5GC? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS\u00a023.040\n2) TS\u00a023.273\n3) TS\u00a023.502\n4) TS\u00a023.540\n5) TS\u00a023.228\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6296, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  TS\u00a023.228", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the L2 latency reduction techniques for LTE work item? \n\nOptions:\n1) To increase the effectiveness of available scheduling tools\n2) To improve the DL beamforming performance\n3) To reduce the grant request delay in the UL\n4) To reduce the end to end delay for connected UEs\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6297, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To reduce the end to end delay for connected UEs", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does AS stand for in the context of PLMN selection? \n\nOptions:\n1) Administrative System\n2) Authentication Server\n3) Application Server\n4) Access Server\n5) Availability System\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6300, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Access Server", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NEF do if the mapping information is stored in UDR? \n\nOptions:\n1) Determines the DNN\n2) Determines the S-NSSAI\n3) Subscribes to DNAI mapping information for this DNN and/or S-NSSAI\n4) Notifies the DNAI(s) to the AF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6329, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Subscribes to DNAI mapping information for this DNN and/or S-NSSAI", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Child IAB-DU Restricted Beam Indication MAC CE indicate to the IAB-node? \n\nOptions:\n1) Multiplexing mode of the IAB-node\n2) Availability of RB resources for transmission\n3) Indication of quasi co-location properties of an IAB-DU cell\n4) Timing advance offset value for a serving cell\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6331, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Indication of quasi co-location properties of an IAB-DU cell", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Nmfaf_3daDataManagement service? \n\nOptions:\n1) To configure the MFAF to map data or analytics received by the MFAF to out-bound notification endpoints\n2) To configure the MFAF to stop mapping data or analytics received by the MFAF to out-bound notification endpoints\n3) To supply data or analytics from the MFAF to notification endpoints\n4) To fetch data or analytics from the MFAF based on fetch instructions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6339, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To configure the MFAF to map data or analytics received by the MFAF to out-bound notification endpoints", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich entity is used as an SGSN for only some GTP signalling messages in a GLR-equipped VPLMN? \n\nOptions:\n1) Intermediate Mobile-services Switching Centre (IM-MSC)\n2) Gateway Location Register (GLR)\n3) Intermediate GPRS Serving Node (IM-GSN)\n4) GGSN - packet data networks\n5) CSCF/IBCF - Multimedia IP networks\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6354, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Intermediate GPRS Serving Node (IM-GSN)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the possible ordering criteria for the list of Network Performance information? \n\nOptions:\n1) Number of UEs\n2) Communication performance\n3) Mobility performance\n4) Resource usage\n5) Load information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6356, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Number of UEs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat should the UE do when receiving an RRC message on the BCCH, CCCH, PCCH, MCCH or a PC5 RRC message on SBCCH for which the abstract syntax is invalid? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ignore the message\n2) Treat the message as if the field were absent\n3) Apply the generic error handling\n4) Consider the 'parent' field to be set to a not comprehended value\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6359, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Ignore the message", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of providing suitable APIs to a trusted third-party in a 5G network? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allow the third-party to monitor the network slice used for the third-party\n2) To allow the third-party to define and update the set of services and capabilities supported in a network slice used for the third-party\n3) To configure the information which associates a UE to a network slice used for the third-party\n4) To assign a UE to a network slice used for the third-party\n5) To expose broadcasting capabilities to trusted third-party broadcasters' management systems\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6360, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To allow the third-party to define and update the set of services and capabilities supported in a network slice used for the third-party", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Evolved Packet System provide for interworking between fixed access and Evolved Packet Core? \n\nOptions:\n1) Common operational and management procedures\n2) Authentication and authorization for WLAN terminals\n3) Routing different PDN connections through different accesses\n4) Support for offline charging for traffic routed via the Evolved Packet Core\n5) Support for simultaneous access to PLMN services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6375, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Common operational and management procedures", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich entities can be the consumer of the Network Performance Analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) PCF and NEF\n2) NEF and AF\n3) PCF and OAM\n4) NEF and OAM\n5) PCF, NEF, and AF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6376, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  PCF, NEF, and AF", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn Rel-17, how are user-plane resources over a 3GPP access established in supporting an MA PDU Session? \n\nOptions:\n1) They are always established in the 5G core (5GC) network\n2) They are established over a non-3GPP access connected to 5GC\n3) They may be established in EPC connected to 5GC\n4) They can only be established over NG-RAN access\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6377, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  They may be established in EPC connected to 5GC", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich element can use the identifier of the MSC/SGSN to determine the operator selected by a supporting UE or the operator allocated to a UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) MSC/SGSN itself\n2) Serving GW\n3) GGSN/PDN GW\n4) HSS\n5) gsmSCF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6379, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  gsmSCF", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the manufacturer-assigned ID in NAS signalling? \n\nOptions:\n1) To request UE capabilities\n2) To assign UE capabilities dynamically\n3) To reduce signalling overhead\n4) To support non-contiguous carrier aggregation\n5) To pre-provision a set of capabilities\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6385, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To pre-provision a set of capabilities", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich mode of the NF/NF Service Context Transfer Procedures includes an endpoint address? \n\nOptions:\n1) Direct mode\n2) Indirect mode\n3) Push mode\n4) Pull mode\n5) Context mode\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6393, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Indirect mode", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich logical architectures correspond to LIPA? \n\nOptions:\n1) SIPTO@LN with a co-located L-GW in the MeNB\n2) SIPTO@LN with a stand-alone gateway\n3) SIPTO@LN with a co-located L-GW in the SeNB\n4) SIPTO@LN with a shared hybrid cell\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6396, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  SIPTO@LN with a co-located L-GW in the SeNB", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat types of data can be processed by the Management Data Analytics (MDA)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Performance measurements, KPIs, alarms, and network configuration data\n2) Trace/MDT/RLF/RCEF reports and network analytics data\n3) QoE reports and service experience data from AFs\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6409, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can an Evolved ProSe UE-to-Network Relay act as? \n\nOptions:\n1) A network controller\n2) A communication bridge between an Evolved ProSe Remote UE and E-UTRAN\n3) A PLMN\n4) A standalone device\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6414, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  A communication bridge between an Evolved ProSe Remote UE and E-UTRAN", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of a Privacy Exception List for a Target UE Subscriber? \n\nOptions:\n1) To determine which LCS Clients, services, and classes of LCS Clients can position the Target UE\n2) To specify the target subscriber notification setting for each LCS Client and service\n3) To specify the default treatment for location requests from LCS Clients not registered in the list\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6423, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of UE history information in EN-DC? \n\nOptions:\n1) To optimize inter-system load balancing\n2) To enhance coverage and cell edge interference\n3) To avoid Ping Pong effect during handovers\n4) To improve mobility optimization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6425, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To avoid Ping Pong effect during handovers", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the scheduler in MAC in gNB? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allocate physical layer resources for the uplink and the downlink\n2) To manage the sharing of uplink resources between logical channels\n3) To enable coordination of TDM and FDM cell resources between MAC in the gNB and the corresponding entity in the ng-eNB\n4) To provide support for power-aware packet scheduling\n5) To provide support for QoS-aware packet scheduling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6432, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To allocate physical layer resources for the uplink and the downlink", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many sets of 3GPP PS Data Off Exempt Services can be configured by the HPLMN operator? \n\nOptions:\n1) One\n2) Two\n3) Three\n4) Unlimited\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6446, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Two", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the performance objectives for the Evolved Packet System? \n\nOptions:\n1) Higher user data rates and reduced latency\n2) Improved system capacity and coverage\n3) Reduced network complexity and lower operating costs\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6451, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of ACDC (Application Specific Congestion control for Data Communication)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To prevent overload of the access network and/or the core network\n2) To control access to network provided services or functions\n3) To allow/prevent new access attempts from particular applications\n4) To differentiate between CS and PS domains\n5) To specify the categories of subscribers who are barred from network access\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6452, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To allow/prevent new access attempts from particular applications", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the ARQ functionality in the RLC sublayer? \n\nOptions:\n1) Error detection\n2) Segmentation of RLC SDUs\n3) Sequence numbering\n4) Flow control\n5) Error correction\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6463, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Error correction", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following numbering and addressing schemes are supported for IP multimedia sessions? \n\nOptions:\n1) MSISDN and SIP URL\n2) H.324M and GTT\n3) UDI/RDI and MMS\n4) 3.1kHz Ext. PLMN and CS multimedia calls\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6464, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  MSISDN and SIP URL", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat was the transmit diversity technique used in Rel-15 for V2X Phase 2? \n\nOptions:\n1) Modulation\n2) Spatial multiplexing\n3) Beamforming\n4) Channel coding\n5) Small Delay Cyclic Delay Diversity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6470, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Small Delay Cyclic Delay Diversity", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat security measure does the 3GPP system support to protect the transmission for a V2X application? \n\nOptions:\n1) Authentication\n2) Encryption\n3) Integrity protection\n4) Pseudonymity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6476, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Integrity protection", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does a supporting UE determine available core network operators in a shared network? \n\nOptions:\n1) It relies on the SIM/USIM card for information.\n2) It checks the MCC+MNC of each available operator.\n3) It sends a request to the core network nodes.\n4) It decodes the broadcast system information.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6484, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  It decodes the broadcast system information.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat parameter determines the maximum energy detection threshold? \n\nOptions:\n1) Channel bandwidth\n2) Maximum EIRP of the intended transmission(s)\n3) RF output power limit\n4) Channel occupancy time\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6486, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  RF output power limit", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the source RAT do in inter-RAT handover? \n\nOptions:\n1) Configures Target RAT measurement\n2) Decides on the preparation initiation\n3) Provides necessary information to the target RAT\n4) Prepares radio resources in the target RAT\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6490, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat services enable the 5GS to interact with the Messaging Framework? \n\nOptions:\n1) Nmfaf_3caDataManagement Service\n2) Nmfaf_3daDataManagement Service\n3) Ndccf_DataManagement Service\n4) Nnwdaf_DataManagement Service\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6540, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the Access Network called in the SA architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) 4G Access Network\n2) 5G Access Network\n3) LTE Access Network\n4) Non-Stand Alone Network\n5) Stand-Alone Network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6545, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  5G Access Network", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of ProSe Discovery? \n\nOptions:\n1) To relay data for multiple ProSe-enabled UEs.\n2) To establish new communication paths between ProSe-enabled UEs.\n3) To identify ProSe-enabled UEs in proximity of each other.\n4) To enable communication between Public Safety ProSe-enabled UEs.\n5) To enable ProSe-assisted WLAN direct communication.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6557, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To identify ProSe-enabled UEs in proximity of each other.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main distinguishing factor between UMTS QoS classes? \n\nOptions:\n1) Round trip delay\n2) Bit error rate\n3) Transfer delay\n4) Payload content\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6576, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Transfer delay", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the sub-carrier spacing for uplink transmission? \n\nOptions:\n1) 3.75 kHz\n2) 7.5 kHz\n3) 15 kHz\n4) 30 kHz\n5) 60 kHz\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6579, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  15 kHz", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens if the target RAN node cannot support the requirements in User Plane Security Enforcement information? \n\nOptions:\n1) The PDU Session is released\n2) The PDU Session is handed over to the target RAN node\n3) The user's data is encrypted using a different algorithm\n4) The User Plane Security Policy is modified\n5) The request to set up resources for the PDU Session is rejected\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6582, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The request to set up resources for the PDU Session is rejected", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum range of coverage the 5G system should support in low density areas? \n\nOptions:\n1) Up to 50 km\n2) Up to 100 km\n3) Up to 200 km\n4) Up to 500 km\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6585, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Up to 100 km", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can influence the variations on per-instance NF load and resource usage? \n\nOptions:\n1) The Reporting Threshold\n2) The load itself\n3) The Validity Period\n4) The Analytics ID\n5) The number of running NF instances\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6587, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The number of running NF instances", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Support of EAP Re-authentication Protocol for WLAN Interworking feature? \n\nOptions:\n1) Improving WLAN coverage\n2) Enhancing security for WLAN access\n3) Optimizing WLAN connection speed\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6590, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Enhancing security for WLAN access", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Early data transmission feature in NB-IoT? \n\nOptions:\n1) To allow the UE to transmit data in Msg3 of the random access procedure\n2) To improve the accuracy of narrowband measurement\n3) To enable the UE to request NPUSCH resources for BSR transmission\n4) To reduce UE power consumption during cell access\n5) To support small cell deployments with lower maximum transmit power\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6592, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To allow the UE to transmit data in Msg3 of the random access procedure", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich reference point provides similar functionality for online charging as Ro? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ro\n2) CAP\n3) Gy\n4) Re\n5) Rc\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6596, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  CAP", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich network domain does MPS primarily operate in? \n\nOptions:\n1) IP Multimedia Subsystem (IMS) domain\n2) Circuit-switched (CS) domain\n3) Packet-switched (PS) domain\n4) IoT domain\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6597, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Packet-switched (PS) domain", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Plug and Connect (PnC) in network management? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide basic connectivity information to a NE after it is powered up\n2) To enable self-configuration procedures for NEs\n3) To support provisioning capabilities for adjusting network performance\n4) To optimize the services provided over an NG-RAN and 5GC network\n5) To collect and report fulfilment status of closed control loop goals\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6600, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide basic connectivity information to a NE after it is powered up", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Random Access Channel (RACH)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transmit data themselves\n2) Carry control information for HARQ procedures\n3) Carry ACK/NAK feedback\n4) Carry scheduling requests\n5) Indicate resource and other transmission parameters\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6602, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Carry scheduling requests", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat measures does the MPS system support for interactions between interconnected networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) Signalling of MPS priorities\n2) Propagation of MPS session indications\n3) Verification and admission of incoming MPS sessions\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6603, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the IM-MSC in a GLR-equipped VPLMN? \n\nOptions:\n1) To handle location management of roaming subscribers\n2) To relay messages between home network and serving MSC\n3) To handle GTP signalling messages\n4) To optimize signalling traffic between PLMNs\n5) To provide IMS services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6604, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To relay messages between home network and serving MSC", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is one of the key functionalities covered by the 5G data connectivity charging solution? \n\nOptions:\n1) Inter-operator security\n2) UE presence in Presence Reporting Area(s)\n3) Secondary RAT usage reporting\n4) Session and Service Continuity modes\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6609, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Session and Service Continuity modes", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich entities are involved in the PDU Session establishment for supporting HR-SBO in VPLMN? \n\nOptions:\n1) AMF and V-SMF\n2) AMF and H-SMF\n3) UE and H-SMF\n4) UE and V-SMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6612, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  AMF and V-SMF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the formula to calculate the DL and UL max data rate supported by the UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Rmax * maxNumberMIMO-LayersNonCB-PUSCH * supportedModulationOrderUL * scalingFactor * symbolDuration * maxRBallocation * overhead\n2) maxNumberMIMO-LayersPDSCH * supportedModulationOrderDL * scalingFactor * symbolDuration * maxRBallocation * overhead\n3) Rmax * maxNumberMIMO-LayersCB-PUSCH * supportedModulationOrderUL * scalingFactor * symbolDuration * maxRBallocation * overhead\n4) maxNumberMIMO-LayersCB-PUSCH * supportedModulationOrderUL * scalingFactor * symbolDuration * maxRBallocation * overhead\n5) Rmax * maxNumberMIMO-LayersPDSCH * supportedModulationOrderDL * scalingFactor * symbolDuration * maxRBallocation * overhead\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6615, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Rmax * maxNumberMIMO-LayersPDSCH * supportedModulationOrderDL * scalingFactor * symbolDuration * maxRBallocation * overhead", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat enhancements were introduced for reliable delivery of NIDD in Rel-14? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reliable delivery by acknowledgements on a hop-by-hop basis and Reliable Data Service (RDS) between UE and SCEF\n2) Reliable delivery by acknowledgements on a hop-by-hop basis and support for CN overload control\n3) Reliable delivery by acknowledgements on a hop-by-hop basis and improvements to location services for CIoT\n4) Reliable delivery by acknowledgements on a hop-by-hop basis and support for inter-RAT idle mode mobility\n5) Reliable delivery by acknowledgements on a hop-by-hop basis and enhancements to dedicated core networks selection mechanism\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6616, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Reliable delivery by acknowledgements on a hop-by-hop basis and Reliable Data Service (RDS) between UE and SCEF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Recovery/Restoration functionality in the MPS system? \n\nOptions:\n1) To expedite service recovery and restoration after a disruption\n2) To provide priority treatment for supplementary services\n3) To enforce policy control for MPS application services\n4) To prioritize handover of MPS voice calls to CS\n5) To support MPS when roaming outside the home country\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6617, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To expedite service recovery and restoration after a disruption", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich control mechanism allows UEs configured for EAB to access the network under EAB conditions? \n\nOptions:\n1) Access Class Barring\n2) Service Specific Access Control\n3) Extended Access Barring\n4) Overriding Extended Access Barring\n5) Application Specific Congestion Control for Data Communication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6628, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Overriding Extended Access Barring", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich sublayer is responsible for header compression and decompression? \n\nOptions:\n1) MAC sublayer\n2) RLC sublayer\n3) PDCP sublayer\n4) SDAP sublayer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6632, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  PDCP sublayer", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat response indicates that the MS is camped on a non-CAG cell belonging to a PLMN and is only allowed to access 5GS via CAG cells? \n\nOptions:\n1) PLMN not allowed\n2) Temporarily not authorized for this SNPN\n3) EPS services not allowed\n4) 5GS services not allowed\n5) No suitable cell of the selected PLMN or SNPN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6633, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  5GS services not allowed", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of an investigation PLMN scan for a multi-mode terminal? \n\nOptions:\n1) To select a specific VPLMN as the highest priority\n2) To search for a higher prioritized PLMN that does not offer CS voice service\n3) To direct the UE to register on a different VPLMN\n4) To perform periodic network selection attempts\n5) To avoid ping-pong between systems\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6648, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To search for a higher prioritized PLMN that does not offer CS voice service", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can CA be configured for DCP? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only on the PCell\n2) Only on the SCell\n3) On the entire DL frequency of the cell\n4) On both PCell and SCell\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6651, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Only on the PCell", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does a Multi-USIM UE include Paging Restriction Information in the Service Request or Registration Request message? \n\nOptions:\n1) When it wants to restrict all paging\n2) When it wants to restrict paging for voice service only\n3) When it wants to restrict paging for certain PDU session(s)\n4) When it wants to restrict paging for voice service and certain PDU session(s)\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6652, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the SGNB MODIFICATION REQUIRED message in the inter-gNB-DU mobility procedure using MCG SRB in EN-DC? \n\nOptions:\n1) To query the latest SCG configuration from the gNB-CU.\n2) To migrate the IPsec tunnels to new IP outer addresses.\n3) To perform RRC Connection Reconfiguration at the MeNB and UE.\n4) To configure BH RLC channels and BAP-layer route entries on the target path.\n5) To provide information such as data forwarding addresses and new SN security key.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6661, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To provide information such as data forwarding addresses and new SN security key.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Semi-static CFI configuration in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) To improve the reliability of the uplink data channel\n2) To improve the reliability of the downlink data channel\n3) To provide a granular time reference\n4) To allow PDCP packet duplication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6663, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To improve the reliability of the downlink data channel", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the management services required for the assessment of the energy efficiency of 5G networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) Performance management services\n2) Management services for network function provisioning\n3) Management services for Fault Supervision\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6664, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is traffic routing influenced for a 5G VN group? \n\nOptions:\n1) By configuring the UPFs with N19 tunnels\n2) By providing information and DNAIs in an AF request\n3) By establishing VLAN tags for Ethernet PDU Sessions\n4) By selecting a dedicated SMF for the 5G VN group\n5) By subscribing to notification of group status changes\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6682, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  By providing information and DNAIs in an AF request", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the definition of dispatchable location? \n\nOptions:\n1) A location delivered to the PSAP by the network with an emergency service call that consists of the street address of the calling party\n2) The location of the nearest service point\n3) A location obtained at the activation of a Call or PDP Context\n4) A location determined by continuously checking the current location\n5) The location information of a specific target UE at the release of a Call or PDP Context\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6692, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  A location delivered to the PSAP by the network with an emergency service call that consists of the street address of the calling party", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does a UE not expect to be provided pdsch-HARQ-ACK-Codebook = semi-static for multicast HARQ-ACK information? \n\nOptions:\n1) When it is not using HARQ-ACK information\n2) When it is using unicast HARQ-ACK information\n3) When it is using multicast HARQ-ACK information\n4) When it is using dynamic HARQ-ACK information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6697, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  When it is using dynamic HARQ-ACK information", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can the UE skip when responding to a restricted set of bands request? \n\nOptions:\n1) Duplex mode\n2) Feature Set combinations\n3) Capability parameters\n4) Carrier aggregation\n5) Band combinations\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6698, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Band combinations", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the required call type for the 3GPP circuit-switched multimedia call? \n\nOptions:\n1) 3G-324M\n2) UDI/RDI\n3) Speech\n4) H.223 and H.245\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6701, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  3G-324M", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the completeness of charging information in IMS? \n\nOptions:\n1) The processing within the BD.\n2) The generation and processing of charging information.\n3) The tracking of IMS NEs and applications.\n4) The inclusion of IOI identities within SIP signalling.\n5) The aggregation of charging events in the same session.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6706, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The processing within the BD.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Access Class 10? \n\nOptions:\n1) To differentiate between CS and PS domains\n2) To indicate the network access for Emergency Calls\n3) To control UE capabilities\n4) To prevent overload of the access network and/or the core network\n5) To specify the categories of subscribers who are barred from network access\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6714, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To indicate the network access for Emergency Calls", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nA UE monitors PDCCH for scheduling PDSCH receptions for which types of transmissions? \n\nOptions:\n1) Unicast and multicast\n2) Broadcast and multicast\n3) Unicast and broadcast\n4) Multicast and SPS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6721, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Multicast and SPS", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the entity that handles the user data in the 5G System architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) User Equipment (UE)\n2) (Radio) Access Network [(R)AN]\n3) User Plane Function (UPF)\n4) (External) Data Network (DN)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6722, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  User Plane Function (UPF)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can N2 overload control be achieved by the AMF? \n\nOptions:\n1) By adjusting the weight factor of the AMF\n2) By invoking the N2 overload procedure to 5G-AN nodes\n3) By sending a Control Plane data back-off timer to the UE\n4) By using Session Management Congestion Control Experience analytics provided by NWDAF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6727, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  By invoking the N2 overload procedure to 5G-AN nodes", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used to support mobility and bearer management between the MME and S-GW? \n\nOptions:\n1) S1-MME-interface\n2) S1-U-interface\n3) S11-interface\n4) S6a-interface\n5) S5-interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6735, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  S11-interface", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Service Enabler Architecture Layer (SEAL)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To offer common services to the verticals industry applications and V2X applications\n2) To provide enhanced functionalities for cyber-physical control applications\n3) To support network and application enablement for verticals\n4) To enable non-public networks and private networks\n5) To enhance the 5GC Location Services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6737, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To offer common services to the verticals industry applications and V2X applications", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn a shared network, how can the share of usage of the shared core network node(s) between the sharing partners be distinguished? \n\nOptions:\n1) By the number of PLMN-id lists broadcasted by the network\n2) By the location of the core network node\n3) By the type of radio access technology used\n4) By the identity of the serving core network operator\n5) By the network allocation process\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6739, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  By the identity of the serving core network operator", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the PCF include the Duplicated notification indication in the PCC rule? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the AF initiates an AF session\n2) When the PCF makes the policy decision\n3) When the L-PSA UPF detects a QoS monitoring event\n4) When the AF revokes the AF session\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6741, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  When the PCF makes the policy decision", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the SN-CU-UP send to the SN-CU-CP after receiving the BEARER CONTEXT MODIFICATION REQUEST message? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMPLETE\n2) UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION REQUEST\n3) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMMAND\n4) BEARER CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE\n5) UE CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6744, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  BEARER CONTEXT MODIFICATION RESPONSE", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of data does NWDAF collect from AF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Application ID\n2) Performance data\n3) Network data\n4) QoS profile\n5) Service data\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6750, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Service data", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of the Core Network Bearer Service? \n\nOptions:\n1) To connect the UMTS CN Edge Node with the CN Gateway\n2) To provide radio access to the user data\n3) To segment and reassemble user flows\n4) To handle the layer 1/Layer2 functionality\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6752, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To connect the UMTS CN Edge Node with the CN Gateway", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does AMF stand for in the 5G System? \n\nOptions:\n1) Access and Mobility Function\n2) Authentication and Management Function\n3) Application and Media Function\n4) Authorization and Monitoring Function\n5) Association and Maintenance Function\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6755, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Access and Mobility Function", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich feature introduces a new type of transmission point that only transmits PRS? \n\nOptions:\n1) OTDOA enhancements in shared physical cell identity scenario\n2) PRS based Beacon\n3) PRS plus CRS measurement for OTDOA\n4) Multipath Time of Arrival (ToA)\n5) Reduced quantization error\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6759, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  PRS based Beacon", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is dispersion analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) A method to predict QoS attributes for UEs\n2) A technique to analyze the location of user equipment (UE)\n3) An approach to rank hot locations based on data volume\n4) A method to analyze data traffic patterns in a network slice\n5) A technique to limit access to an area of interest based on UE activity\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6760, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  A method to analyze data traffic patterns in a network slice", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NWDAF provide to the NF in response to the Nnwdaf_AnalyticsInfo_Request or Nnwdaf_AnalyticsSubscription_Subscribe Request? \n\nOptions:\n1) Measurement information for the requested location\n2) Analytics for congestion\n3) Notification for analytics\n4) UE mobility event notification\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6762, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Analytics for congestion", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn a shared UTRAN/GERAN network, what does the RAN node do when the UE is allowed to attach? \n\nOptions:\n1) The RAN node forwards the NAS message to the UE and cleans up any stored redirect data\n2) The RAN node selects a CN node based on the NRI received from the UE\n3) The RAN node sends a Reroute Command message to the Core Network\n4) The RAN node queries the SGSN to determine if the UE is allowed to attach\n5) The RAN node sends an ATTACH REQUEST message to the network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6763, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The RAN node forwards the NAS message to the UE and cleans up any stored redirect data", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Flexible eNB-ID and Cell-ID feature in E-UTRAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support SRS switching on PUSCH-less TDD CCs\n2) To enable switching between TDD and FDD CCs\n3) To achieve interference cancellation within one cell\n4) To facilitate flexible identification of eNB and cell\n5) To define power control parameters for SRS transmission\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6769, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To facilitate flexible identification of eNB and cell", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the common functional architecture called that supports mission critical services? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 22.281\n2) TS 22.282\n3) MCImp-MC_VIDEO\n4) MCImp-MC_ARCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6775, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  MCImp-MC_ARCH", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Fast Spherical Coverage Method? \n\nOptions:\n1) To calculate the CDF of the EIRP/EIS distribution in 3D\n2) To determine the total power radiated by the DUT in the TX beam peak direction\n3) To determine the RX beam peak direction\n4) To reduce the test time for Tx and Rx spherical coverage measurements\n5) To perform RSRP scans for RX beam peak direction\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6776, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To reduce the test time for Tx and Rx spherical coverage measurements", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the aim of MINT? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable a UE to obtain service from a PLMN offering Disaster Roaming service\n2) To enable a UE to obtain service from any PLMN\n3) To enable a UE to obtain service from a PLMN without Disaster Roaming service\n4) To enable a UE to obtain service from a 4G network\n5) To enable a UE to obtain service from a 3G network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6777, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable a UE to obtain service from a PLMN offering Disaster Roaming service", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the BSC indicate the selected core network operator to the CN for supporting UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) By transmitting it in the GUTI\n2) By sending the PLMN-id in broadcast system information\n3) By acquiring it from the RAN Selected CN operator\n4) By sending the PLMN-index in dedicated signalling\n5) By selecting the CN operator using the NRI bits from the TLLI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6781, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  By sending the PLMN-index in dedicated signalling", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of PDU Session traffic analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) To determine the load and signaling caused by requesting Any UE.\n2) To provide statistics on whether traffic of UEs via one or multiple PDU sessions is according to the information provided by the service consumer.\n3) To predict future traffic patterns based on historical data.\n4) To monitor the location of UEs where PDU Session traffic is monitored.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6790, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To provide statistics on whether traffic of UEs via one or multiple PDU sessions is according to the information provided by the service consumer.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat case is described in TS 38.304 for PLMN selection? \n\nOptions:\n1) E-UTRA and NB-IoT case\n2) UTRA case\n3) GSM case\n4) CDMA2000 case\n5) NR case\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6799, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  NR case", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens during times of severe congestion when it is necessary to drop packets on a media QoS Flow? \n\nOptions:\n1) MPS packets are dropped first\n2) IMS Signalling packets are dropped first\n3) Non-priority packets are dropped first\n4) Mission Critical services packets are dropped first\n5) Priority sessions packets are dropped first\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6806, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Non-priority packets are dropped first", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a UE do with a BWP inactivity timer for a cell when the timer is running? \n\nOptions:\n1) Increments the timer at the end of a subframe or half subframe\n2) Suspends the timer during active UL/DL BWP changes\n3) Decrements the timer at the end of a subframe or half subframe\n4) Resets the timer every subframe or half subframe\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6828, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Decrements the timer at the end of a subframe or half subframe", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the conditions for network determined user busy in IMS Multimedia Telephony? \n\nOptions:\n1) Maximum number of total communications permitted has been reached\n2) Maximum number of simultaneous media streams supported at the given subscriber's interface(s) has been reached\n3) Maximum bandwidth supported at the given subscriber's interface(s) has been reached\n4) Subscriber making himself 'busy' in a subscriber profile, involved in the incoming multimedia telephony session\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6831, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat service does RRC expect from lower layers? \n\nOptions:\n1) Broadcast of common control information\n2) Notification of UEs in RRC_IDLE\n3) Transfer of dedicated signalling\n4) Integrity protection, ciphering, and loss-less in-sequence delivery of information without duplication\n5) Broadcast of positioning assistance data\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6834, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Integrity protection, ciphering, and loss-less in-sequence delivery of information without duplication", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does CA stand for in the context of RRC? \n\nOptions:\n1) Code Assignment\n2) Channel Allocation\n3) Cell Association\n4) Connection Admission\n5) Carrier Aggregation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6836, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Carrier Aggregation", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nUnder which conditions can the EAS re-discovery in VPLMN be triggered? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE mobility only\n2) AF interacting with VPLMN only\n3) AF interacting with HPLMN only\n4) UE mobility and AF interaction with VPLMN or HPLMN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6839, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  UE mobility and AF interaction with VPLMN or HPLMN", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the minimum period of message transmission supported for sidelink? \n\nOptions:\n1) 10 ms\n2) 20 ms\n3) 30 ms\n4) 40 ms\n5) 50 ms\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6840, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  20 ms", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main concern in AV production applications? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transmitting data to a mass audience.\n2) Amplifying defects in the transmitted data.\n3) Using numerous wireless devices.\n4) Capturing and transmitting data with a high degree of confidence.\n5) Post-processing data with filters.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6842, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Capturing and transmitting data with a high degree of confidence.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich component provides priority handling for the Initial UE Message during Registration procedures? \n\nOptions:\n1) (R)AN\n2) PCF\n3) UPF\n4) SMF\n5) AMF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6856, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  AMF", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich aspects of the Model Training function are out of RAN3 scope? \n\nOptions:\n1) Data pre-processing and cleaning\n2) Data formatting and transformation\n3) How inputs are used to train a model\n4) All aspects of the Model Training function\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6859, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  How inputs are used to train a model", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich function receives charging events from the CTF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Rating Function (RF)\n2) Charging Gateway Function (CGF)\n3) Charging Enablement Function (CEF)\n4) Account Balance Management Function (ABMF)\n5) Charging Data Function (CDF)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6877, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Charging Data Function (CDF)", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the default treatment for positioning requests? \n\nOptions:\n1) Accept the positioning request\n2) Reject the positioning attempt\n3) Always notify the target UE user\n4) Depends on the Target UE Subscription Profile\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6882, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Reject the positioning attempt", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich models are constructed for LOS channel profiles? \n\nOptions:\n1) CDL-A and CDL-B\n2) CDL-C and CDL-D\n3) CDL-D and CDL-E\n4) CDL-E and CDL-F\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6888, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  CDL-D and CDL-E", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the MPS code/identifier used for? \n\nOptions:\n1) To configure the UE for MPS in 5GS\n2) To indicate the status of the MPS session\n3) To establish priority treatment in the terminating network\n4) To request MPS in the session origination request\n5) To indicate a voice fallback in 5GS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6889, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To request MPS in the session origination request", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can the UE trigger reporting of its RLM and BFD relaxation status? \n\nOptions:\n1) When the RLM and BFD relaxation status changes\n2) During the on-duration\n3) When the serving cell changes\n4) On every DRX cycle\n5) Whenever the UE wakes up\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6901, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  When the RLM and BFD relaxation status changes", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Mobile Communication System for Railways? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide communication capabilities beyond what legacy systems support\n2) To increase data rates and reduce data latencies\n3) To improve communication reliability and provide multimedia communication\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6909, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the possible classifications of OFDM symbols in a slot in a downlink frame? \n\nOptions:\n1) 'downlink', 'flexible', or 'uplink'\n2) 'downlink' or 'flexible' symbols\n3) 'uplink' or 'flexible' symbols\n4) 'downlink' or 'uplink' symbols\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6912, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  'downlink' or 'flexible' symbols", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of sequence and cyclic shift hopping in PUCCH formats 0, 1, 3, and 4? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide frequency diversity in the PUCCH transmission.\n2) To improve the orthogonality of the transmitted signals.\n3) To adapt the PUCCH transmission to the channel conditions.\n4) To reduce the interference between PUCCH transmissions.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6923, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To reduce the interference between PUCCH transmissions.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the BEARER CONTEXT SETUP REQUEST message in the UE Initial Access procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) To request the setup of the bearer context in the gNB-CU-UP\n2) To initiate the signalling flow for UE Initial access\n3) To allocate F1-U UL TEID and transport layer address\n4) To send the BEARER CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE message to the gNB-CU-CP\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6939, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To request the setup of the bearer context in the gNB-CU-UP", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn a 5G system with satellite access, what information should charging call records associated with satellite access include? \n\nOptions:\n1) Location of the UE\n2) Type of authentication mechanism\n3) Used frequency bands\n4) Access type (e.g. 3GPP, non-3GPP, satellite)\n5) Indirect network connection\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6956, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Location of the UE", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIs a cell in energySaving state considered as a cell outage or a fault condition? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes\n2) No\n3) Only during peak traffic hours\n4) Only in rural areas\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6963, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  No", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the work item for Non-IP for Cellular IoT for EC-EGPRS? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support Non-IP Data Delivery using SCEF and SGi\n2) To introduce support for PDN/PDP Type Non-IP\n3) To optimize the GGSN IP address allocation\n4) To improve inter-RAT mobility\n5) To configure APN rate control for CIoT Optimization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6965, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To support Non-IP Data Delivery using SCEF and SGi", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the role of the Edge Enabler Server (EES) in enabling edge applications? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide configurations to the Edge Configuration Server\n2) To support service provisioning for UE\n3) To expose EES capability as APIs to EAS\n4) To enable service continuity during UE mobility\n5) To enable discovery of Edge Application Servers\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6972, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To expose EES capability as APIs to EAS", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is one of the requirements for differentiated paging in the Evolved Packet System? \n\nOptions:\n1) Support for efficient streaming services\n2) No loss of data during handovers between different access systems\n3) Support for network resource utilization based on context information\n4) Support for resilient multicast and broadcast services\n5) Support for a distinction between voice and non-voice over E-UTRAN traffic\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6977, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Support for a distinction between voice and non-voice over E-UTRAN traffic", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does MPS prioritize in the PS domain when the network does not support the requested service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Data bearer services only\n2) Voice and Video services only\n3) IMS services only\n4) Voice services only\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6991, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Voice services only", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat modifications were made to PC5 for V2V use cases? \n\nOptions:\n1) Additional DMRS symbols\n2) New arrangement of scheduling assignment and data resources\n3) Enhancements for high speed and high density\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 6995, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identifier is used to uniquely identify the UE within the AMF? \n\nOptions:\n1) SUPI\n2) PEI\n3) 5G-GUTI\n4) GUAMI\n5) AMF UE NGAP ID\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7005, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  AMF UE NGAP ID", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nUnder what conditions will a UE provide a valid CSI report for the n-th triggered report? \n\nOptions:\n1) If the first uplink symbol to carry the corresponding CSI report(s) starts earlier than at symbol Zref\n2) If the first uplink symbol to carry the n-th CSI report starts earlier than at symbol Z'ref(n)\n3) If the PUSCH indicated by the DCI is overlapping with another PUCCH or PUSCH\n4) If the number of triggered reports is one and no HARQ-ACK or transport block is multiplexed on the PUSCH\n5) If the PDCCH reception includes two PDCCH candidates from two respective search space sets\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7012, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  If the first uplink symbol to carry the corresponding CSI report(s) starts earlier than at symbol Zref", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does ThreshBackhRateDLWLAN, Low represent? \n\nOptions:\n1) The WLAN channel utilization threshold for traffic steering from E-UTRAN to WLAN.\n2) The WLAN RSSI threshold for traffic steering from WLAN to E-UTRAN.\n3) The backhaul available uplink bandwidth threshold for traffic steering from E-UTRAN to WLAN.\n4) The backhaul available downlink bandwidth threshold for traffic steering from E-UTRAN to WLAN.\n5) The backhaul available downlink bandwidth threshold for traffic steering from WLAN to E-UTRAN.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7022, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The backhaul available downlink bandwidth threshold for traffic steering from WLAN to E-UTRAN.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the duration of a frame in the downlink? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1 ms\n2) 2 ms\n3) 5 ms\n4) 10 ms\n5) 14 ms\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7024, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  10 ms", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can RLM and BFD relaxation be enabled? \n\nOptions:\n1) On per serving cell basis\n2) On per Cell Group basis\n3) On per UE basis\n4) On per DRX group basis\n5) On per frequency basis\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7027, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  On per Cell Group basis", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum rank supported with slot/subslot PDSCH repetition in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) 1\n2) 2\n3) 3\n4) 4\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7028, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  2", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat assistance information may reduce UE's power consumption? \n\nOptions:\n1) Mobility history information\n2) Power preferred information\n3) SCell configuration information\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7045, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the RRM requirements enhancements introduced in Rel-16 for connected mode at a velocity of 500km/h? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reduced cell identification delay\n2) Reduced cell detection delay\n3) Reduced measurement period\n4) Enhanced UL timing adjustment\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7056, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens to a call on hold after voice call continuity has been performed? \n\nOptions:\n1) The call on hold is terminated\n2) The call on hold is re-established\n3) The call on hold is transferred to the IMS domain\n4) The call on hold is transferred to another party on the call\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7063, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The call on hold is re-established", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Time Sensitive Communication Assistance Information (TSCAI) in the support of NR Industrial Internet of Things? \n\nOptions:\n1) To measure packet delay between UE and PSA UPF\n2) To provide information about TSC traffic characteristics for more efficient scheduling\n3) To support strict synchronization accuracy requirements of TSC applications\n4) To enhance the inter UE transmission prioritization and multiplexing\n5) To optimize handling of a mixture of URLLC and eMBB traffic\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7070, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To provide information about TSC traffic characteristics for more efficient scheduling", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich high-level EE KPIs are used to calculate the energy efficiency of 5G networks? \n\nOptions:\n1) EEMN,DV\n2) EEMN,CoA\n3) EEMN,TCP\n4) EECAT,DV\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7077, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  EEMN,DV", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is VarPendingRNA-Update used for? \n\nOptions:\n1) To store the result of an RNA update procedure\n2) To indicate the completion of an RNA update procedure\n3) To indicate the success of an RNA update procedure\n4) To store the information required for an RNA update procedure\n5) To indicate the presence of a pending RNA update procedure\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7085, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To indicate the presence of a pending RNA update procedure", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich types of requirements are defined for Enhanced Mobile Broadband (eMBB) in 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) Low latency and high service availability\n2) High traffic densities of devices\n3) Higher data rates and traffic/connection density\n4) Flexible network operations\n5) Efficient content delivery\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7090, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Higher data rates and traffic/connection density", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the redundancy handling of a PDU Session in URLLC? \n\nOptions:\n1) The presence of PDU Session Pair ID and/or RSN in the PDU Session Establishment Request.\n2) The QoS Flow authorized by the PCF and the user subscription.\n3) The operator configuration of UPF selection for disjoint paths.\n4) The S-NSSAI, DNN, and local policy configuration in the SMF.\n5) The capability of NG-RAN to support redundant transmission on N3/N9 interfaces.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7093, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The presence of PDU Session Pair ID and/or RSN in the PDU Session Establishment Request.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat lists can be stored on the SIM/USIM card for network selection? \n\nOptions:\n1) Allowed PLMNs and forbidden PLMNs\n2) HPLMN and EHPLMN\n3) User Controlled PLMN Selector list and Operator Controlled PLMN Selector list\n4) Forbidden LAs and forbidden TAs\n5) Preferred PLMNs and supported services\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7094, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  User Controlled PLMN Selector list and Operator Controlled PLMN Selector list", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich architecture can support local breakout roaming? \n\nOptions:\n1) Roaming architecture with home-routed traffic\n2) Non-roaming architecture\n3) Local breakout roaming architecture for interworking between ePDG/EPC and 5GS\n4) Local breakout roaming architecture for interworking between 5GS and EPC/E-UTRA\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7095, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Local breakout roaming architecture for interworking between 5GS and EPC/E-UTRA", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the gNB-DU include in the UE CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE message? \n\nOptions:\n1) Suspend configuration\n2) RLC/MAC/PHY configuration\n3) SRB ID\n4) PAGING message\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7136, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  RLC/MAC/PHY configuration", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn Rel-17, how are load-balancing split percentages determined? \n\nOptions:\n1) They are fixed and pre-defined by the network\n2) They are based on the network's strong steering requirements\n3) They are determined by the UE and UPF using RTT measurements\n4) They are always 50% on 3GPP access and 50% on non-3GPP access\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7148, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  They are determined by the UE and UPF using RTT measurements", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat message does the UE send to initiate the initial access procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) RRC_CONNECTION_SETUP_COMPLETE\n2) RRCSetup\n3) RRCSetupRequest\n4) SecurityModeCommand\n5) RRCReconfiguration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7160, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  RRCSetupRequest", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of IOI concept in inter-operator charging? \n\nOptions:\n1) To aggregate charging events generated by CTF while they belong to the same session.\n2) To correlate charging information for the same resource usage.\n3) To enable different operators involved in IMS sessions to identify each other.\n4) To determine the completeness of charging information in IMS.\n5) To track IMS NEs and applications generating charging information.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7164, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To enable different operators involved in IMS sessions to identify each other.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Backbone Network Service? \n\nOptions:\n1) To handle control signalling\n2) To manage QoS\n3) To connect the UMTS CN Edge Node with the CN Gateway\n4) To provide layer 1/Layer2 functionality\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7166, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To provide layer 1/Layer2 functionality", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich 5G usage includes the operational aspects that apply to the wide range of IoT devices and services anticipated in the 5G timeframe? \n\nOptions:\n1) Enhanced Mobile Broadband (eMBB)\n2) Critical Communications (CC)\n3) Ultra Reliable and Low Latency Communications (URLLC)\n4) Massive Internet of Things (mIoT)\n5) Flexible network operations\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7171, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Massive Internet of Things (mIoT)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is the location request processed with the highest priority level? \n\nOptions:\n1) For all location requests\n2) Only for emergency services\n3) Only for PLMN operator Services\n4) For location requests towards the user\u2019s Target UE\n5) For location requests towards her own Target UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7173, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Only for emergency services", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the impact on latency with the reduction of antenna ports? \n\nOptions:\n1) Positive impact\n2) No impact\n3) Negative impact\n4) Significant impact\n5) Variable impact\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7180, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Negative impact", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the range of frequencies for the operating band unwanted emissions? \n\nOptions:\n1) From 30 MHz to the fifth harmonic of the upper frequency edge of the DL operating band\n2) From the channel edge up to frequencies separated from the channel edge by 200% of the necessary bandwidth\n3) From the assigned channel frequency to an adjacent channel frequency\n4) From the channel edge up to frequencies separated from the channel edge by 100% of the necessary bandwidth\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7188, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  From the channel edge up to frequencies separated from the channel edge by 200% of the necessary bandwidth", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of a Local Coordinate System (LCS) in the context of a Global Coordinate System (GCS)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To determine the polarized field components\n2) To define the orientation of the array with respect to the GCS\n3) To map the vector fields of the array elements from the GCS to the LCS\n4) To compute the composite rotation matrix\n5) To define the vector far-field of each antenna element in an array\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7194, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To define the vector far-field of each antenna element in an array", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich type of IOI is used between the home IMS network operator and a service provider? \n\nOptions:\n1) Type 1 IOI\n2) Type 2 IOI\n3) Type 3 IOI\n4) Type 4 IOI\n5) Type 5 IOI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7199, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Type 3 IOI", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the NSSRG information in UE subscription? \n\nOptions:\n1) To indicate which S-NSSAIs can be simultaneously provided to the UE in the Allowed NSSAI\n2) To limit the aggregate data rate per UE across all QoS Flows for all PDU sessions associated with a slice\n3) To monitor the data rate per Network Slice\n4) To provide Target NSSAI and RFSP to RAN to steer the UE to another cell\n5) To allocate resources to a slice in case of slice resources shortage\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7209, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To indicate which S-NSSAIs can be simultaneously provided to the UE in the Allowed NSSAI", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Paging Restriction feature in Multi-USIM? \n\nOptions:\n1) To request the network to not page the UE for any MT service.\n2) To request the network to only page the UE for voice service.\n3) To request the network to page the UE for specific traffic arriving on selected PDU Session / PDN Connection.\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7210, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich 3GPP specification specifies the security aspects of application layer support of the Edge Applications? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.501\n2) TS 23.558\n3) TS 28.538\n4) TS 33.558\n5) TS 24.558\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7222, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  TS 33.558", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the channel coding scheme used for transport blocks in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Polar Coding\n2) Convolutional Coding\n3) Turbo Coding\n4) Reed-Solomon Coding\n5) Cyclic Redundancy Check\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7242, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Turbo Coding", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere is the Charging Trigger Function (CTF) located in the distributed CTF architecture for offline charging? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE\n2) Network Element\n3) Service Element\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7252, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  UE", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich physical channel carries the uplink scheduling grant and the sidelink scheduling grant? \n\nOptions:\n1) PHICH\n2) EPDCCH\n3) MPDCCH\n4) PDCCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7255, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  PDCCH", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of IUC in NR Sidelink enhancement? \n\nOptions:\n1) To indicate QoS requirements\n2) To enable inter-UE coordination\n3) To support power saving\n4) To provide relay selection\n5) To handle network authorization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7261, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To enable inter-UE coordination", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich measurements are agreed to be introduced for SL Positioning using SL PRS measurements? \n\nOptions:\n1) SL RSRQ measurement\n2) SL RTOA measurement\n3) SL RSSI measurement\n4) SL RSRP measurement\n5) SL CQI measurement\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7267, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  SL RSRP measurement", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can an NG-RAN node do with the paging enhancements mechanism? \n\nOptions:\n1) Page all UEs within a cell\n2) Page specific UE groups\n3) Page UE(s) in a restricted area using certain SSB(s)\n4) Page UEs located in neighboring cells\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7274, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Page UE(s) in a restricted area using certain SSB(s)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is V2X authorization between the UE and the V2X Control Function conducted? \n\nOptions:\n1) Over the V1 interface\n2) Over the V2 interface\n3) Over the V3 interface\n4) Over the V4 interface\n5) Over the V5 interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7278, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Over the V3 interface", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens if the UE ignores the scheduling DCI when the first uplink symbol to carry the corresponding CSI report(s) starts earlier than at symbol Zref? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UE may ignore the scheduling DCI if no HARQ-ACK or transport block is multiplexed on the PUSCH\n2) The UE is not required to update the CSI for the n-th triggered CSI report\n3) The UE may ignore the scheduling DCI if the number of triggered reports is one and no HARQ-ACK or transport block is multiplexed on the PUSCH\n4) The UE should transmit the CSI report(s) on the PUSCH indicated by the DCI\n5) The UE should provide a valid CSI report for the n-th triggered report\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7288, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The UE may ignore the scheduling DCI if no HARQ-ACK or transport block is multiplexed on the PUSCH", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen is AS security applied in the SDT procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) Before initiating the SDT procedure.\n2) During the ongoing SDT procedure.\n3) After successful completion of the SDT procedure.\n4) Before the UE transitions to RRC_IDLE state.\n5) Before the UE transitions to RRC_CONNECTED state.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7296, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  During the ongoing SDT procedure.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat needs to be changed or added based on the analytics information of Application AI/ML traffic transmission status? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE equipment\n2) UPF\n3) AF\n4) PCF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7307, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  UPF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the typical height of base stations in the UMi scenario? \n\nOptions:\n1) 10m\n2) 25m\n3) 1.5-2.5m\n4) 2-3m\n5) Not specified\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7310, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  10m", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the main characteristic of 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) Mobile Edge Computing\n2) Deeper use of Network Slicing\n3) Introduction of a new radio interface\n4) Network Capability Exposure\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7311, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Introduction of a new radio interface", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat information does the EAS address and DNAI Mapping Information record in UDR provide? \n\nOptions:\n1) EAS address information\n2) DNAI mapping information\n3) DNN and S-NSSAI\n4) AF Identifier\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7315, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  DNAI mapping information", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the gNB-CU in the NG-RAN architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) To connect gNBs to the 5GC\n2) To interconnect gNBs through the Xn interface\n3) To consist of a gNB-CU-CP and one or more gNB-CU-UPs\n4) To establish a wireless backhaul connection with IAB nodes\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7330, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To connect gNBs to the 5GC", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the SL-AccessInfo-L2U2N-r17 IE include? \n\nOptions:\n1) Radio information for L2 U2N relay operation\n2) Radio information for L3 U2N relay operation\n3) Radio information for L1 U2N relay operation\n4) Radio information for L2 N2U relay operation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7333, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Radio information for L2 U2N relay operation", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the observed ranges of BS energy savings when SSB and/or SIB is saved from one carrier of two carriers? \n\nOptions:\n1) 5.1%~98.4%\n2) 1.0%~7.9%\n3) 0.3%~5.7%\n4) 3.0%~58.4%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7335, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  5.1%~98.4%", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Transport of NAS Messages in RRC? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable reliable and in-sequence delivery of NAS messages\n2) To facilitate handover without packet loss\n3) To ensure proper synchronization between the UE and the network\n4) To support encryption and decryption of NAS messages\n5) To enable multi-hop communication in non-terrestrial networks\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7339, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable reliable and in-sequence delivery of NAS messages", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich IE shall be included in the Attach request message if the MS supports at least one positioning method for the provision of location services (LCS) via the PS domain in Gb-mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) Old P-TMSI signature\n2) Requested READY timer value\n3) TMSI status\n4) PS LCS Capability\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7340, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  PS LCS Capability", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the three aspects that voice and video enhancements in RAN2 and RAN3 focus on? \n\nOptions:\n1) RAN-assisted codec adaptation, VoLTE/ViLTE signalling optimization, and voice/video coverage enhancement\n2) UL/DL bitrate recommendation, PUSCH enhancement mode, and multi-subframe channel estimation\n3) RobVoLTE, QCI-1 bearer setup, and handover thresholds\n4) LTE radio signal improvement, CS fallback, and UE-1MSC communication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7346, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  RAN-assisted codec adaptation, VoLTE/ViLTE signalling optimization, and voice/video coverage enhancement", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWho can obtain priority access to the next available radio channel in MPS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only PLMN users\n2) Only MPS Service Provider network\n3) Qualified and authorized users\n4) Only machine interactions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7365, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Qualified and authorized users", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum number of MR-DC combinations for IDC? \n\nOptions:\n1) 256\n2) 64\n3) 512\n4) 128\n5) 1024\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7370, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  512", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat types of LCS responses are there? \n\nOptions:\n1) Immediate and deferred\n2) Internal and external\n3) Successful and failed\n4) Regional and national\n5) Mobile assisted and mobile based\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7378, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Immediate and deferred", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich statement is true regarding the IMS Multimedia Telephony service? \n\nOptions:\n1) It is limited to only including speech as a media component.\n2) It supports real-time video and file transfer.\n3) It does not include supplementary services.\n4) It can only be used for point-to-point communication.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7383, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  It supports real-time video and file transfer.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can the Hosting E-UTRAN/NG-RAN Operator control in terms of resource usage? \n\nOptions:\n1) Signalling traffic and user traffic independently\n2) User traffic only\n3) Signalling traffic only\n4) Resource allocation for each Participating Operator\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7385, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Signalling traffic and user traffic independently", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat functions are supported by the HeNB GW? \n\nOptions:\n1) Relaying UE-associated S1 application part messages\n2) Terminating non-UE associated S1 application part procedures\n3) Optionally terminating S1-U interface with the HeNB and with the S-GW\n4) Supporting TAC and PLMN ID used by the HeNB\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7392, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Media Handling Extensions of IMS-based Telepresence work item? \n\nOptions:\n1) To introduce password protection for activation of supplementary services in IMS\n2) To specify eMBMS enhancements for LTE\n3) To provide media handling extensions for IMS-based telepresence\n4) To introduce the support of end-to-end eCall over IMS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7397, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To provide media handling extensions for IMS-based telepresence", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the tdd-UL-DL-ConfigurationCommon provide? \n\nOptions:\n1) Slot configuration period\n2) Reference SCS configuration\n3) Number of downlink symbols\n4) Number of uplink symbols\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7399, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Reference SCS configuration", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich series of documents in 3GPP documentation focus on LTE, LTE-Advanced, and LTE-Advanced Pro radio technology?\n\nOptions:\n1) 36.xxx\n2) 37.xxx\n3) 38.xxx\n4) 36.xxx and 37.xxx\n5) 37.xxx and 38.xxx\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7401, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  36.xxx", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nAre there any impacts on legacy UEs if the spatial element adaptation is used on a UE-specific basis? \n\nOptions:\n1) Yes, there is a positive impact\n2) No, there is no impact\n3) Yes, there is a negative impact\n4) Yes, there is a significant impact\n5) Yes, there is a variable impact\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7408, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  No, there is no impact", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of QoS Monitoring in the enhancement of URLLC support in the 5G Core network? \n\nOptions:\n1) To measure packet delay between UE and PSA UPF\n2) To calculate the core network Packet Delay Budget (CN PDB)\n3) To provide support for up to eight simultaneously active semi-persistent scheduling (SPS) configurations\n4) To support accurate reference timing delivery for Time Sensitive Communications\n5) To enhance the inter UE transmission prioritization and multiplexing\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7409, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To measure packet delay between UE and PSA UPF", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specification defines the functions of NG-RAN? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 23.501\n2) TS 36.300\n3) TS 38.300\n4) TS 38.305\n5) TS 38.400\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7411, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS 38.300", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is the packet delay measured for a QoS Flow in URLLC? \n\nOptions:\n1) By performing end-to-end UL/DL packet delay measurement between UE and PSA UPF.\n2) By estimating the RAN part of UL/DL packet delay based on QoS Monitoring request from SMF.\n3) By performing GTP-U Echo Request/Response for the corresponding transport path.\n4) By activating QoS monitoring for GTP-U path between UPF and (R)AN.\n5) By mapping QoS Flows to appropriate network instances based on QoS monitoring results.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7415, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By performing GTP-U Echo Request/Response for the corresponding transport path.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are physical resource blocks defined? \n\nOptions:\n1) consecutive OFDM symbols in the frequency domain\n2) consecutive subcarriers in the time domain\n3) consecutive subcarriers in the frequency domain\n4) consecutive OFDM symbols in the time domain\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7420, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  consecutive subcarriers in the frequency domain", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can a UE be provided for scrambling the CRC of multicast DCI formats for scheduling PDSCH receptions? \n\nOptions:\n1) G-RNTIs\n2) G-CS-RNTIs\n3) MCCH-RNTIs\n4) C-RNTIs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7428, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  G-RNTIs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich document contains the requirements needed for the 5G system to support 5G LAN-type services? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 22.261\n2) TS 23.501\n3) TS 23.502\n4) TS 23.503\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7429, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  TS 22.261", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nUnder what conditions can target UEs making an emergency call be positioned? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only if the privacy attribute value allows positioning\n2) Only if there is no privacy attribute value set\n3) Always\n4) Never\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7435, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Always", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does a supporting UE select a core network operator to serve it in a shared network? \n\nOptions:\n1) The shared network selects an operator for the UE.\n2) The UE selects an operator from the available CN operators.\n3) The RAN routes the UE to an available CN node.\n4) The BSC/RNC/eNodeB relays the chosen operator to the core network node.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7439, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The UE selects an operator from the available CN operators.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich series of documents in 3GPP documentation focus on multiple radio access technology aspects?\n\nOptions:\n1) 36.xxx\n2) 37.xxx\n3) 38.xxx\n4) 36.xxx and 37.xxx\n5) 37.xxx and 38.xxx\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7441, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  37.xxx", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nFor V2X communication over LTE-Uu, how can a UE receive V2X messages? \n\nOptions:\n1) Via downlink broadcast\n2) Via uplink unicast\n3) Via downlink unicast or broadcast\n4) Via uplink broadcast\n5) Via P2P connection\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7445, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Via downlink unicast or broadcast", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat factors does the 5G-AN node consider for selecting a TNL association for the AMF for the initial N2 message? \n\nOptions:\n1) Availability of TNL associations\n2) Weight factors of TNL associations\n3) Availability and weight factors of TNL associations\n4) Weight factors and AMF preferences\n5) Availability and AMF preferences\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7446, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Availability and weight factors of TNL associations", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a mobile base station relay? \n\nOptions:\n1) A mobile base station acting as a relay between a UE and the 5G network\n2) A mobile base station that uses PC5-based link to provide indirect connection to remote UEs\n3) A mobile base station that provides 5G access for UEs inside a vehicle\n4) A mobile base station that supports multi-hop relay scenarios\n5) A mobile base station that supports wireless self-backhaul functionalities\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7453, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  A mobile base station acting as a relay between a UE and the 5G network", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum inter-site distance supported by the 5G system for a stand-alone multicast/broadcast network? \n\nOptions:\n1) 50 km\n2) 100 km\n3) 200 km\n4) 250 km\n5) 500 km\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7463, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  200 km", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the PCF do in relation to monitoring data rate per Network Slice? \n\nOptions:\n1) Monitors the data rate per Network Slice and applies policy decisions\n2) Enforces the Slice MBR and usage of Target NSSAI\n3) Monitors and controls the number of registered UEs per network slice\n4) Provides Target NSSAI and RFSP to RAN to steer the UE to another cell\n5) Supports slice specific RACH configuration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7464, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Monitors the data rate per Network Slice and applies policy decisions", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat type of measurement does the UE need to perform for cell selection and intra-frequency reselection in sidelink operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Inter-frequency measurement\n2) Inter-RAT measurement\n3) Intra-frequency measurement\n4) Inter-carrier measurement\n5) Non-serving frequency measurement\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7470, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Intra-frequency measurement", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat message does the eNB send to perform redirection to another E-UTRAN frequency? \n\nOptions:\n1) GBR bearer message\n2) RRC Connection Release message\n3) Redirect message\n4) Frequency update message\n5) UE CONTEXT RELEASE REQUEST message\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7471, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  UE CONTEXT RELEASE REQUEST message", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the impact on UE power consumption with the reduction of TRPs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Decrease in power consumption\n2) No impact\n3) Increase in power consumption\n4) Significant impact\n5) Variable impact\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7476, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Increase in power consumption", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the SMF determine when it receives notification on the requested analytics from the NWDAF? \n\nOptions:\n1) Which UEs need to download new AI/ML models\n2) Which UEs need to disable analytics information exposure\n3) Which UEs need to enable analytics information exposure\n4) Which UEs need to subscribe to the Analytics ID\n5) Which UEs the SMF needs to provide the analytics information to\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7477, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Which UEs the SMF needs to provide the analytics information to", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does NEF do after receiving the DNAI mapping information from UDR? \n\nOptions:\n1) Determines the DNN and/or S-NSSAI\n2) Notifies the DNAI(s) to the AF\n3) Determines the suitable DNAI(s)\n4) Subscribes to DNAI mapping information for this DNN and/or S-NSSAI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7478, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Determines the suitable DNAI(s)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the focus of the work item on Handsets Featuring Non-Traditional Earpieces? \n\nOptions:\n1) Enhancing the functionality of Multimedia Telephony Service for IMS\n2) Updating the test specifications for handsets with traditional earpieces\n3) Introducing new test methods for acoustic performance evaluation\n4) Defining proper guidance for setting up UEs with traditional earpieces\n5) Improving the acoustic test methods for UEs with non-traditional earpieces\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7479, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Improving the acoustic test methods for UEs with non-traditional earpieces", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the primary service state selected after power on? \n\nOptions:\n1) No IMSI\n2) Location Update Needed\n3) Normal Service\n4) Limited Service\n5) eCall Inactive\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7482, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Normal Service", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat may the NWDAF containing MTLF do if ML Model accuracy degradation is detected? \n\nOptions:\n1) Reselect a new ML model\n2) Retrain the existing ML model\n3) Notify the ML Model consumer(s)\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7487, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Coverage and Handoff Enhancements for Multimedia (CHEM) feature? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable the network to delay or reduce handoffs of a Multimedia Telephony Service for IMS terminal by providing additional information about packet losses\n2) To enable the network to prioritize handoffs of a Multimedia Telephony Service for IMS terminal by providing additional information about packet losses\n3) To enable the network to avoid handoffs of a Multimedia Telephony Service for IMS terminal by providing additional information about packet losses\n4) To enable the network to switch handoffs of a Multimedia Telephony Service for IMS terminal by providing additional information about packet losses\n5) To enable the network to identify handoffs of a Multimedia Telephony Service for IMS terminal by providing additional information about packet losses\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7488, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To enable the network to delay or reduce handoffs of a Multimedia Telephony Service for IMS terminal by providing additional information about packet losses", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich scenario is intended to capture real-life scenarios such as a city or station square? \n\nOptions:\n1) UMi with O2O and O2I\n2) UMa with O2O and O2I\n3) Indoor\n4) Backhaul\n5) D2D/V2V\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7493, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  UMi with O2O and O2I", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Control and User Plane Separation of EPC nodes in LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable dynamic power sharing between different bands\n2) To reduce the insertion loss for multi-band antenna sharing\n3) To provide low latency for services like social networks and web browsing\n4) To support multi-RAT operation (GSM and LTE) in Europe\n5) No specific purpose is mentioned for Control and User Plane Separation of EPC nodes\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7497, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To provide low latency for services like social networks and web browsing", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere are the relevant procedures for Disaster Roaming service updated? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 24.501\n2) TS 22.011\n3) TS 33.501\n4) TS 23.122\n5) TS 31.102\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7503, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  TS 24.501", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of Bandwidth Adaptation (BA)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To adjust the width, location, and subcarrier spacing of the UE's receive and transmit bandwidth\n2) To compress and decompress headers\n3) To map QoS flows to data radio bearers\n4) To multiplex and demultiplex MAC SDUs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7506, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To adjust the width, location, and subcarrier spacing of the UE's receive and transmit bandwidth", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the SMF Service Context Transfer procedures? \n\nOptions:\n1) To gracefully close the Source SMF\n2) To transfer the Service Context from the Target SMF Instance to the Source SMF Instance\n3) To retrieve the context from an endpoint address in the indirect mode\n4) To notify the consumers subscribed to changes in the resource\n5) To transfer context-specific information between SMF Sets\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7509, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To transfer context-specific information between SMF Sets", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich message does the gNB-DU respond with to the UE after receiving the RRCRelease message? \n\nOptions:\n1) RRCResumeRequest message\n2) UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMPLETE message\n3) PAGING message\n4) UE CONTEXT SETUP RESPONSE message\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7511, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  UE CONTEXT RELEASE COMPLETE message", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the function of the Visitor Location Register (VLR)? \n\nOptions:\n1) To hold subscriber data needed to handle packet data transfer.\n2) To terminate the interface towards E-UTRAN.\n3) To perform switching and signaling functions for mobile stations.\n4) To route calls to the actual location of the mobile station.\n5) To store International Mobile Subscriber Identities (IMSI).\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7515, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To route calls to the actual location of the mobile station.", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the difference between reliability and communication service availability? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Reliability is the ability to meet specific KPIs, while communication service availability refers to the system properties of 5G systems\n2) Reliability is the stability of the delay between transmission and receipt of messages, while communication service availability refers to the stability of the end-to-end latency\n3) Reliability is the ability of a system to perform its required functions under stated conditions, while communication service availability refers to the proportion of time a service is available for use\n4) Reliability is the bounded variation of transmission intervals, while communication service availability refers to the bounded variation of the interval between transmissions\n5) Reliability is the predetermined output of an open-loop control system, while communication service availability refers to the control of physical processes\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7517, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Reliability is the ability of a system to perform its required functions under stated conditions, while communication service availability refers to the proportion of time a service is available for use", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the General requirements in the application layer architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support deployment of EAS(s) and AC(s) with or without modifications\n2) To support different deployment models in conjunction with an operator's 3GPP network\n3) To be compatible with the 3GPP network system\n4) To provide mechanisms to provide configuration parameters to an authorized EEC\n5) To specify the requirements for EEC, EAS, and EES registration\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7518, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To support deployment of EAS(s) and AC(s) with or without modifications", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich identity is used for unique UE identification and scheduling? \n\nOptions:\n1) AI-RNTI\n2) SI-RNTI\n3) TPC-PUCCH-RNTI\n4) RA-RNTI\n5) C-RNTI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7520, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  C-RNTI", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the supported features for Multi-USIM UE operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Connection Release only\n2) Paging Cause Indication for Voice Service only\n3) Connection Release and Reject Paging Request\n4) Paging Restriction and Paging Timing Collision Control\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7533, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the finest granularity of QoS differentiation at NAS level? \n\nOptions:\n1) QoS Profiles\n2) DRBs\n3) PDU Sessions\n4) QoS Flows\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7534, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  QoS Flows", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich 3GPP specification captures the segmentation mechanism for NR? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS\u00a023.401\n2) TS\u00a036.331\n3) TS\u00a038.331\n4) TS\u00a023.501\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7542, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  TS\u00a038.331", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich mode does the Intra-CU Backhaul RLF recovery procedure apply to? \n\nOptions:\n1) EN-DC mode\n2) NSA mode\n3) ENA mode\n4) SA mode\n5) ENA-DC mode\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7546, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  SA mode", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich work item of Rel-14 specified the V2X communication to provide basic safety services? \n\nOptions:\n1) WI 'Support for V2V services based on LTE sidelink'\n2) WI 'LTE-based V2X services'\n3) WI 'V2X phase 2 based on LTE'\n4) WI 'Revision of WID:V2X phase 2 based on LTE'\n5) WI 'Enhancement of 3GPP support for V2X scenarios; Stage 1'\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7552, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  WI 'LTE-based V2X services'", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the steps involved in the procedure for NWDAF to derive slice load analytics? \n\nOptions:\n1) Consumer NF subscribes to NWDAF, NWDAF collects input data, NWDAF derives analytics, NWDAF delivers analytics to consumer NF\n2) NWDAF gains slice information, NWDAF collects input data, NWDAF derives analytics, NWDAF delivers analytics to consumer NF\n3) NWDAF subscribes to input data, NWDAF collects input data, NWDAF delivers analytics to consumer NF\n4) Consumer NF subscribes to NWDAF, NWDAF derives analytics, NWDAF collects input data, NWDAF delivers analytics to consumer NF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7561, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  NWDAF gains slice information, NWDAF collects input data, NWDAF derives analytics, NWDAF delivers analytics to consumer NF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the recommended behavior for a UE regarding excessive signaling load during the Paging Timing Collision Control procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) Avoid signaling load from UE\n2) Initiate the AN release procedure\n3) Continue with the normal registration procedure\n4) Request the network to reduce signaling load\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7568, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Avoid signaling load from UE", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat improvements does LTE Rel-13 introduce for machine-type communications (MTC)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Enhanced support for multicast\n2) Improved positioning capabilities\n3) Higher data rate support\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7576, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are cyber-physical systems? [3GPP Release 19]\n\nOptions:\n1) Systems that include engineered physical components\n2) Systems that include computational components\n3) Engineered, interacting networks of physical and computational components\n4) Systems that control physical processes\n5) Systems that support communication in automation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7577, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Engineered, interacting networks of physical and computational components", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow is SIPTO@LN PDN connection released in case of a handover with collocated L-GW? \n\nOptions:\n1) The EPC terminates the connection automatically\n2) The MME sends a release command to the eNB\n3) The collocated S-GW releases the connection\n4) The UE initiates the release procedure\n5) The eNB triggers the release over the S5 interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7587, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The eNB triggers the release over the S5 interface", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the supported measurement gaps for DL PRS and NR/LTE RRM measurements in Rel-16? \n\nOptions:\n1) Measurement gaps with > 10ms measurement gap length (MGL)\n2) Measurement gaps with > 5ms measurement gap length (MGL)\n3) Measurement gaps with > 6ms measurement gap length (MGL)\n4) Measurement gaps with > 8ms measurement gap length (MGL)\n5) Measurement gaps with > 4ms measurement gap length (MGL)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7595, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Measurement gaps with > 6ms measurement gap length (MGL)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UE consider the term 'radio bearer' (RB) to cover? \n\nOptions:\n1) Secondary Radio Bearers (SRBs)\n2) Data Radio Bearers (DRBs)\n3) Message Radio Bearers (MRBs)\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7601, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the process of distributed/federated learning over the 5G system? \n\nOptions:\n1) The cloud server trains a global model by aggregating local models partially-trained by each end devices\n2) The network endpoint executes the remaining parts/layers and feeds the inference results back to the device\n3) The device executes the operation/model up to a specific part/layer and then sends the intermediate data to the network endpoint\n4) Multi-functional mobile terminals switch the AI/ML model based on task and environment variations\n5) The UE reports the interim training results to the cloud server via 5G UL channels\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7605, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  The cloud server trains a global model by aggregating local models partially-trained by each end devices", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat distribution is used to generate delays for random clusters in Step 5 of the channel generation procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) Uniform distribution\n2) Exponential distribution\n3) Gaussian distribution\n4) Laplacian distribution\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7607, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Exponential distribution", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the process of allocating the core network operator to a UE in the CSFB scenario? \n\nOptions:\n1) Based on the network location of the UE\n2) Based on the type of radio access technology used by the UE\n3) Based on the operator configuration\n4) Based on the number of PLMN-id lists broadcasted by the network\n5) Based on the selected PLMN by a supporting UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7608, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Based on the operator configuration", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat criteria are considered for periodic network selection attempts? \n\nOptions:\n1) Signal quality and coverage area\n2) Priority and availability of PLMNs\n3) User preferences and network agreements\n4) Forbidden PLMNs and hysteresis function\n5) Potential for PS services and PLMN restrictions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7614, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Priority and availability of PLMNs", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn what scenarios may the network operator reduce network traffic further without reducing the Quality of Service (QoS)? \n\nOptions:\n1) Asset management services\n2) Privacy Exception List\n3) Value added services\n4) Periodic location determination and reporting\n5) Event-based or time-based decision process by the application\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7622, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Event-based or time-based decision process by the application", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the primary cell (PCell) in the context of RRC? \n\nOptions:\n1) The cell that broadcasts the MIB\n2) The cell that provides the security input\n3) The cell that handles emergency calls\n4) The cell that provides the NAS mobility information\n5) The cell that handles multicast/broadcast data\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7629, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The cell that provides the NAS mobility information", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is HARQ-ACK bundling? \n\nOptions:\n1) A feature that enables UEs to transmit multiple HARQ-ACK feedback for a single DL transport block.\n2) A feature that allows UEs to transmit a single HARQ-ACK feedback for multiple DL transport blocks.\n3) A technique for improving DL peak rate in half-duplex FDD operation.\n4) A method for improving link performance in DL-heavy TDD configurations.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7635, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  A feature that allows UEs to transmit a single HARQ-ACK feedback for multiple DL transport blocks.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can Path update signaling related to Dual Connectivity and UPF re-allocation occur? \n\nOptions:\n1) Only when the Master RAN node is not congested\n2) Sequentially, one after the other\n3) Independent of each other\n4) At the same time\n5) Only when the Secondary RAN node is not congested\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7636, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  At the same time", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does the gNB-CU trigger the UE Context Setup procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) Inactive to Idle transitions\n2) Inactive to active transitions excluding transitions due to signalling exchange only\n3) Inactive to other RRC states transitions\n4) Active to Inactive transitions\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7640, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Inactive to active transitions excluding transitions due to signalling exchange only", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the User Identifier in the context of Network Slice-Specific Authentication and Authorization? \n\nOptions:\n1) To authenticate and authorize a UE for access to a specific network slice\n2) To identify the existing identifiers relating to a 3GPP subscription or UE\n3) To establish PDU Session(s) to the required Data network\n4) To create and manage User Identities\n5) To interwork the 3GPP system with an external entity for authentication and authorization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7650, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To authenticate and authorize a UE for access to a specific network slice", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are some of the enhancements considered for the development of eCAPIF in Release 16? \n\nOptions:\n1) Architecture functional model to support multiple API providers\n2) Architectural model for the CAPIF interconnection\n3) Additional deployment models\n4) Procedure to support API topology hiding\n5) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7654, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  All of the above", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich component handles the request for prioritized QoS Flows for Mobile Originations? \n\nOptions:\n1) AMF\n2) PCF\n3) UPF\n4) SMF\n5) (R)AN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7657, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  PCF", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of inter-level correlation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To aggregate charging events belonging to the same charging session over a time period.\n2) To combine charging events belonging to the same service generated by different CTFs.\n3) To uniquely identify each operator for inter operator accounting purposes.\n4) To enable operators involved in IMS sessions to identify each other.\n5) To include IOI identities within SIP signalling.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7658, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To combine charging events belonging to the same service generated by different CTFs.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the handover to NR procedure? \n\nOptions:\n1) To establish SRBs and DRBs in another RAT\n2) To move a UE in RRC_CONNECTED to a cell using another RAT\n3) To transfer a connection between the UE and another RAN to NR\n4) To activate ciphering in E-UTRA\n5) To re-establish radio resources in NR\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7662, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To transfer a connection between the UE and another RAN to NR", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used to transfer control plane protocol between the E-UTRAN and MME? \n\nOptions:\n1) S1-MME-interface\n2) S1-U-interface\n3) Abis-interface\n4) Iub-interface\n5) Iur-interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7667, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  S1-MME-interface", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat do the delay profiles represent in the multi-path fading propagation conditions? \n\nOptions:\n1) The maximum delay spanned by the taps\n2) The maximum Doppler frequency\n3) The r.m.s. delay spread\n4) The number of taps at fixed positions on a sampling grid\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7677, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  The r.m.s. delay spread", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich measurement is used to calculate the energy efficiency of MIoT network slice based on the number of active UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) GTP.InDataOctN3UPF.SNSSAI\n2) GTP.OutDataOctN3UPF.SNSSAI\n3) RM.RegisteredSubNbrMax.SNSSAI\n4) DRB.MeanActiveUeDl.SNSSAI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7681, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  DRB.MeanActiveUeDl.SNSSAI", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the EDN service area? \n\nOptions:\n1) EDN bundle ID\n2) EES bundle ID\n3) EAS bundle ID\n4) LADN service area\n5) EES service area\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7691, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  LADN service area", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the characteristics of conversational services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Real-time, bi-directional, and low delay variation\n2) Store and forward, user-to-user communication\n3) Retrieval of information stored in information centers\n4) Access to flow of information without user control\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7699, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Real-time, bi-directional, and low delay variation", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the term 'serving cell' refer to when the procedures are applied for MCG? \n\nOptions:\n1) Primary cell of the SCG\n2) Serving cell belonging to the MCG\n3) Serving cell belonging to the SCG\n4) PUCCH-SCell\n5) PUCCH-PathlossReferenceRS\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7703, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Serving cell belonging to the MCG", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen can the SDT procedure over CG resources be initiated? \n\nOptions:\n1) When there is valid UL timing alignment.\n2) When the DL RSRP of the SSB is above a configured threshold.\n3) When the UE is in RRC_INACTIVE state.\n4) When the UE is in RRC_IDLE state.\n5) When the UE receives an RRCRelease message.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7709, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  When there is valid UL timing alignment.", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used to carry information concerning BSS management, call handling, and mobility management between the MSC and BSS? \n\nOptions:\n1) Gb-interface\n2) Iu_CS interface\n3) A-interface\n4) Um-interface\n5) Iu_PS-interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7711, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  A-interface", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich network function is responsible for authentication and authorization? \n\nOptions:\n1) SMF\n2) AMF\n3) AUSF\n4) PCF\n5) UDM\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7721, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  AUSF", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the designated interface for V2V communications? \n\nOptions:\n1) SA\n2) Uu\n3) PC5\n4) PSCCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7727, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  PC5", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the two modes of operation for V2X communication? \n\nOptions:\n1) V2X communication over PC5 interface and V2X communication over LTE-Uu interface\n2) V2X communication over 3GPP interface and V2X communication over non-3GPP interface\n3) V2X communication over E-UTRAN and V2X communication over EPC\n4) V2X communication over E-UTRAN and V2X communication over LTE-Uu interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7739, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  V2X communication over PC5 interface and V2X communication over LTE-Uu interface", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of QoS monitoring for assurance? \n\nOptions:\n1) To assess the QoS of communication services\n2) To provide real-time monitoring of asset conditions\n3) To diagnose and identify problems within a network\n4) To track the location of assets in real-time\n5) To interwork between network operators and application providers\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7740, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To assess the QoS of communication services", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a supporting UE display as the network name in a shared network? \n\nOptions:\n1) The common PLMN\n2) The name stored in the UE for the PLMN-id\n3) The name specified in the broadcast system information\n4) The name of the chosen core network operator\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7742, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The name of the chosen core network operator", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat are the different types of requirements for different 5G usages? \n\nOptions:\n1) Enhanced Mobile Broadband (eMBB), Critical Communications (CC) and Ultra Reliable and Low Latency Communications (URLLC), Flexible network operations\n2) Massive Internet of Things (mIoT), Smart cities, Media and entertainment\n3) Transport, logistics, IoT, Discrete automation, Smart cities\n4) Public Safety, Health and wellness, Electriciy distribution\n5) Transport, logistics, IoT, Media and entertainment\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7753, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Enhanced Mobile Broadband (eMBB), Critical Communications (CC) and Ultra Reliable and Low Latency Communications (URLLC), Flexible network operations", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the maximum relative velocity at which messages can be transferred between UEs supporting V2V applications? \n\nOptions:\n1) 300 km/h\n2) 400 km/h\n3) 500 km/h\n4) 600 km/h\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7756, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  500 km/h", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Ndccf_DataManagement_Notify service operation do? \n\nOptions:\n1) Subscribes to receive data or analytics via the DCCF\n2) Unsubscribes from receiving data or analytics via the DCCF\n3) Notifies the consumer instance of the requested data or analytics\n4) Fetches data or analytics from the DCCF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7762, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Notifies the consumer instance of the requested data or analytics", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the AULC feature improve? \n\nOptions:\n1) User location calculation\n2) Core network overload\n3) User location change awareness\n4) Emergency call handling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7769, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  User location change awareness", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the process of verifying if a Service User is authorized for MPS called? \n\nOptions:\n1) End-to-End Priority Treatment\n2) Service Invocation\n3) Network Interconnection\n4) Authorization\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7773, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Authorization", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich of the following is a requirement for ensuring security in ranging services? \n\nOptions:\n1) Ensuring the use of Ranging is only permitted in network coverage under the full control of the operator.\n2) Ensuring that user privacy is not violated during ranging.\n3) Supporting mechanisms for a UE to discover other UEs supporting ranging.\n4) Supporting mechanisms for a UE to assist another UE in performing ranging.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7775, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Ensuring that user privacy is not violated during ranging.", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is a Feature Set combination? \n\nOptions:\n1) A set of UE features\n2) A set of contiguous serving cells\n3) A two-dimensional matrix of feature sets per band\n4) A set of alternative features\n5) A set of aggregated carriers\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7782, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  A two-dimensional matrix of feature sets per band", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is periodic location reporting? \n\nOptions:\n1) The act of the network operator monitoring the location and status of an asset\n2) The act of the LCS Server initiating multiple position locations spread over a period of time\n3) The act of the target UE querying the LCS server about any valid requests\n4) The act of the PLMN supporting periodic location reporting for Emergency Services\n5) The act of the LCS client activating requests for the target UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7785, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The act of the LCS Server initiating multiple position locations spread over a period of time", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the 'Subscribe-notify' communication paradigm in management service interactions? \n\nOptions:\n1) To authenticate the management service consumer\n2) To establish a connection for management data streaming\n3) To enable the management service producer to invoke operations\n4) To request a subscription to notifications and receive network events\n5) To provide response based on a request from the management service consumer\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7787, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To request a subscription to notifications and receive network events", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the objective of enhancing the interactions between 3GPP management system and supporting external management systems in the context of 5G Trace management? \n\nOptions:\n1) To support the management of 5GC and NG-RAN\n2) To define the Network Resource Model (NRM) for 5G networks and network slicing\n3) To provide Service Based Interface (SBI) for charging\n4) To specify the Fault Supervision related management services\n5) To enhance the Management Services specifications\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7788, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To support the management of 5GC and NG-RAN", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat protocol is IP multimedia session control based on? \n\nOptions:\n1) H.324M\n2) SIP\n3) MMS\n4) GTT\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7803, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  SIP", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat action does the AMF take when the updated subscription data indicates that the UE is not allowed to roam in the network? \n\nOptions:\n1) Initiating an SMF initiated PDU Session Modification procedure\n2) Initiating an AMF initiated Deregistration procedure\n3) Updating UE context stored at RAN to modify the UE-Slice-MBR corresponding to an S-NSSAI\n4) Initiating UE Configuration Update procedure\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7804, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Initiating an AMF initiated Deregistration procedure", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the value of \u2206thermal used in the Noc methodology? \n\nOptions:\n1) 6 dB\n2) 0.33 dB\n3) 0.9 dB\n4) 1 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7810, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  6 dB", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when the DNAI mapping information is changed in the UDR? \n\nOptions:\n1) NEF determines the suitable DNAI(s)\n2) NEF notifies the AF\n3) UDR notifies the NEF with all the DNAI mapping information\n4) NEF determines the DNN and/or S-NSSAI\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7827, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  UDR notifies the NEF with all the DNAI mapping information", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn a gNB-DU, what is the purpose of an MRB context? \n\nOptions:\n1) To maintain information about multiple gNB-DUs\n2) To establish connections with the gNB-CU-CP through the F1-C interface\n3) To control the F1-U tunnels associated with an MBS Session\n4) To uniquely identify the gNB-DU within a gNB-CU\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7828, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To control the F1-U tunnels associated with an MBS Session", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Ndccf_DataManagement_Fetch service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To subscribe to receive data or analytics via the DCCF\n2) To unsubscribe from receiving data or analytics via the DCCF\n3) To notify the DCCF about the requested data or analytics\n4) To retrieve data or analytics from the DCCF\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7830, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To retrieve data or analytics from the DCCF", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the PDN-Connection-Continuity subscription parameter? \n\nOptions:\n1) To handle CN overload from data transmission\n2) To prioritize resource allocation between NB-IoT UEs\n3) To indicate how to handle the PDN connection when moving between broadband and narrowband\n4) To enable UE-assisted DCN selection\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7837, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To indicate how to handle the PDN connection when moving between broadband and narrowband", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is the reference point for mobility management and paging procedures between EPS and CS domain? \n\nOptions:\n1) Gs-interface\n2) S6a-interface\n3) Gr-interface\n4) SGs-interface\n5) Gn/Gp-interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7839, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  SGs-interface", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat inputs are required for the Nmfaf_3caDataManagement_Fetch service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) Data Consumer or Analytics Consumer Information, Transaction Reference Id\n2) Notification Correlation Information\n3) Requested Data with timestamp or Analytics with timestamp, Fetch Instructions\n4) Set of Fetch Correlation ID(s)\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7853, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Set of Fetch Correlation ID(s)", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Nadrf_MLModelManagement_Retrieval Request service operation? \n\nOptions:\n1) To request the ADRF to store or update ML models\n2) To request the ADRF to retrieve stored ML models\n3) To request the ADRF to delete stored ML models\n4) To request the ADRF to retrieve stored ML model addresses\n5) To request the ADRF to delete stored ML model addresses\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7861, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  To request the ADRF to retrieve stored ML models", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhere are the non-roaming and roaming architectures to support Location Services defined? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS\u00a023.040\n2) TS\u00a023.273\n3) TS\u00a023.502\n4) TS\u00a023.540\n5) TS\u00a023.228\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7862, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  TS\u00a023.273", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich symbols are included in the last slots of a slot configuration period? \n\nOptions:\n1) Downlink symbols\n2) Uplink symbols\n3) Flexible symbols\n4) No symbols\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7866, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Uplink symbols", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the Operator controlled signal threshold per access technology specify for network selection? \n\nOptions:\n1) The number of PLMNs to be selected\n2) The order in which PLMNs are selected\n3) The priority of different access technologies\n4) The signal quality required for a PLMN to be selected\n5) The coverage area of a PLMN\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7868, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  The signal quality required for a PLMN to be selected", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich standard provides the specification for interworking between the IMS domain and the CS domain? \n\nOptions:\n1) RFC 3261\n2) ITU-T Recommendation H.248\n3) 3GPP TS 23.228\n4) ETSI TS 183 010\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7873, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  3GPP TS 23.228", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich solutions have been specified to support highly reliable and low latency communication for LTE? \n\nOptions:\n1) Semi-static CFI configuration and PDSCH repetition\n2) UL SPS repetition and PDCP packet duplication\n3) Granular time reference provision and PDCP packet duplication\n4) PDSCH repetition and Granular time reference provision\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7875, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Semi-static CFI configuration and PDSCH repetition", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich interface is used between two eNBs? \n\nOptions:\n1) S1-MME-interface\n2) S1-U-interface\n3) Abis-interface\n4) Iub-interface\n5) X2-interface\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7877, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  X2-interface", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich protocol(s) crossing the Ro reference point should support real-time transactions? \n\nOptions:\n1) Retransmission of charging events\n2) Statefull mode\n3) Reliability mechanisms\n4) Stateless mode\n5) Changeover to secondary destination\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7878, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Stateless mode", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the gNB allocate downlink resources for initial HARQ transmissions to UEs? \n\nOptions:\n1) Through the scheduling request channel\n2) Through power headroom reports\n3) Through activation of configured downlink assignments\n4) Through semi-persistent scheduling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7881, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Through semi-persistent scheduling", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich transmission scheme is used for PDSCH? \n\nOptions:\n1) SU-MIMO\n2) MU-MIMO\n3) DMRS based spatial multiplexing\n4) CP-OFDM with optional DFT-spreading\n5) DFT spreading\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7884, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  DMRS based spatial multiplexing", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich mode does the CGF use to transfer CDR files to the BD? \n\nOptions:\n1) Push mode\n2) Pull mode\n3) Both push and pull mode\n4) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7905, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Both push and pull mode", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of PC5-RRC in NR V2X sidelink? \n\nOptions:\n1) To enable sensing operations\n2) To enable resource allocation\n3) To enable cross-RAT operations\n4) To enable V2X message delivery\n5) To enable location tracking\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7913, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  To enable cross-RAT operations", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the abbreviation (g)PTP stand for? \n\nOptions:\n1) General Packet Transfer Protocol\n2) Generic Precision Timing Protocol\n3) Global PTP\n4) Group-based Precision Timing Protocol\n5) Gateway PTP\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7923, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Generic Precision Timing Protocol", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the basic unit to perform channel sensing? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transmission slot\n2) Sensing slot\n3) Beam slot\n4) Channel slot\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7926, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Sensing slot", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens when a PDU Session with UP confidentiality protection set to Required is handed over to EPS? \n\nOptions:\n1) The UP confidentiality protection is modified to Not Needed\n2) The UP confidentiality protection is disabled\n3) The PDU Session is rejected\n4) The UP confidentiality protection is modified to Preferred\n5) The PDU Session is released\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7929, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  The PDU Session is released", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does NG-RAN stand for? \n\nOptions:\n1) Non-Geographical Radio Access Network\n2) New Generation Radio Antenna Node\n3) Network Gateway Radio Access Node\n4) Next Generation Radio Access Network\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7935, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Next Generation Radio Access Network", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich project was developed at the Fraunhofer Heinrich Hertz Institute to enable the modeling of MIMO radio channels for specific network configurations? \n\nOptions:\n1) METIS\n2) MiWEBA\n3) QuaDRiGa (Fraunhofer HHI)\n4) NYU WIRELESS\n5) mmMAGIC\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7944, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  QuaDRiGa (Fraunhofer HHI)", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich deployment scenarios are possible for the UxNB in the 3GPP network?\n\nOptions:\n1) Aerial base station (ABS)\n2) Aerial relay (AR)\n3) Isolated ABS\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7945, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which 3GPP release was Licensed Assisted Access (LAA) standardized?\n\nOptions:\n1) Rel-11\n2) Rel-12\n3) Rel-13\n4) Rel-14\n5) Rel-15\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7952, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Rel-13", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nIn which phase does MDA identify ongoing issues and potential risks? \n\nOptions:\n1) Observation phase\n2) Analytics phase\n3) Decision phase\n4) Execution phase\n5) Operation phase\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7956, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  Operation phase", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does MCG stand for in 5G? \n\nOptions:\n1) Master Cell Group\n2) Mobile Connectivity Gateway\n3) Multiple Connection Generator\n4) Main Control Group\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7960, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Master Cell Group", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can the K-factor of LOS channel models be changed? \n\nOptions:\n1) By generating additional sub-clusters in delay\n2) By applying a coefficient generation procedure\n3) By scaling the powers and re-normalizing the delay spread\n4) By selecting extreme cases, e.g. uncorrelated, highly correlated, etc.\n5) By using the correlation matrix construction method from TS36.101/104\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7962, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By scaling the powers and re-normalizing the delay spread", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the NWDAF provide to the consumer when the congestion level crosses the threshold? \n\nOptions:\n1) Measurement information for the requested location\n2) Analytics for congestion\n3) Notification for analytics\n4) UE mobility event notification\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7974, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Notification for analytics", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat operation does the UDM use to acknowledge the UE-AMF received the Steering of Roaming information? \n\nOptions:\n1) Nudm_SDM_Notification service operation\n2) Nudm_SDM_Info service operation\n3) Nudm_SDM_Unsubscribe response operation\n4) Nudm_UECM_Deregistration response operation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7975, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Nudm_SDM_Info service operation", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat resource set does a RedCap UE use to transmit PUCCH if it is not provided initialUplinkBWP-RedCap in UplinkConfigCommonSIB and does not have dedicated PUCCH resource configuration? \n\nOptions:\n1) No PUCCH resource set\n2) A PUCCH resource set provided by pucch-ResourceCommon\n3) Any available PUCCH resource set\n4) A subset of PUCCH resources\n5) A PUCCH resource set provided by pucch-ResourceCommonRedCap\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7980, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  A PUCCH resource set provided by pucch-ResourceCommonRedCap", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the Intra-CU Backhaul RLF recovery procedure for IAB-nodes in SA mode? \n\nOptions:\n1) To establish a new RRC connection for the UE in the target gNB-DU\n2) To configure data bearers in the source gNB-DU\n3) To stop the data transmission to the UE in the source gNB-DU\n4) To recover from a backhaul RLF in the IAB-node\n5) To release the UE context in the target gNB-DU\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7984, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  To recover from a backhaul RLF in the IAB-node", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of GNSS in V2V communications? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide time synchronization\n2) To handle high-density communication\n3) To assist eNBs in scheduling and interference management\n4) To enhance resource separation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7985, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide time synchronization", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich logical channel is used for transmitting control information between UEs and the network? \n\nOptions:\n1) BCCH\n2) PCCH\n3) CCCH\n4) DCCH\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7998, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  CCCH", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the max SNR increase for 66 PRB allocation compared to 264 PRBs? \n\nOptions:\n1) 0.33 dB\n2) 0.9 dB\n3) 3.5 dB\n4) 7.7 dB\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 7999, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  7.7 dB", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the term used for HARQ-ACK information associated with multicast DCI formats or multicast PDSCH receptions? \n\nOptions:\n1) Unicast HARQ-ACK information\n2) Dynamic HARQ-ACK information\n3) Multicast HARQ-ACK information\n4) Static HARQ-ACK information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8000, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Multicast HARQ-ACK information", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow can power saving be achieved in RRC_IDLE and RRC_INACTIVE? \n\nOptions:\n1) By adapting the DL maximum number of MIMO layers\n2) By monitoring TRS with CSI-RS for tracking in TRS occasions\n3) By relaxing neighbour cells RRM measurements\n4) By performing RLM and/or BFD relaxation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8003, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  By relaxing neighbour cells RRM measurements", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow does the network provide the paging cause field for voice service to a Multi-USIM UE? \n\nOptions:\n1) By sending a specific indication to the UE.\n2) By including the field in the paging message.\n3) By sending a separate notification message.\n4) By sending a dedicated paging request.\n5) By providing an indication in the downlink data.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8027, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  By providing an indication in the downlink data.", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat determines the configuration of Dual Connectivity for a Data Radio Bearer? \n\nOptions:\n1) RSN and/or PDU Session Pair ID\n2) Network Slice that the PDU Session belongs to\n3) Mobility Restriction List\n4) QoS Flows of the PDU Session\n5) Identity of the cell serving the UE\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8028, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  Network Slice that the PDU Session belongs to", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does a '0' value for a bit of the bitmap, provided by dormancyGroupWithinActiveTime, indicate? \n\nOptions:\n1) A current active DL BWP for the UE.\n2) A dormant DL BWP for the UE.\n3) An active DL BWP for the UE.\n4) A firstWithinActiveTimeBWP-Id for the UE.\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8030, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  An active DL BWP for the UE.", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the composition of low and high loss dependent on? \n\nOptions:\n1) Number of materials used in buildings\n2) Deployment scenarios\n3) Use of metal-coated glass in buildings\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8036, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat RRC states can additional resources be used for RRM measurements? \n\nOptions:\n1) RRC IDLE\n2) RRC INACTIVE\n3) RRC CONNECTED\n4) All of the above\n5) None of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8054, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow are transactions dispersion analytics calculated? \n\nOptions:\n1) By aggregating the number of MM and SM messages generated by UEs\n2) By ranking hot locations based on MM and SM messages\n3) By predicting the number of MM and SM messages generated by UEs\n4) By classifying UEs as fixed, camper or traveller based on MM and SM messages\n5) By determining the location of MM and SM messages generated by UEs\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8063, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  By aggregating the number of MM and SM messages generated by UEs", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhen does a mobile station enter the GMM-DEREGISTERED state? \n\nOptions:\n1) When a GPRS attach or combined GPRS attach procedure is performed\n2) When a GMM procedure has failed\n3) When a GPRS detach or combined GPRS detach procedure is performed\n4) When the MS is switched on\n5) When the MS is IMSI attached for GPRS services only\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8064, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  When the MS is switched on", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nHow many PRBs are supported on a carrier? \n\nOptions:\n1) 275\n2) 264\n3) 14\n4) 12\n5) 271\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8071, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  275", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat happens if the active UICC is removed from the mobile terminal during a call? \n\nOptions:\n1) The call continues with the next available UICC\n2) The call is terminated immediately\n3) The call is put on hold until the UICC is reinserted\n4) The call switches to a different network\n5) The call is automatically transferred to voicemail\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8074, "answer": "The correct option is 2)  The call is terminated immediately", "answer_option": 2}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does AULC decouple between the PCRF and the OCS? \n\nOptions:\n1) UE subscription\n2) User location information\n3) Presence Reporting Area (PRA) subscription\n4) Charging behavior\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8077, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Presence Reporting Area (PRA) subscription", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the power saving gain range for the power saving schemes with UE adaptation to BWP switching? \n\nOptions:\n1) 8.5% - 16%\n2) 16% - 31%\n3) 45% - 57.75%\n4) 8.5% - 45%\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8082, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  8.5% - 45%", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat media capabilities are included in the IMS Multimedia Telephony service? \n\nOptions:\n1) Full duplex speech, real-time video, and fax\n2) Real-time text communication, file transfer, and data (CS)\n3) Video clip sharing, picture sharing, and audio clip sharing\n4) All of the above\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8085, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  All of the above", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich specifications define the charging scenario, charging functionalities, and the Message format of the Common Data structure of Charging Data in the 5G system architecture? \n\nOptions:\n1) TS 32.290\n2) TS 32.291\n3) TS 32.298\n4) TS 32.299\n5) TS 32.274\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8086, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  TS 32.290", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat can be used for intra-system inter-RAT handover if the UE is connected to the 5GC of the source E-UTRA cell? \n\nOptions:\n1) Delta configuration for PDCP and SDAP\n2) Source RAT configuration\n3) Reconfiguration message of target RAT\n4) Re-establishment procedure\n5) NULL algorithm for ciphering\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8096, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Delta configuration for PDCP and SDAP", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat aspect of VoLTE roaming with S8HR architecture did the SA3-LI Study Item 'FS_LIV8' focus on? \n\nOptions:\n1) Emergency call establishment\n2) Location determination at IMS entities\n3) Local number translation\n4) Lawful interception of VoLTE traffic\n5) Charging principles for S8HR roaming\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8101, "answer": "The correct option is 4)  Lawful interception of VoLTE traffic", "answer_option": 4}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is required for the provision of location services without impacting the network's capabilities? \n\nOptions:\n1) Significant impact on the radio transmission\n2) Significant impact on the signalling capabilities\n3) No impact on the radio transmission or the signalling capabilities\n4) Moderate impact on the radio transmission and the signalling capabilities\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8108, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  No impact on the radio transmission or the signalling capabilities", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhich physical layer processing step includes LDPC coding? \n\nOptions:\n1) Transport block CRC attachment\n2) Code block segmentation\n3) Physical-layer hybrid-ARQ processing\n4) Rate matching\n5) Scrambling\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8110, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  Physical-layer hybrid-ARQ processing", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat services does the UMTS Bearer Service consist of? \n\nOptions:\n1) Radio Access Bearer Service and Core Network Bearer Service\n2) Te/MT Local Bearer Service and External Bearer Service\n3) GERAN and UTRAN FDD/TDD\n4) Iu and Gb Bearer Service\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8111, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  Radio Access Bearer Service and Core Network Bearer Service", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat does the UE provide to the AS for slice aware cell reselection? \n\nOptions:\n1) Slice-Maximum Bit Rate\n2) S-NSSAI\n3) NSSRG\n4) S-MBR\n5) NSAG information\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8114, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  NSAG information", "answer_option": 5}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the interfering signal for the dynamic range requirement? \n\nOptions:\n1) An E-UTRA signal\n2) A CW signal\n3) An AWGN signal\n4) An interfering signal with a positive offset\n5) An interfering signal with a negative offset\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8117, "answer": "The correct option is 3)  An AWGN signal", "answer_option": 3}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of AKMA TLS protocol profiles? \n\nOptions:\n1) To provide secure TLS connections between the UE and an AF in the network\n2) To establish a secure tunnel between the network and user equipment\n3) To generate keys for use in the 5G core\n4) To support non-seamless WLAN offload authentication\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8123, "answer": "The correct option is 1)  To provide secure TLS connections between the UE and an AF in the network", "answer_option": 1}, {"question": "Select the correct option for the question below\n\nQuestion: \nWhat is the purpose of the SN Addition Request message? \n\nOptions:\n1) To setup bearer context\n2) To notify the SCG activation or deactivation\n3) To stop the data transmission for the UE\n4) To release the UE context\n5) To indicate the request of SCG activation or deactivation\n\nAnswer: ", "id": 8136, "answer": "The correct option is 5)  To indicate the request of SCG activation or deactivation", "answer_option": 5}]